[
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b5f",
        "question": "How many Canadians served in the Second World War?",
        "choices": [
            "About 900,000",
            "About 300,000",
            "More than one million",
            "About 60,000"
        ],
        "explanation": "More than one million Canadians and Newfoundlanders (Newfoundland was a separate British entity) served in the Second World War, out of a population of 11.5 million. This was a high proportion and of these, 44,000 were killed.",
        "answer": "More than one million"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b62",
        "question": "Which of the following statement is false?",
        "choices": [
            "Canada is a federal state",
            "Canada is a constitutional monarchy",
            "Canada is a parliamentary democracy",
            "Canada is a theocracy"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy, a parliamentary democracy and a federal state. Canadians are bound together by a shared commitment to the rule of law and to the institutions of parliamentary government.",
        "answer": "Canada is a theocracy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b63",
        "question": "What year did Canada start its own honours system?",
        "choices": [
            "1967",
            "1947",
            "1867",
            "1889"
        ],
        "explanation": "After using British honours for many years, Canada started its own honours system with the Order of Canada in 1967, the centennial of Confederation.",
        "answer": "1967"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b64",
        "question": "You’ll swear the following as you take the Oath of Citizenship:",
        "choices": [
            "Experience the Canadian dream",
            "Pledge allegiance to the Queen and abide by British legislation",
            "Pledge loyalty to the Queen, abide by Canadian law, and carry out your citizenship obligations",
            "Purchase real estate in Canada, abide by Canadian laws, and support Canadian commerce"
        ],
        "explanation": "During this important moment, you must pledge loyalty to the King or Queen, abide by Canadian law, and carry out your citizenship obligations.",
        "answer": "Pledge loyalty to the Queen, abide by Canadian law, and carry out your citizenship obligations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b65",
        "question": "Canadians cannot leave their country freely",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians can live and work anywhere they choose in Canada, enter and leave the country freely, and apply for a passport.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b67",
        "question": "When did the term \"First Nations\" begin to be used?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1960s",
            "Never",
            "In the 1980s",
            "In the 1970s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Indian refers to all Aboriginal people who are not Inuit or Métis. In the 1970s, the term First Nations began to be used.",
        "answer": "In the 1970s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b60",
        "question": "Who was the founder of the women’s suffrage movement?",
        "choices": [
            "Ther",
            "Marie Howe",
            "Agnes Macphail",
            "Dr. Emily Stowe"
        ],
        "explanation": "The effort by women to achieve the right to vote is known as the women’s suffrage movement. Its founder in Canada was Dr. Emily Stowe, the first Canadian woman to practise medicine in Canada.",
        "answer": "Dr. Emily Stowe"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b61",
        "question": "Which province is Canada’s major producer of oil and gas?",
        "choices": [
            "Alberta",
            "Ontario",
            "British Columbia",
            "Manitoba"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alberta is the largest producer of oil and gas, and the oil sands in the north are being developed as a major energy source.",
        "answer": "Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b69",
        "question": "Who were the \"voyageurs\" and \"coureurs des bois\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The skilled and courageous men who travelled by canoe and formed strong alliances with First Nations",
            "The French settlers",
            "The French who lived with the Natives",
            "The people who lived in the forest"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1670, King Charles II of England granted the Hudson’s Bay Company exclusive trading rights over the watershed draining into Hudson Bay. For the next 100 years the Company competed with Montreal-based traders. The skilled and courageous men who travelled by canoe were called voyageurs and coureurs des bois, and formed strong alliances with First Nations.",
        "answer": "The skilled and courageous men who travelled by canoe and formed strong alliances with First Nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6a",
        "question": "Family and friends are not allowed to attend your citizenship ceremony.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "If you pass the test and meet all the other requirements, you will receive a Notice to Appear to Take the Oath of Citizenship. You are encouraged to bring your family and friends to celebrate this occasion.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6b",
        "question": "Which famous Canadian artist painted the forests and Aboriginal artifacts of the West Coast?",
        "choices": [
            "Emily Carr",
            "Jean-Paul Riopelle",
            "Kenojuak Ashevak",
            "Louis-Philippe Hebert"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the visual arts, Canada is historically perhaps best known for the Group of Seven, founded in 1920, who developed a style of painting to capture the rugged wilderness landscapes. Emily Carr painted the forests and Aboriginal artifacts of the West Coast.",
        "answer": "Emily Carr"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6c",
        "question": "What is the G8?",
        "choices": [
            "The group of 8 Fathers of Confederation",
            "A group of 8 famous Canadian artists",
            "The 8 countries involved in NAFTA",
            "A group of 8 leading industrialized countries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, Canada has one of the ten largest economies in the world and is part of the G8 group of leading industrialized countries with the United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Japan and Russia.",
        "answer": "A group of 8 leading industrialized countries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6d",
        "question": "What are the responsibilities of the members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures?",
        "choices": [
            "Passing laws, and approving and monitoring expenditures",
            "Monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable",
            "Passing laws, approving and monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable",
            "Matters of international concern"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada’s parliamentary democracy, the people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures. These representatives are responsible for passing laws, approving and monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable.",
        "answer": "Passing laws, approving and monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6e",
        "question": "Who are the representatives for the First Nations?",
        "choices": [
            "Band chiefs and councillors",
            "None",
            "First Nation senators",
            "First Nation mayors"
        ],
        "explanation": "The First Nations have band chiefs and councillors who have major responsibilities on First Nations reserves, including housing, schools and other services.",
        "answer": "Band chiefs and councillors"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b6f",
        "question": "What is the name of the Canadian river that represents the second-longest river system in North America?",
        "choices": [
            "St Lawrence River",
            "Mackenzie River",
            "Yukon River",
            "The Columbia River"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Mackenzie River, at 4,200 kilometres, is the second-longest river system in North America after the Mississippi and drains an area of 1.8 million square kilometres.",
        "answer": "Mackenzie River"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b70",
        "question": "Canada does not personify the Sovereign.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada personifies a King or Queen; however, our government is a democracy.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b71",
        "question": "In Canada, the constitution, the flag and the country are not encompassed by the Sovereign.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, we profess our loyalty to a person who represents all Canadians and not to a document such as a constitution, a banner such as a flag, or a geopolitical entity such as a country. In our constitutional monarchy, these elements are encompassed by the Sovereign (Queen or King). It is a remarkably simple yet powerful principle: Canada is personified by the Sovereign just as the Sovereign is personified by Canada.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b72",
        "question": "How long have settlers and immigrants contributed to the diversity and wealth of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "200 Years",
            "400 Years",
            "300 Years",
            "500 Years"
        ],
        "explanation": "For 400 years, settlers and immigrants have contributed to the diversity and richness of Canada, which is built on a proud history and a strong identity.",
        "answer": "400 Years"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b73",
        "question": "To which industries do forestry, fishing, agriculture, mining and energy belong to?",
        "choices": [
            "Trading Industries",
            "Natural resources industries",
            "Service industries",
            "Manufacturing industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Natural resources industries include forestry, fishing, agriculture, mining and energy. These industries have played an important part in the country’s history and development.",
        "answer": "Natural resources industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b75",
        "question": "Who were pioneers of modern abstract art in the 1950s?",
        "choices": [
            "Les Reformateurs of Quebec",
            "The Group of Seven",
            "\"Les Automatistes\" of Quebec",
            "The Abstractists"
        ],
        "explanation": "Les Automatistes of Quebec were pioneers of modern abstract art in the 1950s, most notably Jean-Paul Riopelle.",
        "answer": "\"Les Automatistes\" of Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b74",
        "question": "Into how many electoral districts is Canada divided?",
        "choices": [
            "402",
            "208",
            "196",
            "308"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is divided into 308 electoral districts, also known as ridings or constituencies. An electoral district is a geographical area represented by a member of Parliament (MP).",
        "answer": "308"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b76",
        "question": "What is the role of the police in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "To resolve legal disputes",
            "To defend Canadian borders",
            "To provide National Security data to the Federal government",
            "To keep people safe and to enforce the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "The police are there to keep people safe and to enforce the law. You can ask the police for help in all kinds of situations—if there’s been an accident, if someone has stolen something from you, if you are a victim of assault, if you see a crime taking place or if someone you know has gone missing.",
        "answer": "To keep people safe and to enforce the law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b77",
        "question": "Where is Western Canada’s largest Francophone community?",
        "choices": [
            "Alberta",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Manitoba",
            "British Columbia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Winnipeg’s French Quarter, St. Boniface, has Western Canada’s largest Francophone community at 45,000. Manitoba is also an important centre of Ukrainian culture, with 14% reporting Ukrainian origins, and the largest Aboriginal population of any province, at over 15%.",
        "answer": "Manitoba"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b68",
        "question": "Which of the following statement is true?",
        "choices": [
            "Immigrants between the ages of 21 and 54 must learn about voting laws in order to become Canadian citizens",
            "Canada has welcomed immigrants for years in order to create a society that is free, just, and affluent",
            "Canada is a Republic",
            "Canadians haven't given up anything to protect their way of life"
        ],
        "explanation": "The prosperity and diversity of Canada depends on all Canadians working together to face challenges of the future. In seeking to become a citizen, you are joining a country that, with your active participation, will continue to grow and thrive.",
        "answer": "Canada has welcomed immigrants for years in order to create a society that is free, just, and affluent"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7a",
        "question": "The citizenship test is:",
        "choices": [
            "A written exam, but it could also be an interview",
            "Usually taken online",
            "Always a written test",
            "Always in the form of an interview"
        ],
        "explanation": "The citizenship test is usually a written test, but it could be an interview. You will be tested on two basic requirements for citizenship: 1) knowledge of Canada and of the rights and responsibilities of citizenship, and 2) adequate knowledge of English or French.",
        "answer": "A written exam, but it could also be an interview"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b66",
        "question": "In the Canadian justice system, what is \"due process\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The principle that the government must complete a particular judicial process before convicting anyone",
            "The principle that the government has its own process when dealing with criminals",
            "The principle that the government must respect certain legal rights a person is entitled under the law",
            "The principle that the government must respect all of legal rights a person is entitled to under the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "Due process is the principle that the government must respect all the legal rights a person is entitled to under the law.",
        "answer": "The principle that the government must respect all of legal rights a person is entitled to under the law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7b",
        "question": "In Canada, to which following category do the laws not apply?",
        "choices": [
            "None of the above",
            "Judges",
            "Police",
            "Politicians"
        ],
        "explanation": "The law applies to everyone. No one is above the law in Canada.",
        "answer": "None of the above"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7c",
        "question": "Which elections as a Canadian citizen are you required to participate in?",
        "choices": [
            "Local elections only",
            "Federal, provincial or territorial elections",
            "Federal, provincial or territorial and local elections",
            "Federal elections only"
        ],
        "explanation": "Living in a democracy, Canadian citizens have the right and the responsibility to participate in making decisions that affect them. It is important for Canadians aged 18 or more to participate in their democracy by voting in federal, provincial or territorial and municipal elections.",
        "answer": "Federal, provincial or territorial and local elections"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7d",
        "question": "What is \"Magna Carta\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Great Code of England",
            "The Great Charter of Freedoms",
            "The constitution of Ireland",
            "A map of the world in 1216"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta is another name for \"The Great Charter of Freedoms\" which was signed in the year 1215.",
        "answer": "The Great Charter of Freedoms"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7f",
        "question": "What does it mean for the Cabinet Ministers to retain the \"confidence of the House\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The House of Commons is responsible for the Cabinet ministers",
            "Cabinet ministers must retain the confidence of the people",
            "Cabinet ministers have to resign if they are defeated in a non-confidence vote",
            "Cabinet ministers must swear allegiance to the House of England"
        ],
        "explanation": "Cabinet ministers are responsible to the elected representatives, which means they must retain the “confidence of the House” and have to resign if they are defeated in a non-confidence vote.",
        "answer": "Cabinet ministers have to resign if they are defeated in a non-confidence vote"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b7e",
        "question": "Quebec enjoys sovereignty in Canada",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "The movement for Quebec sovereignty gained strength but was defeated in a referendum in the province in 1980. After much negotiation, in 1982 the Constitution was amended without the agreement of Quebec.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b80",
        "question": "Who was Mary Ann (Shadd) Carey?",
        "choices": [
            "The founder of the Canadian feminist movement",
            "The founder of the women's suffrage movement",
            "An anti-slavery activist and the first woman publisher in Canada",
            "The first woman fur trader"
        ],
        "explanation": "Mary Ann Shadd Cary was an outspoken activist in the movement to abolish slavery in the U.S.A. In 1853 she became the first woman publisher in Canada, helping to found and edit The Provincial Freeman, a weekly newspaper dedicated to anti-slavery, black immigration to Canada, temperance (urging people to drink less alcohol) and upholding British rule.",
        "answer": "An anti-slavery activist and the first woman publisher in Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b82",
        "question": "What type of government is there in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Confederation",
            "Republic",
            "Oligarchy",
            "Constitutional monarchy"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy, a parliamentary democracy and a federal state. Canadians are bound together by a shared commitment to the rule of law and to the institutions of parliamentary government.",
        "answer": "Constitutional monarchy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b81",
        "question": "In Canada, the police are there to help you.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) enforce federal laws throughout Canada, and serve as the provincial police in all provinces and territories except Ontario and Quebec, as well as in some municipalities. Remember, the police are there to help you.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b83",
        "question": "When do Canadians celebrate Victoria Day?",
        "choices": [
            "Tuesday preceding June 25th",
            "Monday preceding June 25th",
            "Monday preceding May 25th",
            "Tuesday preceding May 25th"
        ],
        "explanation": "Victoria Day is celebrated on the Monday preceding May 25th.",
        "answer": "Monday preceding May 25th"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b84",
        "question": "When was the Official Languages Act passed?",
        "choices": [
            "1941",
            "1969",
            "1869",
            "1949"
        ],
        "explanation": "Parliament passed the Official Languages Act in 1969.",
        "answer": "1969"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b85",
        "question": "In Canada, how did democratic institutions develop?",
        "choices": [
            "Rapidly and peacefully",
            "Gradually and with a lot of fighting",
            "Rapidly and with a lot of fighting",
            "Gradually and peacefully"
        ],
        "explanation": "Democratic institutions developed gradually and peacefully. The first representative assembly was elected in Halifax, Nova Scotia, in 1758.",
        "answer": "Gradually and peacefully"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b86",
        "question": "In which of the following situations can you not ask the police for help?",
        "choices": [
            "Your water pipes are leaking",
            "Someone has stolen something from you",
            "You are a victim of assault",
            "There has been an accident"
        ],
        "explanation": "You can ask the police for help in all kinds of situations—if there’s been an accident, if someone has stolen something from you, if you are a victim of assault, if you see a crime taking place or if someone you know has gone missing.",
        "answer": "Your water pipes are leaking"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b87",
        "question": "Which of the following is the home to the training academy of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP)?",
        "choices": [
            "Edmonton",
            "Winnipeg",
            "Regina",
            "Saskatoon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Regina, the capital, is home to the training academy of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police. Saskatoon, the largest city, is the headquarters of the mining industry and an important educational, research and technology centre.",
        "answer": "Regina"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b88",
        "question": "In Canada, how are the rules made?",
        "choices": [
            "By elected representatives",
            "By the Queen",
            "By the people",
            "By the Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is governed by an organized system of laws. These laws are the written rules intended to guide people in our society. They are made by elected representatives.",
        "answer": "By elected representatives"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b89",
        "question": "What are the two guiding principles of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The supremacy of law and the rule of God",
            "Mobility right and the rule of law",
            "The supremacy of God and freedom of speech",
            "The supremacy of God and the rule of law"
        ],
        "explanation": "“Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law.” This phrase underlines the importance of religious traditions to Canadian society and the dignity and worth of the human person.",
        "answer": "The supremacy of God and the rule of law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8a",
        "question": "In Canada, how are individuals and governments regulated?",
        "choices": [
            "By traditions",
            "By force",
            "By laws",
            "By arbitrary actions"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of Canada’s founding principles is the rule of law. Individuals and governments are regulated by laws and not by arbitrary actions. No person or group is above the law.",
        "answer": "By laws"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8b",
        "question": "Who established the first European settlement north of Florida in 1604?",
        "choices": [
            "Jean Talon",
            "John Cabot",
            "Jacques Cartier",
            "Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1604, the first European settlement north of Florida was established by French explorers Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain, first on St. Croix Island (in present-day Maine), then at Port-Royal, in Acadia (present-day Nova Scotia).",
        "answer": "Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8c",
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Canadian national motto, \"A Mari Usque Ad Mare\"?",
        "choices": [
            "\"From sea to sea\"",
            "From east to west",
            "From land to land",
            "From mountains to sea"
        ],
        "explanation": "As an expression of national pride after the First World War, Canada adopted an official coat of arms and a national motto, A mari usque ad mare, which in Latin means “from sea to sea.” The arms contain symbols of England, France, Scotland and Ireland as well as red maple leaves.",
        "answer": "\"From sea to sea\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8d",
        "question": "How can a bill become a law in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "It passed by Senate and receives royal assent",
            "It passed by the House of Common and receives royal assent",
            "It is passed by both chambers and receives royal assent",
            "The people vote in favour of the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "No bill can become law in Canada until it has been passed by both chambers and has received royal assent, granted by the Governor General on behalf of the Sovereign.",
        "answer": "It is passed by both chambers and receives royal assent"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8e",
        "question": "In the Canadian justice system, what is the \"presumption of innocence\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Women are innocent until proven guilty",
            "Most people are guilty until they prove it",
            "Some people are innocent until proven otherwise",
            "Everyone is innocent until proven guilty"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Canadian justice system guarantees everyone due process under the law. Our judicial system is founded on the presumption of innocence in criminal matters, meaning everyone is innocent until proven guilty.",
        "answer": "Everyone is innocent until proven guilty"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b79",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of a territorial or provincial elected official?",
        "choices": [
            "Education",
            "Criminal Justice",
            "Citizenship",
            "Aboriginal Affairs"
        ],
        "explanation": "The provinces are responsible for municipal government, education, health, natural resources, property and civil rights, and highways.",
        "answer": "Education"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b91",
        "question": "Which of the following does not contain the Canadian coat of arms?",
        "choices": [
            "Government documents",
            "Dollar bills",
            "RCMP logo",
            "Public buildings"
        ],
        "explanation": "The arms contain symbols of England, France, Scotland and Ireland as well as red maple leaves. Today the arms can be seen on dollar bills, government documents and public buildings.",
        "answer": "RCMP logo"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b78",
        "question": "What area does a \"by-law\" apply to in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The local community",
            "The territory",
            "The entire country",
            "The province"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipal governments usually have a council that passes laws called “by-laws” that affect only the local community. The council usually includes a mayor (or a reeve) and councillors or aldermen.",
        "answer": "The local community"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b92",
        "question": "What is traditionally known as \"the world’s longest undefended border\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Great Wall of China",
            "Canada-U.S.A border",
            "Mexico-U.S.A border",
            "Both Canadian Atlantic and Pacific coasts"
        ],
        "explanation": "Over three-quarters of Canadian exports are destined for the U.S.A. In fact we have the biggest bilateral trading relationship in the world. Integrated Canada-U.S.A. supply chains compete with the rest of the world. Canada exports billions of dollars worth of energy products, industrial goods, machinery, equipment, automotive, agricultural, fishing and forestry products, and consumer goods every year.Millions of Canadians and Americans cross every year and in safety what is traditionally known as “the world’s longest undefended border.”",
        "answer": "Canada-U.S.A border"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b93",
        "question": "When was the Free Trade agreement signed with the United States?",
        "choices": [
            "1905",
            "1814",
            "1810",
            "1988"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1988, Canada enacted free trade with the United States. Mexico became a partner in 1994 in the broader North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), with over 444 million people and over $1 trillion in merchandise trade in 2008.",
        "answer": "1988"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b94",
        "question": "What began Canada’s modern energy industry in 1947?",
        "choices": [
            "The discovery of hydro-electricity in British Columbia",
            "The discovery of coal in Manitoba",
            "The discovery of oil in Alberta",
            "The Energy Bill passed by the House of Common"
        ],
        "explanation": "The discovery of oil in Alberta in 1947 began Canada’s modern energy industry. In 1951, for the first time, a majority of Canadians were able to afford adequate food, shelter and clothing.",
        "answer": "The discovery of oil in Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b95",
        "question": "When did the French and the Iroquois make peace?",
        "choices": [
            "1601",
            "1754",
            "1701",
            "1801"
        ],
        "explanation": "Champlain allied the colony with the Algonquin, Montagnais and Huron, historic enemies of the Iroquois, a confederation of five (later six) First Nations who battled with the French settlements for a century. The French and the Iroquois made peace in 1701.",
        "answer": "1701"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b97",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of a territorial or provincial elected official?",
        "choices": [
            "Property and Civil Rights",
            "Highways",
            "Natural Resources",
            "Foreign Policy"
        ],
        "explanation": "In our federal state, the federal government takes responsibility for matters of national and international concern. These include defence, foreign policy, interprovincial trade and communications, currency, navigation, criminal law and citizenship.",
        "answer": "Foreign Policy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b96",
        "question": "In which province(s) does the RCMP not serve as the provincial police?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "Manitoba and Alberta",
            "Ontario and Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) enforce federal laws throughout Canada, and serve as the provincial police in all provinces and territories except Ontario and Quebec, as well as in some municipalities.",
        "answer": "Ontario and Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b98",
        "question": "When were the majority of Canadians able to afford adequate food, shelter and clothing for the first time?",
        "choices": [
            "1954",
            "1949",
            "1951",
            "1945"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1951, for the first time, a majority of Canadians were able to afford adequate food, shelter and clothing.",
        "answer": "1951"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b99",
        "question": "Canada is not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada joined with other democratic countries of the West to form the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), a military alliance, and with the United States in the North American Aerospace Defence Command (NORAD).",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9a",
        "question": "What is an electoral district?",
        "choices": [
            "The area in which elections are held",
            "The building in which the voting poll is located",
            "A geographical area represented by a member of Parliament",
            "The government office in which you register for voting"
        ],
        "explanation": "An electoral district is a geographical area represented by a member of Parliament (MP).",
        "answer": "A geographical area represented by a member of Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9b",
        "question": "What represents a significant part of the economy of the Yukon?",
        "choices": [
            "Mining",
            "Hunting",
            "Trapping",
            "Fishing"
        ],
        "explanation": "Thousands of miners came to the Yukon during the Gold Rush of the 1890s, as celebrated in the poetry of Robert W. Service. Mining remains a significant part of the economy.",
        "answer": "Mining"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9c",
        "question": "When is Sir John A. Macdonald Day celebrated in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "February 11th",
            "January 4th",
            "November 11th",
            "January 11th"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir John A. Macdonald was a lawyer in Kingston, Ontario, a gifted politician and a colourful personality. Parliament has recognized January 11 as Sir John A. Macdonald Day. His portrait is on the $10 bill.",
        "answer": "January 11th"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9e",
        "question": "In Canada, we formally pledge allegiance to the Sovereign (King or Queen).",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, we profess our loyalty to a person who represents all Canadians and not to a document such as a constitution, a banner such as a flag, or a geopolitical entity such as a country.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba0",
        "question": "For what did the first companies in Canada compete?",
        "choices": [
            "Silver",
            "Timber",
            "Gold",
            "Fur"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first companies in Canada were formed during the French and British regimes and competed for the fur trade.",
        "answer": "Fur"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9d",
        "question": "Name one source of Canadian law.",
        "choices": [
            "English common law",
            "United States common law",
            "The military code of France",
            "Irish common law"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian law is derived from a variety of sources, including laws passed by Parliament and provincial legislatures, English common law, the French civil code, and the unwritten constitution that we inherited from the United Kingdom.",
        "answer": "English common law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b9f",
        "question": "Which of the following is a person of letters who had a significant cultural impact?",
        "choices": [
            "Kenojuak Ashevak",
            "Jean-Paul Riopelle",
            "Sir Ernest MacMillan",
            "Pauline Johnson"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians have made significant contributions to literature in English and in French. Novelists, poets, historians, educators and musicians have had a significant cultural impact. Men and women of letters included Stephen Leacock, Louis Hémon, Sir Charles G.D. Roberts, Pauline Johnson, Émile Nelligan, Robertson Davies, Margaret Laurence and Mordecai Richler.",
        "answer": "Pauline Johnson"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba2",
        "question": "If you cannot pay for a lawyer, how can you get legal help?",
        "choices": [
            "Go to the Police",
            "Go to legal aid services available in most communities",
            "Borrow money from the government",
            "Apply for financial aid with the Court"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lawyers can help you with legal problems and act for you in court. If you cannot pay for a lawyer, in most communities there are legal aid services available free of charge or at a low cost.",
        "answer": "Go to legal aid services available in most communities"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba1",
        "question": "What is \"Habeas corpus\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The right for peaceful assembly",
            "The right to challenge unlawful detention by the state",
            "The right to live and work anywhere within Canada",
            "The right to speak freely in Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "Habeas corpus, the right to challenge unlawful detention by the state, comes from English common law.",
        "answer": "The right to challenge unlawful detention by the state"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba3",
        "question": "What is Canada’s second most popular sport?",
        "choices": [
            "Basketball",
            "Curling",
            "Football",
            "Ice hockey"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian football is the second most popular sport in Canada.",
        "answer": "Football"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba7",
        "question": "Which country lies on Canada’s southern border?",
        "choices": [
            "Mexico",
            "Washington",
            "U.S.A.",
            "Central America"
        ],
        "explanation": "U.S.A. lies on Canada’s southern border.",
        "answer": "U.S.A."
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba4",
        "question": "What are the three parts of Parliament?",
        "choices": [
            "Police, Senate and House of Commons",
            "Sovereign, Senate and House of Commons",
            "Sovereign, Premier and House of Commons",
            "Sovereign, Senate and House of Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "Parliament has three parts: the Sovereign (Queen or King), the Senate and the House of Commons. Provincial legislatures comprise the Lieutenant Governor and the elected Assembly.",
        "answer": "Sovereign, Senate and House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba6",
        "question": "What is a fundamental characteristic of the Canadian heritage and identity?",
        "choices": [
            "Maple Syrup",
            "Multiculturalism",
            "Habeas Corpus",
            "Hockey"
        ],
        "explanation": "A fundamental characteristic of the Canadian heritage and identity. Canadians celebrate the gift of one another’s presence and work hard to respect pluralism and live in harmony.",
        "answer": "Multiculturalism"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba5",
        "question": "Who were the English-speaking settlers?",
        "choices": [
            "Australians and British",
            "English, Irish and French",
            "English, Welsh, Scottish and Irish",
            "English, Welsh, Scottish and Metis"
        ],
        "explanation": "The basic way of life in English-speaking areas was established by hundreds of thousands of English, Welsh, Scottish and Irish settlers, soldiers and migrants from the 1600s to the 20th century.",
        "answer": "English, Welsh, Scottish and Irish"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba8",
        "question": "Since the 1800s, the majority of Canadians were born in:",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "China",
            "England",
            "Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The majority of Canadians were born in this country and this has been true since the 1800s. However, Canada is often referred to as a land of immigrants because, over the past 200 years, millions of newcomers have helped to build and defend our way of life.",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ba9",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of the RCMP in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Serve as the provincial police in all provinces and territories except Ontario and Quebec",
            "Enforce federal laws throughout Canada",
            "Serve as municipal police in all major cities in Canada",
            "Serve as the provincial police in some municipalities"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) enforce federal laws throughout Canada, and serve as the provincial police in all provinces and territories except Ontario and Quebec, as well as in some municipalities.",
        "answer": "Serve as municipal police in all major cities in Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8baa",
        "question": "When called to do so, serving on a jury is:",
        "choices": [
            "An option",
            "A legal requirement"
        ],
        "explanation": "When called to do so, you are legally required to serve. Serving on a jury is a privilege that makes the justice system work as it depends on impartial juries made up of citizens.",
        "answer": "A legal requirement"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bab",
        "question": "What are the regions of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Atlantic Provinces, Central Canada, Prairie Provinces, and West Coast",
            "South Provinces, Northern Canada, West Provinces, East Provinces, and Central Territories",
            "Atlantic Provinces, Central Canada, Prairie Provinces, West Coast and Northern Territories",
            "Ontario, Quebec, Prairie Provinces and Central Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada includes many different geographical areas and five distinct regions.- The Atlantic Provinces- Central Canada- The Prairie Provinces- The West Coast- The Northern Territories",
        "answer": "Atlantic Provinces, Central Canada, Prairie Provinces, West Coast and Northern Territories"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8baf",
        "question": "What is the name of the agency that produces the voters’ list?",
        "choices": [
            "Voting Canada",
            "Electives Canada",
            "Voters Canada",
            "Elections Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The voters’ lists used during federal elections and referendums are produced from the National Register of Electors by a neutral agency of Parliament called Elections Canada.",
        "answer": "Elections Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bac",
        "question": "Which province has the most extensive park system in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "British Columbia",
            "Ontario",
            "Yukon"
        ],
        "explanation": "The most valuable forestry industry in Canada. B.C. is also known for mining, fishing, and the fruit orchards and wine industry of the Okanagan Valley. B.C. has the most extensive park system in Canada, with approximately 600 provincial parks.",
        "answer": "British Columbia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb0",
        "question": "Who considers and reviews proposals for new laws?",
        "choices": [
            "The House of Commons and the Senate",
            "The Senate",
            "The House of Commons",
            "The Cabinet Ministers"
        ],
        "explanation": "Both the House of Commons and the Senate consider and review bills (proposals for new laws).",
        "answer": "The House of Commons and the Senate"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b8f",
        "question": "Which section of the Constitution summarize fundamental freedoms while also setting out additional rights?",
        "choices": [
            "The Canadian Charter of Freedoms",
            "The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms",
            "The British Charter of Rights and Freedoms",
            "The Canadian Charter of Rights"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Charter attempts to summarize fundamental freedoms while also setting out additional rights which includes:- Mobility Rights- Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights- Official Language Rights - Multiculturalism",
        "answer": "The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb1",
        "question": "Anglo-Quebecers have a heritage of:",
        "choices": [
            "150 years",
            "350 years",
            "250 years",
            "100 years"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons recognized in  2006 that the Quebecois form a nation within a united Canada. One million Anglo-Quebecers have a heritage of 250 years and form a vibrant part of the Quebec fabric.",
        "answer": "250 years"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8b90",
        "question": "When were Japanese first granted the right to vote?",
        "choices": [
            "1600",
            "1948",
            "1901",
            "1701"
        ],
        "explanation": "Most Canadians of Asian descent had in the past been denied the vote in federal and provincial elections. In 1948 the last of these, the Japanese Canadians, gained the right to vote.",
        "answer": "1948"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bad",
        "question": "What is the name of the National Anthem?",
        "choices": [
            "My Canada",
            "Eh Canada",
            "Oh Canadians",
            "O Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "O Canada was proclaimed as the national anthem in 1980. It was first sung in Québec City in 1880. French and English Canadians sing different words to the national anthem.",
        "answer": "O Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb3",
        "question": "What does \"Confederation\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "The joining of several British colonies to form a new country",
            "The joining of several cities to form a new province",
            "The split between the South and the North",
            "The joining of several provinces to form a new country"
        ],
        "explanation": "The old Province of Canada was split into two new provinces: Ontario and Quebec, which, together with New Brunswick and Nova Scotia, formed the new country called the Dominion of Canada.",
        "answer": "The joining of several provinces to form a new country"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb4",
        "question": "Who is Marjorie Turner-Bailey?",
        "choices": [
            "An Olympian and descendant of black Loyalists",
            "A famous Canadian settler",
            "The first woman to become Prime Minister",
            "The first Canadian female athlete"
        ],
        "explanation": "Olympian Marjorie Turner-Bailey of Nova Scotia is a descendant of black Loyalists, escaped slaves and freed men and women of African origin who in the 1780s fled to Canada from America, where slavery remained legal until 1863.",
        "answer": "An Olympian and descendant of black Loyalists"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb5",
        "question": "Which of the following statement is false",
        "choices": [
            "The Canadian flag is encompassed by the Sovereign",
            "The Sovereign is personified by Canada",
            "Canada is personified by the Sovereign",
            "In Canada, we do not profess our loyalty to the Sovereign"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, we profess our loyalty to a person who represents all Canadians and not to a document such as a constitution, a banner such as a flag, or a geopolitical entity such as a country. Canada is personified by the Sovereign just as the Sovereign is personified by Canada.",
        "answer": "In Canada, we do not profess our loyalty to the Sovereign"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb9",
        "question": "What does \"federalism\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "The different provinces can adopt policies tailored to their own populations",
            "The Federal government has the final decision over all matters",
            "Canada is a federal country",
            "The Federal Government has jurisdiction over certain matters"
        ],
        "explanation": "Federalism allows different provinces to adopt policies tailored to their own populations, and gives provinces the flexibility to experiment with new ideas and policies.",
        "answer": "The different provinces can adopt policies tailored to their own populations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bba",
        "question": "What is the name of the Royal Anthem of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Canada Honour the Queen",
            "Canada Save the Queen",
            "God Save the Queen",
            "God Save Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Anthem of Canada, “God Save the Queen (or King),” can be played or sung on any occasion when Canadians wish to honour the Sovereign.",
        "answer": "God Save the Queen"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb8",
        "question": "Who defeated Napoleon in 1815?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "The Duke of Wellington",
            "Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe",
            "Major-General Sir Isaac Brock"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Duke of Wellington sent some of his best soldiers to defend Canada in 1814. He then chose Bytown (Ottawa) as the endpoint of the Rideau Canal, part of a network of forts to prevent the U.S.A. from invading Canada again. Wellington, who defeated Napoleon in 1815, therefore played a direct role in founding the national capital.",
        "answer": "The Duke of Wellington"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bbb",
        "question": "Name three beliefs that have enabled Canadians to build a prosperous society in a rugged environment?",
        "choices": [
            "Ordered liberty, enterprise and buying houses",
            "Hard work, fair play and ordered liberty",
            "Outdoor life, hard work, and fair play",
            "Enterprise, hard work and driving cars"
        ],
        "explanation": "A belief in ordered liberty, enterprise, hard work and fair play has enabled Canadians to build a prosperous society in a rugged environment from our Atlantic shores to the Pacific Ocean and to the Arctic Circle—so much so that poets and songwriters have hailed Canada as the “Great Dominion.”",
        "answer": "Hard work, fair play and ordered liberty"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb6",
        "question": "To which industries do products such as paper, high technology equipment, aerospace technology, automobiles, machinery, food and clothing belong to?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural resources industries",
            "Manufacturing industries",
            "Trading Industries",
            "Service industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manufacturing industries make products to sell in Canada and around the world. Manufactured products include paper, high technology equipment, aerospace technology, automobiles, machinery, food, clothing and many other goods.",
        "answer": "Manufacturing industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb7",
        "question": "Who is Canada’s largest international trading partner?",
        "choices": [
            "Mexico",
            "United States",
            "Europe",
            "China"
        ],
        "explanation": "Our largest international trading partner is the United States.",
        "answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bbf",
        "question": "What is a \"hereditary Sovereign\"?",
        "choices": [
            "A Senator",
            "A Governor General",
            "A Queen or a King",
            "A Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "As a constitutional monarchy, Canada’s Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King), who reigns in accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law.",
        "answer": "A Queen or a King"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bbc",
        "question": "What is the \"House of Commons\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The representative chamber made up of Federal Deputies",
            "The representative chamber made up of Cabinet Ministers",
            "The representative chamber made up of Senators",
            "The representative chamber made up of members of Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons is the representative chamber, made up of members of Parliament elected by the people, traditionally every four years.",
        "answer": "The representative chamber made up of members of Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bbd",
        "question": "Who proclaimed the first territorial right guarantee for the First Nations?",
        "choices": [
            "King George I",
            "King George III",
            "Queen Elizabeth",
            "King George II"
        ],
        "explanation": "Territorial rights were first guaranteed through the Royal Proclamation of 1763 by King George III, and established the basis for negotiating treaties with the newcomers— treaties that were not always fully respected.",
        "answer": "King George III"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc4",
        "question": "In terms of size, how does Canada rank?",
        "choices": [
            "First largest country on earth",
            "Fourth largest country on earth",
            "Third largest country on earth",
            "Second largest country on earth"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is the second largest country on earth—10 million square kilometres. Three oceans line Canada’s frontiers: the Pacific Ocean in the west, the Atlantic Ocean in the east, and the Arctic Ocean to the north.",
        "answer": "Second largest country on earth"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc2",
        "question": "Canadians work hard to respect:",
        "choices": [
            "Capitalism",
            "Individualism",
            "Marxism",
            "Pluralism"
        ],
        "explanation": "A fundamental characteristic of the Canadian heritage and identity. Canadians celebrate the gift of one another’s presence and work hard to respect pluralism and live in harmony.",
        "answer": "Pluralism"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bbe",
        "question": "What does the Canadian justice system guarantee?",
        "choices": [
            "Quick process under the law",
            "Arbitrary process under the law",
            "Smooth process under the law",
            "Due process under the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Canadian justice system guarantees everyone due process under the law. Our judicial system is founded on the presumption of innocence in criminal matters, meaning everyone is innocent until proven guilty.",
        "answer": "Due process under the law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc3",
        "question": "When did the name of \"Canada\" begin appearing on maps?",
        "choices": [
            "By the 1550s",
            "By the 1650s",
            "By the 1750s",
            "By the 1580s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Cartier heard two captured guides speak the Iroquoian word kanata, meaning “village.” By the 1550s, the name of Canada began appearing on maps.",
        "answer": "By the 1550s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc0",
        "question": "Which of the following statements is false about the Canada-U.S.A. relationship?",
        "choices": [
            "They have the biggest bilateral trading relationship in the world",
            "Canada exports almost no goods to the U.S.A.",
            "Millions of Canadians and Americans cross every year the Canada-U.S.A. border",
            "They have the world's longest undefended border"
        ],
        "explanation": "Over three-quarters of Canadian exports are destined for the U.S.A. In fact we have the biggest bilateral trading relationship in the world. Integrated Canada-U.S.A. supply chains compete with the rest of the world. Canada exports billions of dollars worth of energy products, industrial goods, machinery, equipment, automotive, agricultural, fishing and forestry products, and consumer goods every year.Millions of Canadians and Americans cross every year and in safety what is traditionally known as “the world’s longest undefended border.”",
        "answer": "Canada exports almost no goods to the U.S.A."
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc1",
        "question": "What does \"federalism\" do?",
        "choices": [
            "Allows the Federal government to adopt policies for all provinces",
            "Allows different provinces to adopt policies tailored to their own populations",
            "Gives all the power to the Prime Minister",
            "Gives all the power to the federal government"
        ],
        "explanation": "Federalism allows different provinces to adopt policies tailored to their own populations, and gives provinces the flexibility to experiment with new ideas and policies.",
        "answer": "Allows different provinces to adopt policies tailored to their own populations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc5",
        "question": "What is the capital of Alberta?",
        "choices": [
            "Edmonton",
            "Regina",
            "Calgary",
            "Red Deer"
        ],
        "explanation": "Edmonton is the capital of Alberta.",
        "answer": "Edmonton"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc6",
        "question": "Why was the Peace Tower built in Ottawa?",
        "choices": [
            "In memory of the Second World War",
            "In memory of the First World War",
            "To portray Canada as a peaceful nation",
            "In memory of the war between Canada and the United States"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Peace Tower was completed in 1927 in memory of the First World War.",
        "answer": "In memory of the First World War"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc7",
        "question": "When were Aboriginal voting rights granted?",
        "choices": [
            "1801",
            "1980",
            "1960",
            "1700"
        ],
        "explanation": "Most Canadians of Asian descent had in the past been denied the vote in federal and provincial elections. In 1948 the last of these, the Japanese Canadians, gained the right to vote. Aboriginal people were granted the vote in 1960. Today every citizen over the age of 18 may vote.",
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bca",
        "question": "How much merchandise trade was involved within NAFTA in 2008?",
        "choices": [
            "Over $100 trillion",
            "About $100 billion",
            "About $500 billion",
            "Over $1 trillion"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1988, Canada enacted free trade with the United States. Mexico became a partner in 1994 in the broader North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), with over 444 million people and over $1 trillion in merchandise trade in 2008.",
        "answer": "Over $1 trillion"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc9",
        "question": "What are the responsibilities of the Cabinet?",
        "choices": [
            "International matters",
            "Education",
            "Prepare the budget and propose most new laws",
            "Natural Resources"
        ],
        "explanation": "They prepare the budget and propose most new laws. Their decisions can be questioned by all members of the House of Commons.",
        "answer": "Prepare the budget and propose most new laws"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bcd",
        "question": "Who is permitted unrestricted entry and exit from Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Canadian citizens",
            "Landed immigrants",
            "Commonwealth citizens",
            "British citizens"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians can live and work anywhere they choose in Canada, enter and leave the country freely, and apply for a passport.",
        "answer": "Canadian citizens"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bcb",
        "question": "During an election period, where is the location of your polling station indicated?",
        "choices": [
            "In your local Member of Parliament's office",
            "On your ballot",
            "On your voter information card",
            "Online"
        ],
        "explanation": "To vote either on election day or at advance polls, go to the polling station listed on your voter information card.",
        "answer": "On your voter information card"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bcc",
        "question": "Who established the first European settlements?",
        "choices": [
            "The Irish",
            "The French",
            "The English",
            "The Spanish"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1604, the first European settlement north of Florida was established by French explorers Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain, first on St. Croix Island (in present-day Maine), then at Port-Royal, in Acadia (present-day Nova Scotia).",
        "answer": "The French"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bc8",
        "question": "What percentage of Aboriginal people are Metis?",
        "choices": [
            "65",
            "40",
            "30",
            "4"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 65% of the Aboriginal people are First Nations, while 30% are Métis and 4% Inuit.",
        "answer": "30"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bce",
        "question": "Which animal is an official symbol of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The eagle",
            "The bear",
            "The moose",
            "The beaver"
        ],
        "explanation": "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a symbol of the Hudson’s Bay Company. It became an emblem of the St. Jean Baptiste Society, a French-Canadian patriotic association, in 1834, and was also adopted by other groups.",
        "answer": "The beaver"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bae",
        "question": "Which of the following is not allowed by a non-Canadian Citizen?",
        "choices": [
            "Drive a car",
            "Own a house",
            "Vote in a federal or provincial election",
            "Go to University"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of the privileges of Canadian citizenship is the right to vote. You are eligible to vote in a federal election or cast a ballot in a federal referendum if you are:- a Canadian citizen; and- at least 18 years old on voting day; and- on the voters’ list",
        "answer": "Vote in a federal or provincial election"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bb2",
        "question": "What percentage of Aboriginal people are Inuit?",
        "choices": [
            "30",
            "65",
            "20",
            "4"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 65% of the Aboriginal people are First Nations, while 30% are Métis and 4% Inuit.",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bcf",
        "question": "How does Canada’s Head of State reign?",
        "choices": [
            "By making decision alone",
            "In accordance with the British Constitution only",
            "In accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law",
            "By directly governing the country"
        ],
        "explanation": "As a constitutional monarchy, Canada’s Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King), who reigns in accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law.",
        "answer": "In accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd2",
        "question": "What does a vote by secret ballot mean?",
        "choices": [
            "You must not tell anyone who you voted for",
            "No one can watch you vote except the election officials",
            "No one can watch you vote and no one should look at how you voted",
            "You can only show your ballot to one person"
        ],
        "explanation": "You may choose to discuss how you voted with others, but no one, including family members, your employer or union representative, has the right to insist that you tell them how you voted.",
        "answer": "No one can watch you vote and no one should look at how you voted"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd3",
        "question": "How many judges on the Supreme Court of Canada are appointed by the Governor General?",
        "choices": [
            "Five",
            "Nine",
            "Three",
            "Twelve"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Court was originally composed of six judges. In 1927, the number of Supreme Court judges was raised to seven, and the Court reached its present total of nine members in 1949.",
        "answer": "Nine"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd8",
        "question": "What marked the end of France’s empire in America in the 1700s?",
        "choices": [
            "The British invaded Quebec City",
            "English colonies became more populated than French colonies",
            "the British defeated the French in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham at Quebec City",
            "The French defeated the English in warfare"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the 1700s France and Great Britain battled for control of North America. In 1759, the British defeated the French in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham at Québec City — marking the end of France’s empire in America.",
        "answer": "the British defeated the French in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham at Quebec City"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd5",
        "question": "How much of Canadian exports are destined for the U.S.A.?",
        "choices": [
            "Two-third",
            "Over three-quarters",
            "Half",
            "Over one-third"
        ],
        "explanation": "Over three-quarters of Canadian exports are destined for the U.S.A. In fact we have the biggest bilateral trading relationship in the world.",
        "answer": "Over three-quarters"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd6",
        "question": "Who pioneered modern Inuit art?",
        "choices": [
            "Jean-Paul Riopelle",
            "Louis-Philippe Hebert",
            "Kenojuak Ashevak",
            "Emily Carr"
        ],
        "explanation": "Kenojuak Ashevak pioneered modern Inuit art with etchings, prints and soapstone sculptures.",
        "answer": "Kenojuak Ashevak"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd4",
        "question": "Who has the right to vote in a federal election?",
        "choices": [
            "Adult Canadian citizens and permanent residents",
            "Canadian citizens on the voters' list",
            "An adult Canadian citizen",
            "A Canadian citizen, at least 18 years old on voting day and on the voters' list"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of the privileges of Canadian citizenship is the right to vote. You are eligible to vote in a federal election or cast a ballot in a federal referendum if you are:- a Canadian citizen; and- at least 18 years old on voting day; and- on the voters’ list.",
        "answer": "A Canadian citizen, at least 18 years old on voting day and on the voters' list"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd7",
        "question": "Every province has its own elected Legislative Assembly",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Every province has its own elected Legislative Assembly, like the House of Commons in Ottawa.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bda",
        "question": "What is Canada’s most popular spectator sport?",
        "choices": [
            "Ice skating",
            "Ice hockey",
            "Table Tennis",
            "Football"
        ],
        "explanation": "Hockey is Canada’s most popular spectator sport and is considered to be the national winter sport. Ice hockey was developed in Canada in the 1800s.",
        "answer": "Ice hockey"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd9",
        "question": "On election day, what happens when the polls close?",
        "choices": [
            "No ballot gets counted for 24 hours",
            "No ballot gets counted for 48 hours",
            "Every ballot is counted and the results are kept secret for 48 hours",
            "Every ballot is counted and the results are made public"
        ],
        "explanation": "When the polls close, every ballot is counted and the results are made public. You can see the results on television or on the Elections Canada website (www.elections.ca).",
        "answer": "Every ballot is counted and the results are made public"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bdd",
        "question": "In Canada, you can question the police about their service or conduct if you feel the need.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "You can also question the police about their service or conduct if you feel you need to. Almost all police forces in Canada have a process by which you can bring your concerns to the police and seek action.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bdb",
        "question": "Who has the right to run as a candidate in federal elections?",
        "choices": [
            "Canadian citizens and landed immigrants",
            "Canadian citizens",
            "Canadian citizens who are 18 years old or older",
            "Canadian citizens who are 16 years or older"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian citizens who are 18 years old or older may run in a federal election. The people who run for office are called candidates. There can be many candidates in an electoral district.",
        "answer": "Canadian citizens who are 18 years old or older"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bdc",
        "question": "As what have poets and songwriters hailed Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The \"Great Dominion\"",
            "Peace, Order and Good Government",
            "The \"Great Outdoors\"",
            "The \"Land of the Brave\""
        ],
        "explanation": "A belief in ordered liberty, enterprise, hard work and fair play has enabled Canadians to build a prosperous society in a rugged environment from our Atlantic shores to the Pacific Ocean and to the Arctic Circle—so much so that poets and songwriters have hailed Canada as the “Great Dominion.”",
        "answer": "The \"Great Dominion\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be0",
        "question": "When were the Parliament buildings completed?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1820s",
            "In the 1860s",
            "In the 1780s",
            "In the 1920s"
        ],
        "explanation": "The buildings were completed in the 1860s. The Centre Block was destroyed by an accidental fire in 1916 and rebuilt in 1922.",
        "answer": "In the 1860s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be1",
        "question": "How are senators chosen?",
        "choices": [
            "They are appointed by the House of Commons",
            "They are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister",
            "They are appointed by the Prime Minister",
            "They are elected by the people"
        ],
        "explanation": "Senators are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister and serve until age 75.",
        "answer": "They are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be3",
        "question": "Why can a woman have the same education as any guy as a new immigrant to Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Because she probably has a university degree",
            "Because in Canada, men and women are equal under the law",
            "Because her husband approved it",
            "Because she is from France"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, men and women are equal under the law. Canada’s openness and generosity do not extend to barbaric cultural practices that tolerate spousal abuse.",
        "answer": "Because in Canada, men and women are equal under the law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be2",
        "question": "Which natives preserved fish by drying and smoking?",
        "choices": [
            "West Coast natives",
            "East Coast Natives",
            "Northern Natives",
            "Interior Natives"
        ],
        "explanation": "West Coast natives preserved fish by drying and smoking. Warfare was common among Aboriginal groups as they competed for land, resources and prestige.",
        "answer": "West Coast natives"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bdf",
        "question": "In Quebec, how many people speak French as their first language?",
        "choices": [
            "About one-third",
            "1",
            "Less than half",
            "More than three-quarters"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nearly eight million people live in Quebec, the vast majority along or near the St. Lawrence River. More than three-quarters speak French as their first language",
        "answer": "More than three-quarters"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bde",
        "question": "Which Canadian city is called the \"diamond capital of North America\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Edmonton",
            "Calgary",
            "Yellowknife",
            "Whitehorse"
        ],
        "explanation": "Yellowknife (population 20,000), is called the “diamond capital of North America.” More than half the population is Aboriginal (Dene, Inuit and Métis).",
        "answer": "Yellowknife"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be4",
        "question": "For what is the Victoria Cross awarded?",
        "choices": [
            "The most conspicuous bravery or self-sacrifice in the presence of the enemy",
            "The best hockey player in the Stanley Cup",
            "The most brilliant scientific research",
            "The best Canadian film-making of the year"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Victoria Cross (V.C.) is the highest honour available to Canadians and is awarded for the most conspicuous bravery, a daring or pre-eminent act of valour or self-sacrifice, or extreme devotion to duty in the presence of the enemy.",
        "answer": "The most conspicuous bravery or self-sacrifice in the presence of the enemy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be5",
        "question": "In Canada, what is the definition of \"law\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The written rules intended to guide people in our society",
            "The oral rules intended to guide people in our society",
            "The rules only applicable to a certain category of people",
            "The rules intended to punish people whenever possible"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is governed by an organized system of laws. These laws are the written rules intended to guide people in our society.",
        "answer": "The written rules intended to guide people in our society"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be6",
        "question": "What does \"constitutional monarchy\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "Canada's Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King)",
            "The Sovereign (Queen or King) has the constitutional rights to make laws in Canada",
            "The responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments are constitutional",
            "Freedom of speech and mobility"
        ],
        "explanation": "As a constitutional monarchy, Canada’s Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King), who reigns in accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law.",
        "answer": "Canada's Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King)"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be8",
        "question": "When did the federal government place many Aboriginal children in residential schools?",
        "choices": [
            "From the 1700s until the 1980s",
            "From the 1800s until the 1980s",
            "From the beginning of the 1900s until the 1980s",
            "From the 1700s until the 1970s"
        ],
        "explanation": "From the 1800s until the 1980s, the federal government placed many Aboriginal children in residential schools to educate and assimilate them into mainstream Canadian culture. The schools were poorly funded and inflicted hardship on the students. Ottawa formally apologized to the former students.",
        "answer": "From the 1800s until the 1980s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be7",
        "question": "Of the following, which one is not a part of the Great Charter of Freedom?",
        "choices": [
            "Freedom of conscience and religion",
            "Freedom to buy property",
            "Freedom of association",
            "Freedom of thought, belief, opinion and expression."
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) includes:- Freedom of conscience and religion;- Freedom of thought, belief, opinion and expression, including freedom of speech and of the press.- Freedom of peaceful assembly- Freedom of association",
        "answer": "Freedom to buy property"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bea",
        "question": "Who appoints the judges on the Supreme Court of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The Sovereign",
            "The Governor General",
            "The Senate"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Governor General is responsible for assigning nine judges to the Supreme Court of Canada.",
        "answer": "The Governor General"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bec",
        "question": "When was introduced Unemployment insurance (now called \"employment insurance\")?",
        "choices": [
            "1970",
            "1965",
            "1940",
            "1927"
        ],
        "explanation": "Unemployment insurance (now called “employment insurance”) was introduced by the federal government in 1940. Old Age Security was devised as early as 1927, and the Canada and Quebec Pension Plans in 1965.",
        "answer": "1940"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8be9",
        "question": "Which two of the following are Great Lakes?",
        "choices": [
            "Lake Hudson and Lake Michigan",
            "Lake Hudson and Lake Erie",
            "Lake Ontario and Lake Erie",
            "Lake Superior and Lake Lawrence"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are five Great Lakes located between Ontario and the United States: Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake Michigan (in the U.S.A.) and Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world.",
        "answer": "Lake Ontario and Lake Erie"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8beb",
        "question": "In becoming Canadian, which principles are newcomers expected to embrace?",
        "choices": [
            "Democratic",
            "Libertarian",
            "Capitalist",
            "Liberalist"
        ],
        "explanation": "Some Canadians immigrate from places where they have experienced warfare or conflict. Such experiences do not justify bringing to Canada violent, extreme or hateful prejudices. In becoming Canadian, newcomers are expected to embrace democratic principles such as the rule of law.",
        "answer": "Democratic"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bee",
        "question": "What is the highest honour available to Canadians?",
        "choices": [
            "The Royal Cross",
            "The British Cross",
            "The Victoria Cross",
            "The Canadian Cross"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Victoria Cross (V.C.) is the highest honour available to Canadians and is awarded for the most conspicuous bravery, a daring or pre-eminent act of valour or self-sacrifice, or extreme devotion to duty in the presence of the enemy.",
        "answer": "The Victoria Cross"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bed",
        "question": "Insulin was discovered by a Canadian",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Frederick Banting of Toronto and Charles Best discovered insulin, a hormone to treat diabetes that has saved 16 million lives worldwide.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf1",
        "question": "When was the Alberta Oil rush?",
        "choices": [
            "1947",
            "1990",
            "2000",
            "1600"
        ],
        "explanation": "The discovery of oil in Alberta in 1947 began Canada’s modern energy industry. In 1951, for the first time, a majority of Canadians were able to afford adequate food, shelter and clothing.",
        "answer": "1947"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf2",
        "question": "Canadian football is absolutely identical to American football",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian football is a popular game that differs in a number of ways from American football.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf0",
        "question": "What does the Great Charter of Freedom include?",
        "choices": [
            "Employment rights",
            "Aboriginal Peoples' rights",
            "Freedom of conscience and religion",
            "Freedom from taxes"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) includes:- Freedom of conscience and religion;- Freedom of thought, belief, opinion and expression, including freedom of speech and of the press.- Freedom of peaceful assembly- Freedom of association",
        "answer": "Freedom of conscience and religion"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bef",
        "question": "When do Canadians celebrate Thanksgiving?",
        "choices": [
            "Second Monday of November",
            "Third Monday of October",
            "Second Monday of October",
            "Second Tuesday of October"
        ],
        "explanation": "Thanksgiving is on the second Monday of October.",
        "answer": "Second Monday of October"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf8",
        "question": "Which of the following defines Central Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec and Manitoba",
            "Manitoba and Saskatchewan",
            "Quebec and Ontario",
            "Ontario and Saskatchewan"
        ],
        "explanation": "More than half the people in Canada live in cities and towns near the Great Lakes and the St. Lawrence River in southern Quebec and Ontario, known as Central Canada and the industrial and manufacturing heartland.",
        "answer": "Quebec and Ontario"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf7",
        "question": "How many Anglophones are there in Canada today?",
        "choices": [
            "5 million",
            "18 million",
            "10 million",
            "50 million"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, there are 18 million Anglophones—people who speak English as a first language—and seven million Francophones—people who speak French as their first language.",
        "answer": "18 million"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf5",
        "question": "What happens if the cabinet ministers are defeated in a non-confidence vote?",
        "choices": [
            "They have to resign",
            "Nothing",
            "They keep their positions for 6 more months only",
            "They keep their positions for one more year only"
        ],
        "explanation": "If the government loses a confidence vote in the assembly it must resign.",
        "answer": "They have to resign"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf4",
        "question": "How are the results of an election announced in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Announced on radio, on television, and in the newspapers",
            "Announced on television",
            "Announced on radio",
            "Announced in the newspaper"
        ],
        "explanation": "Immediately after the polling stations close, election officers count the ballots and the results are announced on radio and television, and in the newspapers.",
        "answer": "Announced on radio, on television, and in the newspapers"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf3",
        "question": "On election day, what should you bring to the polling station?",
        "choices": [
            "The voter information card",
            "Nothing",
            "A piece of identification",
            "The voter information card and proof of your identity and address"
        ],
        "explanation": "On election day, bring the voter information card and proof of your identity and address.",
        "answer": "The voter information card and proof of your identity and address"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf6",
        "question": "Who are the three founding peoples of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Aboriginal, French, and British",
            "British, Metis and Aboriginal",
            "Aboriginal, Metis and Inuit",
            "Early settlers, Metis and Inuit"
        ],
        "explanation": "The three founding peoples of Canada are the Aboriginal, French and British.",
        "answer": "Aboriginal, French, and British"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bf9",
        "question": "What is the key phrase in Canada’s original constitutional document?",
        "choices": [
            "Peace, Order and Good Government",
            "Peace, Order and Mobility Rights",
            "Work, Order and Good Government",
            "Government, Work and Good Order"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s institutions uphold a commitment to Peace, Order and Good Government, a key phrase in Canada’s original constitutional document in 1867, the British North America Act.",
        "answer": "Peace, Order and Good Government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd1",
        "question": "What happens if you are not listed in the National Register of Electors?",
        "choices": [
            "You can still be added to the voters' list at any time, excluding election day",
            "You won't be able to vote",
            "You can still be added to the voters' list but only on election day",
            "You can still be added to the voters' list at any time, including election day"
        ],
        "explanation": "Even if you choose not to be listed in the National Register of Electors or do not receive a voter information card, you can still be added to the voters’ list at any time, including on election day.",
        "answer": "You can still be added to the voters' list at any time, including election day"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bfc",
        "question": "Who is known as \"the greatest living Canadian\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Dr. Wilder Penfield",
            "Sir Sandford Fleming",
            "Terry Fox"
        ],
        "explanation": "Dr. Wilder Penfield — was a pioneering brain surgeon at McGill University in Montreal, and was known as “the greatest living Canadian.”",
        "answer": "Dr. Wilder Penfield"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bfb",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what does MLA stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Municipal Legislative Assembly",
            "Members of the Legal Assembly",
            "Municipal Legal Action",
            "Members of the Legislative Assembly"
        ],
        "explanation": "The members of the legislature are called members of the Legislative Assembly (MLAs), members of the National Assembly (MNAs), members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs) or members of the House of Assembly (MHAs), depending on the province or territory.",
        "answer": "Members of the Legislative Assembly"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bfd",
        "question": "What is the system \"if the government loses a confidence vote in the assembly it must resign\" called?",
        "choices": [
            "A vote-based government",
            "An assembly government",
            "A confident government",
            "A responsible government"
        ],
        "explanation": "This is the system that we have today: if the government loses a confidence vote in the assembly it must resign.",
        "answer": "A responsible government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bfe",
        "question": "Which province is Canada’s largest producer of hydroelectricity?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "British Columbia",
            "Manitoba",
            "Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec produces the most hydroelectricity in Canada, with British Columbia, Manitoba, Newfoundland and Labrador, and Ontario also producing large amounts.   te",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bff",
        "question": "What does RCMP stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Roy's Corona Military Police",
            "Royal California Miller Protection",
            "Royal Canadian Mounted Police",
            "Registered Canadian Mounted Police"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP or “the Mounties”) are the national police force and one of Canada’s best-known symbols.",
        "answer": "Royal Canadian Mounted Police"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c00",
        "question": "Canada is a member of the United Nations (UN)",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada joined international organizations such as the United Nations (UN). It participated in the UN operation defending South Korea in the Korean War (1950–53), with 500 dead and 1,000 wounded.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c04",
        "question": "Who declared independence in 1776 and formed the United States?",
        "choices": [
            "The ten British colonies to the south of Quebec",
            "All the French colonies",
            "All British Colonies in Canada",
            "The thirteen British colonies to the south of Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1776, the 13 British colonies to the south of Quebec declared independence and formed the United States. North America was again divided by war. More than 40,000 people loyal to the Crown, called “Loyalists,” fled the oppression of the American Revolution to settle in Nova Scotia and Quebec.",
        "answer": "The thirteen British colonies to the south of Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c05",
        "question": "The \"right to contest unlawful detention by the state\" is known as what?",
        "choices": [
            "Habeas corpus",
            "A mari usque ad mare",
            "Magna Carta",
            "Constitutional Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "Habeas corpus, the right to challenge unlawful detention by the state, comes from English common law.",
        "answer": "Habeas corpus"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c01",
        "question": "How were the laws impacted by the Quebec Act of 1774?",
        "choices": [
            "The Act cancelled French civil law while maintaining British criminal law",
            "The Act restored French civil law while maintaining British criminal law",
            "The Act restored British civil law while maintaining French criminal law",
            "The Act cancelled all British Laws in Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "To better govern the French Roman Catholic majority, the British Parliament passed the Quebec Act of 1774. One of the constitutional foundations of Canada, the Quebec Act accommodated the principles of British institutions to the reality of the province.It allowed religious freedom for Catholics and permitted them to hold public office, a practice not then allowed in Britain.",
        "answer": "The Act restored French civil law while maintaining British criminal law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c02",
        "question": "What information does the Elector Card contain?",
        "choices": [
            "When and where to vote and the number to call if an interpreter or other special services are required",
            "The elector's name",
            "When and where to vote",
            "The number to call if an interpreter or other special services are required"
        ],
        "explanation": "Once an election has been called, Elections Canada mails a voter information card to each elector whose name is in the National Register of Electors. The card lists when and where you vote and the number to call if you require an interpreter or other special services.",
        "answer": "When and where to vote and the number to call if an interpreter or other special services are required"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bd0",
        "question": "Who first adopted the maple leaf as a symbol in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "French-Canadians",
            "English",
            "Irish",
            "Metis"
        ],
        "explanation": "The maple leaf is Canada’s best-known symbol. Maple leaves were adopted as a symbol by French Canadians in the 1700s, have appeared on Canadian uniforms and insignia since the 1850s, and are carved into the headstones of our fallen soldiers buried overseas and in Canada.",
        "answer": "French-Canadians"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c03",
        "question": "Which of the following are Atlantic Provinces?",
        "choices": [
            "Newfoundland and Labrador, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island",
            "Ontario, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Labrador",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador, Prince Edward Island, New Brunswick and Quebec",
            "Newfoundland, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Atlantic Provinces are Newfoundland and Labrador, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c08",
        "question": "What was the main economy of the early Europeans settlers?",
        "choices": [
            "Farming",
            "Timber",
            "Fur trade",
            "Mining"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first companies in Canada were formed during the French and British regimes and competed for the fur trade.",
        "answer": "Fur trade"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c07",
        "question": "What do Canadians vote for in a federal election?",
        "choices": [
            "A person to become the Premier of Canada",
            "The people they want to represent them in the House of Commons",
            "The Governor General they want to represent them in Canada",
            "All candidates in their electoral district"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians vote in elections for the people they want to represent them in the House of Commons. In each election, voters may re-elect the same members of the House of Commons or choose new ones.",
        "answer": "The people they want to represent them in the House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c09",
        "question": "Where are the names of soldiers, sailors and airmen, who died serving Canada in wars or while on duty, written?",
        "choices": [
            "The Library",
            "The Peace Arch",
            "The Memorial Chamber",
            "The Centre Block"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Memorial Chamber within the Tower contains the Books of Remembrance in which are written the names of soldiers, sailors and airmen who died serving Canada in wars or while on duty.",
        "answer": "The Memorial Chamber"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0c",
        "question": "How many Acadians were deported from their homeland during the war between Britain and France?",
        "choices": [
            "More than two thirds",
            "All of them",
            "About half",
            "About one-third"
        ],
        "explanation": "Between 1755 and 1763, during the war between Britain and France, more than two-thirds of the Acadians were deported from their homeland.",
        "answer": "More than two thirds"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0d",
        "question": "What are the responsibilities of the federal government?",
        "choices": [
            "Matters of national concern",
            "Matters of national and international concern",
            "Matters of provincial concern",
            "Matters of international concern"
        ],
        "explanation": "In our federal state, the federal government takes responsibility for matters of national and international concern.",
        "answer": "Matters of national and international concern"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0a",
        "question": "What is \"La Francophonie\"?",
        "choices": [
            "An association of French-speaking nations",
            "A traditional French music",
            "A region in Quebec",
            "A French-Canadian political party"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec films, music, literary works and food have international stature, especially in La Francophonie, an association of French-speaking nations. Montreal, Canada’s second largest city and the second largest mainly French-speaking city in the world after Paris, is famous for its cultural diversity.",
        "answer": "An association of French-speaking nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0b",
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a provincial court?",
        "choices": [
            "Small claims court",
            "Court of Queen",
            "High court",
            "Traffic court"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are also provincial courts for lesser offences, family courts, traffic courts and small claims courts for civil cases involving small sums of money.",
        "answer": "Court of Queen"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c11",
        "question": "When did the British Parliament abolish slavery throughout the Empire?",
        "choices": [
            "1807",
            "1853",
            "1833",
            "1793"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1807, the British Parliament prohibited the buying and selling of slaves, and in 1833 abolished slavery throughout the Empire.",
        "answer": "1833"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c13",
        "question": "When was ice hockey developed in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1700s",
            "In the 1900s",
            "In the 1800s",
            "In the 1600s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ice hockey was developed in Canada in the 1800s. The National Hockey League plays for the championship Stanley Cup, donated by Lord Stanley, the Governor General, in 1892.",
        "answer": "In the 1800s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0e",
        "question": "Basketball was invented by a Canadian",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Basketball was invented by Canadian James Naismith in 1891.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c10",
        "question": "Which of the following statements regarding citizenship applications is false?",
        "choices": [
            "Officials will make sure you adhere to the rules.",
            "Officials will examine your status",
            "You'll be asked for presents or cash by officials.",
            "Officials will verify that you are not prohibited from applying"
        ],
        "explanation": "When you apply for citizenship, officials will check your status, verify that you are not prohibited from applying, and ensure that you meet the requirements.",
        "answer": "You'll be asked for presents or cash by officials."
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c0f",
        "question": "The Great Charter of Freedoms was signed in:",
        "choices": [
            "Ireland",
            "France",
            "England",
            "Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) was signed in the year 1215 in England.",
        "answer": "England"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c12",
        "question": "When did the House of Commons recognize that the Quebecois form a nation within a united Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "2006",
            "1972",
            "2001",
            "1986"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons recognized in 2006 that the Quebecois form a nation within a united Canada.",
        "answer": "2006"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c14",
        "question": "Which of the following is a criterion to become a Canadian citizen?",
        "choices": [
            "Have a Canadian driving license",
            "Own property in Canada",
            "Play hockey",
            "Have adequate knowledge of English or French"
        ],
        "explanation": "Immigrants between the ages of 18 and 54 must have adequate knowledge of English or French in order to become Canadian citizens.",
        "answer": "Have adequate knowledge of English or French"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c15",
        "question": "What are the levels of government in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Federal, provincial, territorial and municipal",
            "Federal and provincial",
            "Federal, provincial, and territorial",
            "Provincial, territorial and municipal"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are federal, provincial, territorial and municipal governments in Canada. The responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments were defined in 1867 in the British North America Act, now known as the Constitution Act, 1867.",
        "answer": "Federal, provincial, territorial and municipal"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c16",
        "question": "Who is the King of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Her Majesty Queen Anne the Second",
            "Her Majesty Queen Victoria",
            "His Majesty King Charles the Third",
            "Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth the Second"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy whereby the Sovereign is Canada’s Head of State. King Charles III automatically became Sovereign of Canada on the passing of his predecessor, Queen Elizabeth II.",
        "answer": "His Majesty King Charles the Third"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c18",
        "question": "Where is Canada’s largest naval base?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Vancouver"
        ],
        "explanation": "Halifax, Nova Scotia has played an important role in Atlantic trade and defence and is home to Canada’s largest naval base.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c17",
        "question": "What does it mean to retain the \"confidence of the House\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Cabinet ministers are responsible to the elected representatives",
            "The House of Commons has to have confidence in the Prime Minister",
            "The Queen has to have confidence in the Cabinet ministers",
            "The House of Commons has to have confidence in the senators"
        ],
        "explanation": "Cabinet ministers are responsible to the elected representatives, which means they must retain the “confidence of the House” and have to resign if they are defeated in a non-confidence vote.",
        "answer": "Cabinet ministers are responsible to the elected representatives"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c19",
        "question": "When was \"O Canada\" proclaimed as the national anthem?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "1947",
            "1889",
            "1980"
        ],
        "explanation": "O Canada was proclaimed as the national anthem in 1980. It was first sung in Québec City in 1880. French and English Canadians sing different words to the national anthem.",
        "answer": "1980"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1a",
        "question": "Who passed the Quebec Act of 1774?",
        "choices": [
            "The Canadian Parliament",
            "The British Parliament",
            "The Quebec Parliament",
            "The French majority"
        ],
        "explanation": "To better govern the French Roman Catholic majority, the British Parliament passed the Quebec Act of 1774. One of the constitutional foundations of Canada, the Quebec Act accommodated the principles of British institutions to the reality of the province.",
        "answer": "The British Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1b",
        "question": "After you pass the test and meet all the other requirements",
        "choices": [
            "You will receive some money from Citizenship and Immigration Canada",
            "You will have to pay additional fees to attend your Citizenship Ceremony",
            "You will receive a Notice to Appear to Take the Oath of Citizenship",
            "You will immediately receive your Citizenship Certificate in the Mail"
        ],
        "explanation": "If you pass the test and meet all the other requirements, you will receive a Notice to Appear to Take the Oath of Citizenship. This document tells you the date, time and place of your citizenship ceremony.",
        "answer": "You will receive a Notice to Appear to Take the Oath of Citizenship"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1e",
        "question": "Which of the following responsibilities does not come with being a Canadian citizen?",
        "choices": [
            "Helping others in the community",
            "Learning French and English",
            "Serving on a jury",
            "Obeying the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, rights come with responsibilities. These include:- Obeying the law- Taking responsibility for oneself and one’s family- Serving on a jury- Voting in elections- Helping others in the community- Protecting and enjoying our heritage and environment",
        "answer": "Learning French and English"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c20",
        "question": "When was Magna Carta signed?",
        "choices": [
            "1215",
            "1615",
            "1649",
            "1425"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) was signed in 1215 in England.",
        "answer": "1215"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1f",
        "question": "What is the speaking background of the  Metis population?",
        "choices": [
            "French",
            "Acadian",
            "Both French and English",
            "English"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Métis are a distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry, the majority of whom live in the Prairie provinces. They come from both French- and English-speaking backgrounds and speak their own dialect, Michif.",
        "answer": "Both French and English"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1c",
        "question": "Which of the following statements is false?",
        "choices": [
            "At your citizenship ceremony, you will be asked to join the Canadian Army",
            "At your citizenship ceremony, you will take the Oath of Citizenship",
            "At your citizenship ceremony, you will sign the oath form",
            "At your citizenship ceremony, you will receive your Citizenship Certificate"
        ],
        "explanation": "At the ceremony, you will:- Take the Oath of Citizenship;- Sign the oath form; and- Receive your Canadian Citizenship Certificate.If you do not pass the test, you will receive a notification indicating the next steps.",
        "answer": "At your citizenship ceremony, you will be asked to join the Canadian Army"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c1d",
        "question": "In what year were Upper and Lower Canada united?",
        "choices": [
            "1882",
            "1867",
            "1759",
            "1840"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1840, Upper and Lower Canada were united as the Province of Canada. Reformers such as Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine and Robert Baldwin, in parallel with Joseph Howe in Nova Scotia, worked with British governors toward responsible government.",
        "answer": "1840"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c21",
        "question": "Who claimed Canadian land for King Francis I of France between 1534 and 1542?",
        "choices": [
            "Jacques Cartier",
            "Samuel de Champlain",
            "John Cabot",
            "Pierre de Monts"
        ],
        "explanation": "Between 1534 and 1542, Jacques Cartier made three voyages across the Atlantic, claiming the land for King Francis I of France.",
        "answer": "Jacques Cartier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c22",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of a municipal elected official?",
        "choices": [
            "Emergency Services",
            "Citizenship",
            "Social and Community Health",
            "Transportation and Utilities"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipalities are normally responsible for urban or regional planning, streets and roads, sanitation (such as garbage removal), snow removal, firefighting, ambulance and other emergency services, recreation facilities, public transit and some local health and social services.",
        "answer": "Citizenship"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c23",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Nunavut?",
        "choices": [
            "Northwest Territories",
            "Ontario",
            "Manitoba",
            "Arctic Ocean"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ontario does not border Nunavut.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c24",
        "question": "What is Canada’s second largest, mainly French-speaking city in the world, after Paris?",
        "choices": [
            "Ottawa",
            "Montreal",
            "Halifax",
            "Quebec City"
        ],
        "explanation": "Montreal, Canada’s second largest city and the second largest mainly French-speaking city in the world after Paris, is famous for its cultural diversity.",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c26",
        "question": "Where is the largest east coast port located in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Halifax",
            "St. John's",
            "Fredericton",
            "Charlottetown"
        ],
        "explanation": "As Canada’s largest east coast port, deep-water and ice-free, the capital, Halifax, has played an important role in Atlantic trade and defence and is home to Canada’s largest naval base.",
        "answer": "Halifax"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c25",
        "question": "To which religious affiliation do the great majority of Canadians identify?",
        "choices": [
            "Muslim",
            "Jewish",
            "Christian",
            "Hinduism"
        ],
        "explanation": "The great majority of Canadians identify as Christians. The largest religious affiliation is Catholic, followed by various Protestant churches. The numbers of Muslims, Jews, Hindus, Sikhs and members of other religions, as well as people who state “no religion” are also growing.",
        "answer": "Christian"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c28",
        "question": "Who are Francophones?",
        "choices": [
            "People born in England",
            "People who speak French as a first language",
            "People that migrated from from France",
            "Native American People"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, there are 18 million Anglophones—people who speak English as a first language—and seven million Francophones—people who speak French as their first language.",
        "answer": "People who speak French as a first language"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c27",
        "question": "What is the name of the highest judiciary court in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Supreme Court",
            "The Executive Court",
            "Her Majesty Court",
            "The Federal Court"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Supreme Court of Canada is our country’s highest court. The Federal Court of Canada deals with matters concerning the federal government.",
        "answer": "The Supreme Court"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2a",
        "question": "Why is Terry Fox a Canadian national hero?",
        "choices": [
            "He became the first elected President of Canada",
            "He was the greatest hockey player of all time",
            "He united Canada in the 19th century",
            "He inspired people to contribute money for cancer research"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1980, Terry Fox, a British Columbian who lost his right leg to cancer at the age of 18, began a cross-country run, the “Marathon of Hope,” to raise money for cancer research.",
        "answer": "He inspired people to contribute money for cancer research"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2b",
        "question": "How many candidates can there be in an electoral district?",
        "choices": [
            "Three",
            "Many",
            "A maximum of five",
            "Two"
        ],
        "explanation": "The people who run for office are called candidates. There can be many candidates in an electoral district.",
        "answer": "Many"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c29",
        "question": "In Canada, there is no mandatory military service",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "There is no compulsory military service in Canada. However, serving in the regular Canadian Forces (navy, army and air force) is a noble way to contribute to Canada and an excellent career choice.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2c",
        "question": "Since when have red and white been the national colors of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1965",
            "1921",
            "1949",
            "1892"
        ],
        "explanation": "Red and white had been colours of France and England since the Middle Ages and the national colours of Canada since 1921.",
        "answer": "1921"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2f",
        "question": "When did France and Great Britain battle for control of North America?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1700s",
            "In the 1800s",
            "In the 1600s",
            "Never"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the 1700s France and Great Britain battled for control of North America.",
        "answer": "In the 1700s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2e",
        "question": "When was the Constitution of Canada amended to include the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?",
        "choices": [
            "1700",
            "1800",
            "1600",
            "1982"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitution of Canada was amended in 1982 to entrench the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms.",
        "answer": "1982"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c2d",
        "question": "On what is Canada’s legal system based?",
        "choices": [
            "Democratic principles and due process",
            "The rule of law",
            "The rule of law and freedom under the law",
            "The rule of law, freedom under the law, democratic principles and due process"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s legal system is based on a heritage that includes the rule of law, freedom under the law, democratic principles and due process. Due process is the principle that the government must respect all the legal rights a person is entitled to under the law.",
        "answer": "The rule of law, freedom under the law, democratic principles and due process"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c30",
        "question": "Where are the Parliament buildings located?",
        "choices": [
            "Toronto",
            "Quebec City",
            "Ottawa",
            "Vancouver"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Parliament Buildings are located in Ottawa, Ontario.",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8bfa",
        "question": "Which of the following are Prairie Provinces?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba, Ontario and Saskatchewan",
            "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta",
            "Saskatchewan, Alberta and Nova Scotia",
            "Ontario, Manitoba and Alberta"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta are all Prairie Provinces in Canada.",
        "answer": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c06",
        "question": "When did Canadian medical officer Lt. Col. John McCrae composed the poem \"In Flanders Fields\" that is often recited on Remembrance Day?",
        "choices": [
            "1918",
            "1915",
            "1945",
            "1812"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian medical officer Lieutenant Colonel John McCrae composed the poem “In Flanders Fields” in 1915; it is often recited on Remembrance Day.",
        "answer": "1915"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c37",
        "question": "How many Canadians served in the First World War?",
        "choices": [
            "About 10,000",
            "More than 600,000",
            "About 60,000",
            "About 170,000"
        ],
        "explanation": "More than 600,000 Canadians served in the war, most of them volunteers, out of a total population of eight million.",
        "answer": "More than 600,000"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c36",
        "question": "Which of the following is a Canadian musician who won renown in Canada and abroad?",
        "choices": [
            "Emile Nelligan",
            "Joy Kogawa",
            "Jean-Paul Riopelle",
            "Sir Ernest MacMillan"
        ],
        "explanation": "Musicians such as Sir Ernest MacMillan and Healey Willan won renown in Canada and abroad.",
        "answer": "Sir Ernest MacMillan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c33",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border the Yukon?",
        "choices": [
            "Northwest Territories",
            "British Columbia",
            "Arctic Ocean",
            "Alberta"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alberta does not border the Yukon.",
        "answer": "Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c34",
        "question": "To what does the term \"Indians\" refer?",
        "choices": [
            "Early settlers, Metis and Inuit",
            "All aboriginal peoples who are not Inuit or Metis",
            "Metis and Inuit",
            "Acadians, Metis and First Nations"
        ],
        "explanation": "Indian refers to all Aboriginal people who are not Inuit or Métis. In the 1970s, the term First Nations began to be used.",
        "answer": "All aboriginal peoples who are not Inuit or Metis"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c35",
        "question": "What is the current name of the fortress that Samuel de Champlain built in 1608?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec City",
            "Montreal",
            "Port Royal",
            "Ottawa"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1604, the first European settlement north of Florida was established by French explorers Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain, first on St. Croix Island (in present-day Maine), then at Port-Royal, in Acadia (present-day Nova Scotia). In 1608 Champlain built a fortress at what is now Québec City.",
        "answer": "Quebec City"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3c",
        "question": "Which three rights are included in the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?",
        "choices": [
            "Mobility rights, Aboriginal Peoples' rights, and official language rights",
            "Aboriginal Peoples' rights, voting rights and official language rights",
            "Freedom of expression rights, property rights and fair trial rights",
            "Employment rights, mobility rights, and freedom rights"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Charter attempts to summarize fundamental freedoms while also setting out additional rights. The most important of these include Mobility Rights, Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights, Official Language Rights and Minority Language Educational Rights and Multiculturalism.",
        "answer": "Mobility rights, Aboriginal Peoples' rights, and official language rights"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c38",
        "question": "When do Canadians celebrate Labour Day?",
        "choices": [
            "Second Monday of September",
            "Third Monday of October",
            "Third Monday of September",
            "First Monday of September"
        ],
        "explanation": "Labour Day is celebrated on the first Monday of September.",
        "answer": "First Monday of September"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c39",
        "question": "What is the leader of the party with the most seats in the House of Commons called?",
        "choices": [
            "Senator",
            "Queen or King",
            "Governor General",
            "Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ordinarily, after an election, the leader of the political party with the most seats in the House of Commons is invited by the Governor General to form the government.",
        "answer": "Governor General"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3a",
        "question": "What does \"parliamentary democracy\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "The Queen elects members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures",
            "The people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures",
            "The parliament elects members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures",
            "The senators elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada’s parliamentary democracy, the people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures.",
        "answer": "The people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3b",
        "question": "What is the former name of the Constitution Act?",
        "choices": [
            "The French North American Act",
            "The Federal Act",
            "The British Act",
            "The British North American Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "The responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments were defined in 1867 in the British North America Act, now known as the Constitution Act, 1867.",
        "answer": "The British North American Act"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3d",
        "question": "Where are more than three quarters of all Canadian manufactured goods produced?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec and Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "Ontario and Manitoba"
        ],
        "explanation": "Southern Ontario and Quebec have cold winters and warm humid summers. Together, Ontario and Quebec produce more than three-quarters of all Canadian manufactured goods.",
        "answer": "Quebec and Ontario"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3e",
        "question": "When was the first representative assembly in Canada elected?",
        "choices": [
            "1889",
            "1609",
            "1791",
            "1758"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first representative assembly was elected in Halifax, Nova Scotia, in 1758. Prince Edward Island followed in 1773, New Brunswick in 1785.",
        "answer": "1758"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c3f",
        "question": "Which current provinces came out from the Constitutional Act?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario and Quebec",
            "Ontario and Prince Edward Island",
            "Ontario and New Brunswick",
            "Prince Edward Island and Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 divided the Province of Quebec into Upper Canada (later Ontario), which was mainly Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking, and Lower Canada (later Quebec), heavily Catholic and French-speaking.",
        "answer": "Ontario and Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c40",
        "question": "When was the modern Canadian Flag first raised?",
        "choices": [
            "1965",
            "1865",
            "1855",
            "1999"
        ],
        "explanation": "A new Canadian flag was raised for the first time in 1965. The red-white-red pattern comes from the flag of the Royal Military College, Kingston, founded in 1876.",
        "answer": "1965"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c45",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of a municipality?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural Resources",
            "Education",
            "Citizenship",
            "Sanitation"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipalities are normally responsible for urban or regional planning, streets and roads, sanitation (such as garbage removal), snow removal, firefighting, ambulance and other emergency services, recreation facilities, public transit and some local health and social services.",
        "answer": "Sanitation"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c47",
        "question": "Obeying the law is:",
        "choices": [
            "A responsibility",
            "A right"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of Canada’s founding principles is the rule of law. Individuals and governments are regulated by laws and not by arbitrary actions. No person or group is above the law.",
        "answer": "A responsibility"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c44",
        "question": "Which of the following criteria makes you eligible to vote?",
        "choices": [
            "You own a property in Canada",
            "You have a valid Canadian driving license",
            "You are a landed immigrant",
            "You are on the voters' list"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of the privileges of Canadian citizenship is the right to vote. You are eligible to vote in a federal election or cast a ballot in a federal referendum if you are:- a Canadian citizen; and- at least 18 years old on voting day; and- on the voters’ list.",
        "answer": "You are on the voters' list"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c42",
        "question": "Which city is the headquarters of the Canadian mining industry?",
        "choices": [
            "Winnipeg",
            "Edmonton",
            "Saskatoon",
            "Vancouver"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatoon, the largest city, is the headquarters of the mining industry and an important educational, research and technology centre.",
        "answer": "Saskatoon"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c46",
        "question": "For what are the provincial governments responsible?",
        "choices": [
            "Education, health, and natural resources",
            "Natural resources, property, civil rights, and highways",
            "Education, health, natural resources, property, civil rights, and highways",
            "Natural resources and highways"
        ],
        "explanation": "The provinces are responsible for municipal government, education, health, natural resources, property and civil rights, and highways.",
        "answer": "Education, health, natural resources, property, civil rights, and highways"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c43",
        "question": "What is the significance of the Quebec Act of 1774?",
        "choices": [
            "It provided peace, order and good government",
            "It enacted the birth of Canada",
            "It united the Province of Quebec with the rest of Canada",
            "It allowed religious freedom for Catholics and permitted them to hold public office"
        ],
        "explanation": "To better govern the French Roman Catholic majority, the British Parliament passed the Quebec Act of 1774. One of the constitutional foundations of Canada, the Quebec Actaccommodated the principles of British institutions to the reality of the province. It allowed religious freedom for Catholics and permitted them to hold public office, a practice not then allowed in Britain.",
        "answer": "It allowed religious freedom for Catholics and permitted them to hold public office"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c41",
        "question": "Whose films have been popular in Quebec and across the country, and have won international awards?",
        "choices": [
            "The films of Louis-Philippe Hebert",
            "The films of Emile Nelligan",
            "The films of Denys Arcand",
            "The films of Louis Hemon"
        ],
        "explanation": "The films of Denys Arcand have been popular in Quebec and across the country, and have won international awards. Other noteworthy Canadian filmmakers include Norman Jewison and Atom Egoyan. Canadian television has had a popular following.",
        "answer": "The films of Denys Arcand"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c48",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of a Member of Parliament?",
        "choices": [
            "Education",
            "Citizenship",
            "Foreign Policy",
            "Policing"
        ],
        "explanation": "In our federal state, the federal government takes responsibility for matters of national and international concern. These include defence, foreign policy, interprovincial trade and communications, currency, navigation, criminal law and citizenship.",
        "answer": "Education"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4b",
        "question": "Where are the Great Lakes located?",
        "choices": [
            "Between Ontario and Quebec",
            "Between Quebec and the United States",
            "Between Manitoba and the United States",
            "Between Ontario and the United States"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are five Great Lakes located between Ontario and the United States: Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake Michigan (in the U.S.A.) and Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world.",
        "answer": "Between Ontario and the United States"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4d",
        "question": "What is usually the result of a party in power being defeated?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister asks the Governor General, on behalf of the Sovereign, to call an election",
            "The opposition party automatically gets to run the government",
            "The Governor General asks the Prime Minister, on behalf of the Sovereign, to call an election",
            "The Prime Minister must resign from his party"
        ],
        "explanation": "If a majority of the members of the House of Commons vote against a major government decision, the party in power is defeated, which usually results in the Prime Minister asking the Governor General, on behalf of the Sovereign, to call an election.",
        "answer": "The Prime Minister asks the Governor General, on behalf of the Sovereign, to call an election"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4a",
        "question": "Who was Upper Canada’s first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of York (now Toronto)?",
        "choices": [
            "Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe",
            "Joseph Brant",
            "Joseph Howe",
            "Sir John A. Macdonald"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lieutenant-Colonel John Graves Simcoe was Upper Canada’s first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of York (now Toronto). Simcoe also made Upper Canada the first province in the British Empire to abolish slavery.",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c49",
        "question": "What are the three key facts about Canada’s system of government?",
        "choices": [
            "Canada is a federal state, a parliamentary monarchy and a constitutional democracy",
            "Canada is a British Kingdom, a parliamentary democracy and a constitutional monarchy",
            "Canada is a federal democracy, a parliamentary state and a constitutional monarchy",
            "Canada is a federal state, a parliamentary democracy and a constitutional monarchy"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy, a parliamentary democracy and a federal state. Canadians are bound together by a shared commitment to the rule of law and to the institutions of parliamentary government.",
        "answer": "Canada is a federal state, a parliamentary democracy and a constitutional monarchy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4c",
        "question": "Which province is Canada’s main producer of pulp and paper?",
        "choices": [
            "New Brunswick",
            "Quebec",
            "Ontario",
            "British Columbia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec is Canada’s main producer of pulp and paper.",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c51",
        "question": "The citizenship test will assess",
        "choices": [
            "If you meet all the criteria to become a Canadian citizen",
            "Your knowledge of Canada and the rights and responsibilities of citizenship",
            "If you are honest",
            "Your knowledge of English or French"
        ],
        "explanation": "You will be tested on two basic requirements for citizenship: 1) knowledge of Canada and of the rights and responsibilities of citizenship, and 2) adequate knowledge of English or French.",
        "answer": "Your knowledge of Canada and the rights and responsibilities of citizenship"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c52",
        "question": "What is the capital of the Northwest Territories?",
        "choices": [
            "Iqaluit",
            "Edmonton",
            "Whitehorse",
            "Yellowknife"
        ],
        "explanation": "Yellowknife is the capital of the Northwest Territories.",
        "answer": "Yellowknife"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4e",
        "question": "What is the National Register of Electors?",
        "choices": [
            "A database of landed immigrants 18 years of age or older who have to register to vote in federal elections and referendums",
            "A database of Canadian citizens 18 years of age or older who are qualified to run as a candidate in federal elections",
            "A database of Canadian citizens 18 years of age or older who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums",
            "A database of taxpayers who elected to serve on a jury"
        ],
        "explanation": "The voters’ lists used during federal elections and referendums are produced from the National Register of Electors by a neutral agency of Parliament called Elections Canada.",
        "answer": "A database of Canadian citizens 18 years of age or older who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c50",
        "question": "From where were the ancestors of Aboriginal peoples believed to have migrated?",
        "choices": [
            "Europe",
            "Asia",
            "Africa",
            "Australia"
        ],
        "explanation": "The ancestors of Aboriginal peoples are believed to have migrated from Asia many thousands of years ago. They were well established here long before explorers from Europe first came to North America.",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c56",
        "question": "Who will receive a voter information card?",
        "choices": [
            "Electors who own a house",
            "Electors whose information is in the National Register of Electors",
            "Everybody",
            "Electors who are 18 years or older"
        ],
        "explanation": "Once an election has been called, Elections Canada mails a voter information card to each elector whose name is in the National Register of Electors.",
        "answer": "Electors whose information is in the National Register of Electors"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c54",
        "question": "What are Canada’s two official languages?",
        "choices": [
            "English and French",
            "French and British",
            "English and First Nations",
            "First Nations and French"
        ],
        "explanation": "English and French are the two official languages and are important symbols of identity. English speakers (Anglophones) and French speakers (Francophones) have lived together in partnership and creative tension for more than 300 years.",
        "answer": "English and French"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c55",
        "question": "Who do the citizens in each electoral district elect?",
        "choices": [
            "Masters of Parliament",
            "Ministers of Parliaments",
            "Member of Parliament",
            "Member of Politics"
        ],
        "explanation": "The citizens in each electoral district elect one MP who sits in the House of Commons to represent them, as well as all Canadians.",
        "answer": "Member of Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c4f",
        "question": "What is the significance of serving on a jury?",
        "choices": [
            "It makes the justice system work by eliminating the need of judges",
            "You get paid very generously",
            "Your police record is cleared afterwards",
            "It makes the justice system work as it depends on impartial juries made up of citizens"
        ],
        "explanation": "When called to do so, you are legally required to serve. Serving on a jury is a privilege that makes the justice system work as it depends on impartial juries made up of citizens.",
        "answer": "It makes the justice system work as it depends on impartial juries made up of citizens"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5f",
        "question": "What are \"mobility rights\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Canadians may enter and leave the country freely, and apply for passports",
            "Canadians have freedom of speech",
            "Canadians are free to enter and leave the nation at will, live and work anywhere they choose, and apply for passports.",
            "Canadians are free to enter and leave the nation at will and live and work anywhere they choose"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians can live and work anywhere they choose in Canada, enter and leave the country freely, and apply for a passport.",
        "answer": "Canadians are free to enter and leave the nation at will, live and work anywhere they choose, and apply for passports"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5b",
        "question": "Which province hosts the vast cattle ranches that make Canada one of the world’s major beef producers?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Manitoba",
            "Alberta",
            "British Columbia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alberta is also renowned for agriculture, especially for the vast cattle ranches that make Canada one of the world’s major beef producers.",
        "answer": "Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5a",
        "question": "When did Canada enjoy one of the strongest economies among industrialized nations?",
        "choices": [
            "Between 1980 and 1990",
            "Between 1945 and 1970",
            "Between 1970 and 1980",
            "Between 1925 and 1960"
        ],
        "explanation": "Between 1945 and 1970, Canada drew closer to the United States and other trading partners, the country enjoyed one of the strongest economies among industrialized nations.",
        "answer": "Between 1945 and 1970"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c60",
        "question": "Who represents the majority population in Nunavut?",
        "choices": [
            "First Nations",
            "Metis",
            "Inuit",
            "Acadian"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Nunavut, the population is about 85% Inuit, and Inuktitut is an official language and the first language in schools.",
        "answer": "Inuit"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5d",
        "question": "In which year did the American attempt to conquer Canada fail?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "1840",
            "1849",
            "1814"
        ],
        "explanation": "By 1814, the American attempt to conquer Canada had failed. The British paid for a costly Canadian defence system, including the Citadels at Halifax and Québec City, the naval drydock at Halifax and Fort Henry at Kingston—today popular historic sites.",
        "answer": "1814"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5c",
        "question": "In Nunavut, beside English, which other language is also an official language and first language in schools?",
        "choices": [
            "Acadian",
            "Metis",
            "French",
            "Inuktitut"
        ],
        "explanation": "The population is about 85% Inuit, and Inuktitut is an official language and the first language in schools.",
        "answer": "Inuktitut"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c58",
        "question": "Who battled for control of North America in the 1700s?",
        "choices": [
            "France and Ireland",
            "France and Great Britain",
            "Great Britain and the United States",
            "France and the United States"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the 1700s France and Great Britain battled for control of North America. In 1759, the British defeated the French in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham at Québec City — marking the end of France’s empire in America.",
        "answer": "France and Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c53",
        "question": "Which of the following statements about residential schools is false?",
        "choices": [
            "Aboriginal language and cultural practices were mostly prohibited",
            "The federal government placed many Aboriginal children in residential schools to educate and assimilate them into mainstream Canadian culture",
            "The schools were poorly funded and inflicted hardship on the students",
            "Aboriginal people demanded to be placed in residential schools"
        ],
        "explanation": "From the 1800s until the 1980s, the federal government placed many Aboriginal children in residential schools to educate and assimilate them into mainstream Canadian culture. The schools were poorly funded and inflicted hardship on the students; some were physically abused.  Aboriginal languages and cultural practices were mostly prohibited. In 2008, Ottawa formally apologized to the former students.",
        "answer": "Aboriginal people demanded to be placed in residential schools"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c59",
        "question": "What does the lily flower (\"fleur-de-lys\") symbolize?",
        "choices": [
            "Canadian Peace Act with the First Nations",
            "French Royalty",
            "Canadian Armed Forces",
            "English Royalty"
        ],
        "explanation": "It is said that the lily flower (“fleur-de-lys”) was adopted by the French king in the year 496. It became the symbol of French royalty for more than 1,000 years, including the colony of New France.",
        "answer": "French Royalty"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c5e",
        "question": "After English, what is the second most-spoken non-official language in Canadian homes?",
        "choices": [
            "French",
            "Chinese",
            "Punjabi",
            "Spanish"
        ],
        "explanation": "Non-official languages are widely spoken in Canadian homes. Chinese languages are the second most-spoken at home, after English, in two of Canada’s biggest cities. In Vancouver, 13% of the population speak Chinese languages at home; in Toronto, the number is 7%.",
        "answer": "Chinese"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c61",
        "question": "What is a great way to make acquaintances, create contacts, and learn useful skills?",
        "choices": [
            "Volunteer",
            "Pluralism",
            "Serve in the Air Force",
            "Serve on a jury"
        ],
        "explanation": "Millions of volunteers freely donate their time to help others without pay. Helping people in need, assisting at your child’s school, volunteering at a food bank or other charity, or encouraging newcomers to integrate are all excellent ways to gain useful skills and develop friends and contacts.",
        "answer": "Volunteer"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c57",
        "question": "In Canada, how are the laws administered?",
        "choices": [
            "Randomly, it depends on the judge's personal opinion",
            "Only by the police",
            "In a partial manner, the facts may be taken into consideration",
            "In an impartial manner, only the facts are taken into consideration"
        ],
        "explanation": "Justice in Canada is like the blind folded Lady Justice. It symbolizes the impartial manner in which our laws are administered: blind to all considerations but the facts.",
        "answer": "In an impartial manner, only the facts are taken into consideration"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c63",
        "question": "Canada’s economy is among the top:",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "5",
            "10",
            "20"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, Canada has one of the ten largest economies in the world and is part of the G8 group of leading industrialized countries with the United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Japan and Russia.",
        "answer": "10"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c62",
        "question": "Which of the following is not an objective of the Official Languages Act?",
        "choices": [
            "Restrict the ability to speak French outside of Quebec",
            "Maintain and develop official language minority communities in Canada",
            "Promote equality of French and English in Canadian society",
            "Establish equality between French and English in Parliament, the Government of Canada and institutions subject to the Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "Parliament passed the Official Languages Act in 1969. It has three main objectives:- Establish equality between French and English in Parliament, the Government of Canada and institutions subject to the Act;- Maintain and develop official language minority communities in Canada; and- Promote equality of French and English in Canadian society.",
        "answer": "The operations and policy of the government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c64",
        "question": "What is the name of Canada’ s original constitutional document?",
        "choices": [
            "The British North America Act",
            "The Legislative Act",
            "The Constitutional Act",
            "The Confederation Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s original constitutional document was created in 1867, the British North America Act.",
        "answer": "The British North America Act"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c67",
        "question": "What are the three main groups of Aboriginal peoples?",
        "choices": [
            "First Nations, Metis and Inuit",
            "Acadians, Metis and First Nations",
            "Early settlers, Metis and Inuit",
            "French, English and First Nations"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 65% of the Aboriginal people are First Nations, while 30% are Métis and 4% Inuit.",
        "answer": "First Nations, Metis and Inuit"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c66",
        "question": "Canada is not the only constitutional monarchy in North America",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy, a parliamentary democracy and a federal state. Canadians are bound together by a shared commitment to the rule of law and to the institutions of parliamentary government.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6a",
        "question": "What year was Magna Carta signed?",
        "choices": [
            "1215",
            "1999",
            "2000",
            "2022"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) was signed in England in the year 1215.",
        "answer": "1215"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c68",
        "question": "How did the native people live when the first European arrived in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Off the land, by hunting and gathering",
            "By trading fur with other native in North America",
            "Off the land, by raising crops",
            "Off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops"
        ],
        "explanation": "When Europeans explored Canada they found all regions occupied by native peoples they called Indians, because the first explorers thought they had reached the East Indies. The native people lived off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops. The Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region, like the Iroquois, were farmers and hunters. The Cree and Dene of the Northwest were hunter-gatherers. The Sioux were nomadic, following the bison (buffalo) herd. The Inuit lived off Arctic wildlife. West Coast natives preserved fish by drying and smoking.",
        "answer": "Off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c69",
        "question": "What are three responsibilities of Canadian citizenship?",
        "choices": [
            "Being loyal to Canada, recycling all waste, and serving in the Canadian Forces.",
            "Learning both official languages, voting in elections, and belonging to a union",
            "Obeying the law, taking responsibility for oneself and one's family, and serving on a jury",
            "Buying Canadian products, owning your own house, and using less water"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, rights come with responsibilities. These include:- Obeying the law- Taking responsibility for oneself and one’s family- Serving on a jury- Voting in elections- Helping others in the community- Protecting and enjoying our heritage and environment",
        "answer": "Obeying the law, taking responsibility for oneself and one's family, and serving on a jury"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c65",
        "question": "What happens if you cannot or do not wish to vote on election day?",
        "choices": [
            "You can vote by special ballot only",
            "You can vote at the advance polls or by special ballot",
            "You can vote at the advance polls only",
            "You cannot vote at all"
        ],
        "explanation": "If you cannot or do not wish to vote on election day, you can vote at the advance polls or by special ballot. The dates and location are on your voter information card.",
        "answer": "You can vote at the advance polls or by special ballot"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6c",
        "question": "For centuries, on what was Canada’s economy based?",
        "choices": [
            "Exporting natural resources",
            "Farming and exporting natural resources",
            "Trading with the First Nations",
            "Farming"
        ],
        "explanation": "For centuries Canada’s economy was based mainly on farming and on exporting natural resources such as fur, fish and timber, transported by roads, lakes, rivers and canals.",
        "answer": "Farming and exporting natural resources"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6b",
        "question": "Which of the following is the responsibility of federal government?",
        "choices": [
            "Education",
            "Health",
            "Natural Resources",
            "Criminal law and citizenship"
        ],
        "explanation": "In our federal state, the federal government takes responsibility for matters of national and international concern. These include defence, foreign policy, interprovincial trade and communications, currency, navigation, criminal law and citizenship.",
        "answer": "Criminal law and citizenship"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6d",
        "question": "What is the Royal Canadian Mounted Police?",
        "choices": [
            "A municipal police force",
            "A national police force",
            "army police",
            "A provincial police force"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, the Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP or “the Mounties”) are the national police force and one of Canada’s best-known symbols.",
        "answer": "A national police force"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c73",
        "question": "What is the name of Metis dialect?",
        "choices": [
            "Frenglish",
            "Michif",
            "Inuit",
            "Acadian"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Métis are a distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry, the majority of whom live in the Prairie provinces. They come from both French- and English-speaking backgrounds and speak their own dialect, Michif.",
        "answer": "Michif"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6e",
        "question": "What does the Federal Court deal with?",
        "choices": [
            "Matters concerning the police",
            "Matters concerning the federal government",
            "Matters concerning the federal and provincial government",
            "Matters concerning National Defence"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Supreme Court of Canada is our country’s highest court. The Federal Court of Canada deals with matters concerning the federal government.",
        "answer": "Matters concerning the federal government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c72",
        "question": "Who is Mount Logan, the highest mountain in Canada, named in honour of?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir William Logan, a world-famous pioneer",
            "Sir William Logan, a world-famous navy officer",
            "Sir William Logan, a world-famous mountain climber",
            "Sir William Logan, a world-famous geologist"
        ],
        "explanation": "Mount Logan, located in the Yukon, is the highest mountain in Canada. It is named in honour of Sir William Logan, a world-famous geologist, born in Montreal in 1798 to Scottish immigrant parents. Logan founded and directed the Geological Survey of Canada from 1842 to 1869 and is considered one of Canada’s greatest scientists.",
        "answer": "Sir William Logan, a world-famous geologist"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c70",
        "question": "For how many years has the Crown been a symbol of the state in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "300",
            "100",
            "200",
            "400"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Crown has been a symbol of the state in Canada for 400 years. Canada has been a constitutional monarchy in its own right since Confederation in 1867 during Queen Victoria’s reign.",
        "answer": "400"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c71",
        "question": "Who was the first Canadian to be awarded the Victoria Cross?",
        "choices": [
            "Able Seaman William Hall of Horton",
            "Flying ace Captain Billy Bishop",
            "Corporal Filip Konowal",
            "Lieutenant Alexander Roberts Dunn"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lieutenant Alexander Roberts Dunn, born in present-day Toronto, served in the British Army in the Charge of the Light Brigade at Balaclava (1854) in the Crimean War, and was the first Canadian to be awarded the Victoria Cross.",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Alexander Roberts Dunn"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c6f",
        "question": "During an election period, what happens if you do not receive a voter information card?",
        "choices": [
            "You cannot vote",
            "You can only vote online",
            "You have to call your local elections office, or Elections Canada in Ottawa, to ensure that you are on the voters' list",
            "You have to call the House of Commons in Ottawa to ensure that you are on the voters' list"
        ],
        "explanation": "If you do not receive a voter information card, call your local elections office to ensure that you are on the voters’ list. If you do not have the number, call Elections Canada, in Ottawa, at 1-800-463-6868.",
        "answer": "You have to call your local elections office, or Elections Canada in Ottawa, to ensure that you are on the voters' list"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c31",
        "question": "Which sport has the most registered players of any game in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Baseball",
            "Soccer",
            "Lacrosse",
            "Ice hockey"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lacrosse, an ancient sport first played by Aboriginals, is the official summer sport. Soccer has the most registered players of any game in Canada.",
        "answer": "Soccer"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c32",
        "question": "Whose portrait is on the Canadian $10 bill?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine",
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir John Alexander Macdonald",
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir John Alexander Macdonald was a lawyer in Kingston, Ontario, a gifted politician and a colourful personality. Parliament has recognized January 11 as Sir John A. Macdonald Day. His portrait is on the $10 bill.",
        "answer": "Sir John Alexander Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7c",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Quebec?",
        "choices": [
            "Atlantic Ocean",
            "Ontario",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "New Brunswick"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nova Scotia does not border Quebec.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c77",
        "question": "Which industries have played an important part in Canada’s story and development?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural resources industries",
            "Service industries",
            "Manufacturing industries",
            "Trading industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Natural resources industries include forestry, fishing, agriculture, mining and energy. These industries have played an important part in the country’s history and development.",
        "answer": "Natural resources industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c79",
        "question": "When was Ice Hockey invented?",
        "choices": [
            "1500s",
            "1700s",
            "1800s",
            "1900s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Hockey is Canada’s most popular spectator sport and is considered to be the national winter sport. Ice hockey was developed in Canada in the 1800s.",
        "answer": "1800s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c78",
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a responsibility of a political representative (members of the House of Commons and members of the provincial and territorial legislatures)?",
        "choices": [
            "Passing laws",
            "Keeping the government accountable",
            "Approving and monitoring expenditures",
            "Select the Cabinet Ministers"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada’s parliamentary democracy, the people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures. These representatives are responsible for passing laws, approving and monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable.",
        "answer": "Select the Cabinet Ministers"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7b",
        "question": "How many of the Great Lakes are located between Ontario and the United States?",
        "choices": [
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Four",
            "Five"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are five Great Lakes located between Ontario and the United States: Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake Michigan (in the U.S.A.) and Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world.",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c76",
        "question": "What are the three branches of Canadian government?",
        "choices": [
            "Executive, Federal and Judicial",
            "Executive, Legislative and Monarchy",
            "Senate, Legislative and Judicial",
            "Executive, Legislative and Judicial"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s system of government has three branches: the legislative, the executive and the judicial. Each one has separate powers and responsibilities that are defined in the Constitution: the legislative branch passes laws, the executive implements them, and the judicial interprets them.",
        "answer": "Executive, Legislative and Judicial"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7a",
        "question": "No treaty or other rights or freedoms of Aboriginal peoples will be negatively affected by the rights granted by the Canadian Charter.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights — The rights guaranteed in the Charter will not adversely affect any treaty or other rights or freedoms of Aboriginal peoples.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7d",
        "question": "Which countries fought in the War of 1812?",
        "choices": [
            "United States of America, France and United Kingdom",
            "United Kingdom and United States of America",
            "France and Canada",
            "France and United Kingdom"
        ],
        "explanation": "The United Kingdom and United States of America fought in the War of 1812. After the defeat of Napoleon Bonaparte’s fleet in the Battle of Trafalgar (1805), the Royal Navy ruled the waves. The British Empire, which included Canada, fought to resist Bonaparte’s bid to dominate Europe.This led to American resentment at British interference with their shipping. Believing it would be easy to conquer Canada, the United States launched an invasion in June 1812.",
        "answer": "United Kingdom and United States of America"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7f",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what does MP stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Member of Police",
            "Municipal Politician",
            "Member of Parliament",
            "Main Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "An electoral district is a geographical area represented by a member of Parliament (MP).",
        "answer": "Member of Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c7e",
        "question": "In Canada, voting is secret",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Your vote is secret. You will be invited to go behind the screen to mark your ballot. Once marked, fold it and present it to the poll officials.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c80",
        "question": "To which industries do transportation, education, health care, construction, banking, communications, retail services, tourism and government belong to?",
        "choices": [
            "Trading Industries",
            "Manufacturing industries",
            "Service industries",
            "Natural resources industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Service industries provide thousands of different jobs in areas like transportation, education, health care, construction, banking, communications, retail services, tourism and government.",
        "answer": "Service industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c84",
        "question": "What is a majority government?",
        "choices": [
            "The party in power that holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons",
            "The party in power that holds at least half of the seats in the Senate and the House of Commons",
            "The party in power that holds at least half of the seats in the Senate",
            "The party in power that holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "If the party in power holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons, this is called a majority government.",
        "answer": "The party in power that holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c83",
        "question": "When do Canadians celebrate Sir Wilfrid Laurier Day?",
        "choices": [
            "November 11th",
            "October 20th",
            "November 20th",
            "November 21st"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier Day is celebrated on November 20th.",
        "answer": "November 20th"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c81",
        "question": "In Canada, how are political representatives chosen (members of the House of Commons and members of the provincial and territorial legislatures)?",
        "choices": [
            "They are elected by the Cabinet Ministers",
            "They are elected by the Prime Minister",
            "They are elected by the Senators",
            "They are elected by the people"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons is the representative chamber, made up of members of Parliament elected by the people, traditionally every four years.",
        "answer": "They are elected by the people"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c82",
        "question": "When were Aboriginal people granted the right to vote.",
        "choices": [
            "1960",
            "1948",
            "1949",
            "1961"
        ],
        "explanation": "Most Canadians of Asian descent had in the past been denied the vote in federal and provincial elections. In 1948 the last of these, the Japanese Canadians, gained the right to vote. Aboriginal people were granted the vote in 1960. Today every citizen over the age of 18 may vote.",
        "answer": "1960"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c85",
        "question": "Which of the following provinces/territories does not border the U.S.A.?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "Alberta",
            "British Columbia",
            "Nunavut"
        ],
        "explanation": "The territory of Nunavut borders the Arctic Ocean.",
        "answer": "Nunavut"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c86",
        "question": "Who created insulin?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Sandford Fleming and Charles Best",
            "Dr. John A. Hopps",
            "Sir Frederick Banting of Toronto and Charles Best",
            "Dr. Wilder Penfield"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Frederick Banting of Toronto and Charles Best discovered insulin, a hormone to treat diabetes that has saved 16 million lives worldwide.",
        "answer": "Sir Frederick Banting of Toronto and Charles Best"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c88",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a responsibility of a municipality?",
        "choices": [
            "Civil Rights",
            "Emergency services",
            "Public transit",
            "Regional planning"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipalities are normally responsible for urban or regional planning, streets and roads, sanitation (such as garbage removal), snow removal, firefighting, ambulance and other emergency services, recreation facilities, public transit and some local health and social services.",
        "answer": "Civil Rights"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c87",
        "question": "When was Basketball invented?",
        "choices": [
            "1891",
            "1500",
            "2021",
            "1600"
        ],
        "explanation": "Basketball was invented by Canadian James Naismith in 1891. Many major league sports boast Canadian talent and in the national sport of ice hockey, Canadian teams have dominated the world.",
        "answer": "1891"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8b",
        "question": "The right to apply for a Canadian Passport is included in:",
        "choices": [
            "Mobility Rights",
            "Official Language Act",
            "The Confederation Act",
            "Multiculturalism"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians can live and work anywhere in the country, enter and leave freely, and apply for a passport.",
        "answer": "Mobility Rights"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8a",
        "question": "Which British North American colony was the first to attain full responsible government?",
        "choices": [
            "New Brunswick",
            "Upper Canada",
            "Ontario",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first British North American colony to attain full responsible government was Nova Scotia in 1847–48. In 1848–49 the governor of United Canada, Lord Elgin, with encouragement from London, introduced responsible government.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8c",
        "question": "When were Aboriginal Territorial Rights first guaranteed?",
        "choices": [
            "1988",
            "2000",
            "1763",
            "1900s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Aboriginal and treaty rights are in the Canadian Constitution. Territorial rights were first guaranteed through the Royal Proclamation of 1763 by King George III, and established the basis for negotiating treaties with the newcomers— treaties that were not always fully respected.",
        "answer": "1763"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8d",
        "question": "When were the Canada and Quebec Pension Plans devised?",
        "choices": [
            "1970",
            "1940",
            "1927",
            "1965"
        ],
        "explanation": "Old Age Security was devised as early as 1927, and the Canada and Quebec Pension Plans in 1965.",
        "answer": "1965"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c89",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nova Scotia?",
        "choices": [
            "Halifax",
            "St. John's",
            "Charlottetown",
            "Fredericton"
        ],
        "explanation": "Halifax is the capital of Nova Scotia.",
        "answer": "Halifax"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8e",
        "question": "What do Canadians remember on Remembrance Day?",
        "choices": [
            "The sacrifices of veterans and brave fallen in all wars",
            "Canada's victory in the First World War",
            "Canada's first settlers",
            "Canada's victory in the Second World War"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians remember the sacrifices of our veterans and brave fallen in all wars up to the present day in which Canadians took part, each year on November 11: Remembrance Day.",
        "answer": "The sacrifices of veterans and brave fallen in all wars"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c8f",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what are the people who run for office called?",
        "choices": [
            "Electors",
            "Politicians",
            "Candidates",
            "Member"
        ],
        "explanation": "The people who run for office are called candidates. There can be many candidates in an electoral district.",
        "answer": "Candidates"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c90",
        "question": "In Canada, where can you find Celtic and Gaelic traditions?",
        "choices": [
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nova Scotia’s Celtic and Gaelic traditions sustain a vibrant culture. Nova Scotia is home to over 700 annual festivals, including the spectacular military tattoo in Halifax.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c91",
        "question": "Which natives lived off Arctic wildlife?",
        "choices": [
            "The Inuit",
            "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest",
            "Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region and the Iroquois",
            "The Sioux"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Inuit lived off Arctic wildlife. West Coast natives preserved fish by drying and smoking. Warfare was common among Aboriginal groups as they competed for land, resources and prestige.",
        "answer": "The Inuit"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c93",
        "question": "What is a minority government?",
        "choices": [
            "The party in power that holds less than half of the seats in the Senate and the House of Commons",
            "The party in power that holds less than half of the seats in the Senate",
            "The party in power that holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons",
            "The party in power that holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "If the party in power holds at least half of the seats in the House of Commons, this is called a majority government. If the party in power holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons, this is called a minority government.",
        "answer": "The party in power that holds less than half of the seats in the House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c98",
        "question": "When was O Canada declared the National anthem?",
        "choices": [
            "1980",
            "1822",
            "1805",
            "1920"
        ],
        "explanation": "O Canada was proclaimed as the national anthem in 1980. It was first sung in Québec City in 1880. French and English Canadians sing different words to the national anthem.",
        "answer": "1980"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c97",
        "question": "Who defended the rights of the Canadiens and defeated an American military invasion of Quebec in 1775?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Count Frontenac",
            "Sir Guy Carleton",
            "Bishop Laval"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Guy Carleton (Lord Dorchester), as Governor of Quebec, defended the rights of the Canadiens, defeated an American military invasion of Quebec in 1775, and supervised the Loyalist migration to Nova Scotia and Quebec in 1782–83.",
        "answer": "Sir Guy Carleton"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c95",
        "question": "What do you call the people who run for office?",
        "choices": [
            "Electives",
            "Officers",
            "Ministers",
            "Candidates"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian citizens who are 18 years old or older may run in a federal election. The people who run for office are called candidates. There can be many candidates in an electoral district.",
        "answer": "Candidates"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c96",
        "question": "Which group of Aboriginal peoples has the largest population in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Metis",
            "First Nations",
            "Acadians",
            "Inuit"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 65% of the Aboriginal people are First Nations, while 30% are Métis and 4% Inuit.",
        "answer": "First Nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c94",
        "question": "When did Canada take over the vast northwest region from the Hudson’s Bay Company?",
        "choices": [
            "1864",
            "1949",
            "1905",
            "1869"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada took over the vast northwest region from the Hudson’s Bay Company in 1869, the 12,000 Métis of the Red River were not consulted. In response, Louis Riel led an armed uprising and seized Fort Garry, the territorial capital.",
        "answer": "1869"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c92",
        "question": "What would best describe the role of the King or Queen in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Queen or King is a symbol of Canadian citizenship and mobility rights",
            "The Queen or King appoints all Cabinet Ministers and Prime Ministers",
            "The Queen or King must approve all government decisions",
            "The Queen or King is a symbol of Canadian sovereignty and a guardian of constitutional freedoms"
        ],
        "explanation": "The King or Queen is a symbol of Canadian sovereignty, a guardian of constitutional freedoms, and a reflection of our history.",
        "answer": "The Queen or King is a symbol of Canadian sovereignty and a guardian of constitutional freedoms"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c99",
        "question": "After an election, who is invited by the Governor General to form the government?",
        "choices": [
            "The leader who has the approval of the Queen",
            "The leader who has been directly elected by Canadians",
            "The leader of the political party with the most seats in the House of Commons",
            "The members of Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ordinarily, after an election, the leader of the political party with the most seats in the House of Commons is invited by the Governor General to form the government.",
        "answer": "The leader of the political party with the most seats in the House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9a",
        "question": "When did King Charles III become King?",
        "choices": [
            "1988",
            "2021",
            "2022",
            "1654"
        ],
        "explanation": "King Charles III became the King of Canada in 2022.",
        "answer": "2022"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9b",
        "question": "What does P.E.I. stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Port Edward Island",
            "Prince Edgar Island",
            "Prince Edmond Island"
        ],
        "explanation": "P.E.I. stands for Prince Edward Island.",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca2",
        "question": "What does \"NAFTA\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "North American Free Treasury Agreement",
            "National Armed Forces Treaty Agreement",
            "North American Free Trade Agreement",
            "North American Forced Trade Agreement"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1988, Canada enacted free trade with the United States. Mexico became a partner in 1994 in the broader North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), with over 444 million people and over $1 trillion in merchandise trade in 2008.",
        "answer": "North American Free Trade Agreement"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca0",
        "question": "From which civilization does Canadian society stem largely from?",
        "choices": [
            "Aboriginal",
            "English-speaking and French-speaking Christians",
            "Acadian",
            "Chinese"
        ],
        "explanation": "The great majority of Canadians identify as Christians. The largest religious affiliation is Catholic, followed by various Protestant churches. The numbers of Muslims, Jews, Hindus, Sikhs and members of other religions, as well as people who state “no religion” are also growing.",
        "answer": "English-speaking and French-speaking Christians"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9e",
        "question": "What do you call the King’s or Queen’s representative in the provinces?",
        "choices": [
            "Lieutenant Governor",
            "Premier",
            "Senator",
            "Member of Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign is represented in Canada by the Governor General, who is appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister, usually for five years. In each of the ten provinces, the Sovereign is represented by the Lieutenant Governor, who is appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister, also normally for five years.",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Governor"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9f",
        "question": "Canada is personified by the Sovereign",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, we profess our loyalty to a person who represents all Canadians and not to a document such as a constitution, a banner such as a flag, or a geopolitical entity such as a country. In our constitutional monarchy, these elements are encompassed by the Sovereign (Queen or King). It is a remarkably simple yet powerful principle: Canada is personified by the Sovereign just as the Sovereign is personified by Canada.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca1",
        "question": "In Canada, where can you find one of the longest continuous multispan bridges in the world?",
        "choices": [
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Quebec",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Ontario"
        ],
        "explanation": "Prince Edward Island (P.E.I.) is the smallest province, known for its beaches, red soil and agriculture, especially potatoes. P.E.I. is the birthplace of Confederation, connected to mainland Canada by one of the longest continuous multispan bridges in the world, the Confederation Bridge.",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9d",
        "question": "In Canada, abuse of your spouse is:",
        "choices": [
            "Tolerated",
            "Normal",
            "Lawful",
            "Illegal"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, men and women are equal under the law. Canada’s openness and generosity do not extend to barbaric cultural practices that tolerate spousal abuse.",
        "answer": "Illegal"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c9c",
        "question": "What is the shared jurisdiction of the federal and provincial governments?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural Resources and immigration",
            "Agriculture and civil rights",
            "Agriculture and immigration",
            "Education and highways"
        ],
        "explanation": "The federal government and the provinces share jurisdiction over agriculture and immigration.",
        "answer": "Agriculture and immigration"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca3",
        "question": "To how many other Commonwealth nations is Canada linked?",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "12",
            "53",
            "49"
        ],
        "explanation": "As Head of the Commonwealth, the Sovereign links Canada to 53 other nations that cooperate to advance social, economic and cultural progress.",
        "answer": "53"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca7",
        "question": "What is Canada’s most westerly province?",
        "choices": [
            "British Columbia",
            "Alberta",
            "Yukon",
            "Alaska"
        ],
        "explanation": "British Columbia is Canada’s most westerly province.",
        "answer": "British Columbia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca5",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what does MNA stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Members of the National Assembly",
            "Municipal and National Assembly",
            "Members of the Nunavut Assembly",
            "Major National Assembly"
        ],
        "explanation": "The members of the legislature are called members of the Legislative Assembly (MLAs), members of the National Assembly (MNAs), members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs) or members of the House of Assembly (MHAs), depending on the province or territory.",
        "answer": "Members of the National Assembly"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca4",
        "question": "The Blackberry is a Canadian invention",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "Mike Lazaridis and Jim Balsillie — of Research in Motion (RIM) — a wireless communications company known for its most famous invention: the BlackBerry.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca6",
        "question": "What type of bond did Aboriginals and Europeans form in the first 200 years of coexistence?",
        "choices": [
            "Economic, religious and military",
            "Economic and Military",
            "Religious",
            "Economic"
        ],
        "explanation": "Aboriginals and Europeans formed strong economic, religious and military bonds in the first 200 years of coexistence which laid the foundations of Canada.",
        "answer": "Economic, religious and military"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca9",
        "question": "What did Upper Canada mainly consist of?",
        "choices": [
            "Catholic and French-speaking people",
            "Loyalist, Catholic and English-speaking people",
            "Protestant and French-speaking people",
            "Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking people"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 divided the Province of Quebec into Upper Canada (later Ontario), which was mainly Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking.",
        "answer": "Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking people"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ca8",
        "question": "When was Old Age Security devised?",
        "choices": [
            "1940",
            "1970",
            "1927",
            "1965"
        ],
        "explanation": "Old Age Security was devised as early as 1927, and the Canada and Quebec Pension Plans in 1965.",
        "answer": "1927"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8caa",
        "question": "In Canada, who do we profess loyalty to?",
        "choices": [
            "To the Canadian flag",
            "To Canada",
            "To the Constitution of Canada",
            "To a person who represents all Canadians"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, we profess our loyalty to a person who represents all Canadians and not to a document such as a constitution, a banner such as a flag, or a geopolitical entity such as a country. In our constitutional monarchy, these elements are encompassed by the Sovereign (Queen or King).",
        "answer": "To a person who represents all Canadians"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c74",
        "question": "Why did Canada adopt an official coat of arms and a national motto?",
        "choices": [
            "As a direct request from the Queen of England",
            "To imitate the United States",
            "As an expression of imperialism after the First World War",
            "As an expression of national pride after the First World War"
        ],
        "explanation": "As an expression of national pride after the First World War, Canada adopted an official coat of arms and a national motto, A mari usque ad mare, which in Latin means “from sea to sea.”",
        "answer": "As an expression of national pride after the First World War"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cab",
        "question": "What was the \"Great Upheaval\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The deportation of more than two-third of Inuit from their homeland between 1755 and 1763",
            "The great earthquake that ravaged Canada's East Coast during the 18th century",
            "The deportation of more than two-third of Aboriginal from their homeland between 1755 and 1763",
            "The deportation of more than two-third of Acadians from their homeland between 1755 and 1763"
        ],
        "explanation": "Between 1755 and 1763, during the war between Britain and France, more than two-thirds of the Acadians were deported from their homeland. Despite this ordeal, known as the “Great Upheaval,” the Acadians survived and maintained their unique identity.",
        "answer": "The deportation of more than two-third of Acadians from their homeland between 1755 and 1763"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cad",
        "question": "How do Canadians vote?",
        "choices": [
            "By secret ballot",
            "By open ballot",
            "By mail",
            "Online"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian law secures the right to a secret ballot. This means that no one can watch you vote and no one should look at how you voted.",
        "answer": "By secret ballot"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cae",
        "question": "What forms the Cabinet?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister and the Cabinet ministers",
            "The Prime Minister and the Senators",
            "The Prime Minister and the House of Commons",
            "The Senate and the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Prime Minister and the Cabinet ministers are called the Cabinet and they make important decisions about how the country is governed.",
        "answer": "The Prime Minister and the Cabinet ministers"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb7",
        "question": "Where are the provincial and territorial laws passed?",
        "choices": [
            "In the provincial and territorial courts",
            "In the elected legislature",
            "In the House of Commons",
            "In the Senate"
        ],
        "explanation": "Each provincial and territorial government has an elected legislature where provincial and territorial laws are passed.",
        "answer": "In the provincial and territorial courts"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb9",
        "question": "By the 1960s, how many Canadians had origins that were neither British nor French?",
        "choices": [
            "One-third",
            "One-quarter",
            "Half",
            "Two-third"
        ],
        "explanation": "By the 1960s, one-third of Canadians had origins that were neither British nor French, and took pride in preserving their distinct culture in the Canadian fabric.",
        "answer": "One-third"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb6",
        "question": "In Canada, gays and lesbians enjoy the full protection of and equal treatment under the law, including access to civil marriage",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s diversity includes gay and lesbian Canadians, who enjoy the full protection of and equal treatment under the law, including access to civil marriage. Together, these diverse groups, sharing a common Canadian identity, make up today’s multicultural society.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb2",
        "question": "What do Canadians celebrate on Victoria Day?",
        "choices": [
            "The Sovereign's birthday",
            "The sacrifices of Canadian veterans and brave fallen in all wars",
            "The Canadian Victory in the war of 1812 against the United States",
            "The Birth of Christ"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign’s birthday is celebrated on Victoria Day (Monday preceding May 25).",
        "answer": "The Sovereign's birthday"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8caf",
        "question": "Which of the following is the largest fresh water lake in the world?",
        "choices": [
            "Lake Superior",
            "Lake Erie",
            "Lake Ontario",
            "Lake Huron"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are five Great Lakes located between Ontario and the United States: Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake Michigan (in the U.S.A.) and Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world.",
        "answer": "Lake Superior"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb4",
        "question": "In terms of size, how does Ottawa’s metropolitan area rank in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Third largest metropolitan area",
            "Largest metropolitan area",
            "Second largest metropolitan area",
            "Fourth largest metropolitan area"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ottawa, located on the Ottawa River, was chosen as the capital in 1857 by Queen Victoria, the great-great-grandmother of Queen Elizabeth II. Today it is Canada’s fourth largest metropolitan area.",
        "answer": "Fourth largest metropolitan area"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb5",
        "question": "What do you call the elected officials on a federal level?",
        "choices": [
            "The Governor Generals",
            "Members of Province",
            "Members of Parliament (MPs)",
            "Electorate College"
        ],
        "explanation": "The citizens in each electoral district elect one MP who sits in the House of Commons to represent them, as well as all Canadians.",
        "answer": "Members of Parliament (MPs)"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb1",
        "question": "Who are Anglophones?",
        "choices": [
            "British people",
            "People who speak French as a first language",
            "Aboriginal people who speak English as a first language",
            "People who speak English as a first language"
        ],
        "explanation": "English and French are the two official languages and are important symbols of identity. English speakers (Anglophones) and French speakers (Francophones) have lived together in partnership and creative tension for more than 300 years.",
        "answer": "People who speak English as a first language"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cbe",
        "question": "Who invented the snowmobile?",
        "choices": [
            "Joseph-Armand Bombardier",
            "Joseph-Armand Skidoo",
            "Mike Lazaridis",
            "Matthew Evans"
        ],
        "explanation": "Joseph-Armand Bombardier — invented the snowmobile, a light-weight winter vehicle.",
        "answer": "Joseph-Armand Bombardier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cbb",
        "question": "How are Senators appointed?",
        "choices": [
            "By the Prime Minister",
            "By the Queen on the advice of the Prime Minister",
            "By the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister",
            "They are elected by the people"
        ],
        "explanation": "Senators are appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister and serve until age 75.",
        "answer": "By the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc9",
        "question": "The Great Charter of Freedoms is also known as:",
        "choices": [
            "Dominion of Canada",
            "Magna Carta",
            "Canadian Constitution",
            "Habeas Corpus"
        ],
        "explanation": "Magna Carta (also known as the Great Charter of Freedoms) was signed in the year 1215 in England.",
        "answer": "Magna Carta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cbd",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of a municipal elected official?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural Resources",
            "Healthcare",
            "Snow removal",
            "Highways"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipalities are normally responsible for urban or regional planning, streets and roads, sanitation (such as garbage removal), snow removal, firefighting, ambulance and other emergency services, recreation facilities, public transit and some local health and social services.",
        "answer": "Highways"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb0",
        "question": "Which of the following responsibilities comes with becoming a Canadian citizen?",
        "choices": [
            "Helping others in the community",
            "Buying a piece of land",
            "Camping",
            "Serving in the Army"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, rights come with responsibilities. These include:- Obeying the law- Taking responsibility for oneself and one’s family- Serving on a jury- Voting in elections - Helping others in the community- Protecting and enjoying our heritage and environment",
        "answer": "Helping others in the community"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cbf",
        "question": "What kind of symbols does the Canadian coat of arms contain?",
        "choices": [
            "Symbols of England, France and Scotland",
            "Symbols of England, France, Scotland and Ireland as well as red maple leaves",
            "Symbols of England and France",
            "Symbols of England and red maple leaves"
        ],
        "explanation": "The arms contain symbols of England, France, Scotland and Ireland as well as red maple leaves. Today the arms can be seen on dollar bills, government documents and public buildings.",
        "answer": "Symbols of England, France, Scotland and Ireland as well as red maple leaves"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb8",
        "question": "Who are generally referred to as \"English Canadians\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Aboriginal People",
            "The Anglophones",
            "The British People",
            "French Immigrants"
        ],
        "explanation": "Generations of pioneers and builders of British origins, as well as other groups, invested and endured hardship in laying the foundations of our country. This helps explain why Anglophones (English speakers) are generally referred to as English Canadians.",
        "answer": "The Anglophones"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cba",
        "question": "What is often referred to as \"the goal heard around the world\"?",
        "choices": [
            "the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-Soviet Summit Series in 1972",
            "the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-USA Summit Series in 1972",
            "the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-Soviet Summit Series in 1992",
            "the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-Soviet Stanley Cup Series in 1972"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1972, Paul Henderson scored the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-Soviet Summit Series. This goal is often referred to as “the goal heard around the world” and is still remembered today as an important event in both sports and cultural history.",
        "answer": "the winning goal for Canada in the Canada-Soviet Summit Series in 1972"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc0",
        "question": "What was the Underground Railroad?",
        "choices": [
            "The name of a famous circle of Canadian artists in the late 1960s",
            "The unofficial railroad network linking small communities across Canada",
            "The name of the new railroad linking the East to the West of Canada",
            "A Christian anti-slavery network"
        ],
        "explanation": "Thousands of slaves escaped from the United States, followed “the North Star” and settled in Canada via the Underground Railroad, a Christian anti-slavery network.",
        "answer": "A Christian anti-slavery network"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cb3",
        "question": "When was the official Language Act passed in Parliament?",
        "choices": [
            "1805",
            "1905",
            "1969",
            "1621"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1963 Parliament established the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism. This led to the Official Languages Act (1969), which guarantees French and English services in the federal government across Canada.",
        "answer": "1969"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc1",
        "question": "Who dominated the fur trade in the North West during the French and British regimes?",
        "choices": [
            "The Hudson's Bay Company",
            "The North Star company",
            "The Sears company",
            "The Trading Post company"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Hudson’s Bay Company, with French, British and Aboriginal employees, came to dominate the trade in the northwest from Fort Garry (Winnipeg) and Fort Edmonton to Fort Langley (near Vancouver) and Fort Victoria—trading posts that later became cities.",
        "answer": "The Hudson's Bay Company"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc2",
        "question": "On election day, where should your ballot go?",
        "choices": [
            "In your pocket",
            "In the garbage bin",
            "In the ballot box",
            "It should stay on the voting table"
        ],
        "explanation": "The poll official will tear off the ballot number and give your ballot back to you to deposit in the ballot box.",
        "answer": "In the ballot box"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc7",
        "question": "For how many years is the Lieutenant Governor usually appointed?",
        "choices": [
            "Ten",
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Five"
        ],
        "explanation": "In each of the ten provinces, the Sovereign is represented by the Lieutenant Governor, who is appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister, also normally for five years.",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc4",
        "question": "What are Canada’s main types of industries?",
        "choices": [
            "Service, fishing and natural resources",
            "Farming and fishing",
            "Service, manufacturing and natural resources",
            "Tourism and natural resources"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s main types of industries are service, manufacturing and natural resources.",
        "answer": "Service, manufacturing and natural resources"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8c75",
        "question": "What does the Canada Health Act ensure?",
        "choices": [
            "Drinkable water for all Canadians",
            "Common elements and a basic standard of coverage",
            "Publicly funded education",
            "No more contagious epidemics in Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "As prosperity grew, so did the ability to support social assistance programs. The Canada Health Act ensures common elements and a basic standard of coverage.",
        "answer": "Common elements and a basic standard of coverage"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc5",
        "question": "When did Canada form a responsible government?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "2000",
            "1755",
            "1999"
        ],
        "explanation": "The British Parliament passed the British North America Act in 1867. The Dominion of Canada was officially born on July 1, 1867. Until 1982, July 1 was celebrated as “Dominion Day” to commemorate the day that Canada became a self-governing Dominion.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc6",
        "question": "Which of the following statement is true",
        "choices": [
            "There is no diversity in Canada",
            "Canadians do not enjoy human rights",
            "You are contributing to the ongoing history of Canada by becoming a Canadian",
            "Canadians are bound together by a divergent commitment to the rule of law"
        ],
        "explanation": "Settlers and immigrants have contributed to the diversity and richness of our country, which is built on a proud history and a strong identity.",
        "answer": "You are contributing to the ongoing history of Canada by becoming a Canadian"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc3",
        "question": "Who can question the decisions of the government?",
        "choices": [
            "The Senate only",
            "The Queen only",
            "Only certain members of the House of Commons",
            "All members of the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Prime Minister and the Cabinet ministers are called the Cabinet and they make important decisions about how the country is governed. They prepare the budget and propose most new laws. Their decisions can be questioned by all members of the House of Commons.",
        "answer": "All members of the House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cc8",
        "question": "Which Canadian circled the globe in a wheelchair to raise funds for spinal cord research?",
        "choices": [
            "Terry Fox",
            "Marshall McLuhan",
            "Rick Hansen",
            "Wayne Gretzky"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1985, fellow British Columbian Rick Hansen circled the globe in a wheelchair to raise funds for spinal cord research.",
        "answer": "Rick Hansen"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cca",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border the Northwest Territories?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Nunavut",
            "Yukon",
            "Alberta"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ontario does not border the Northwest Territories.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ccb",
        "question": "In Canada, where can you find the world’s highest tides?",
        "choices": [
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Quebec",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "British Columbia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nova Scotia is the most populous Atlantic Province, with a rich history as the gateway to Canada. Known for the world’s highest tides in the Bay of Fundy, the province’s identity is linked to shipbuilding, fisheries and shipping.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ccc",
        "question": "What do you call the Canadian honours system that recognizes outstanding citizens?",
        "choices": [
            "The Order of Canada",
            "The Honour of Canada",
            "The Medal of Canada",
            "The Decoration of Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "All countries have ways to recognize outstanding citizens. Official awards are called honours, consisting of orders, decorations and medals. After using British honours for many years, Canada started its own honours system with the Order of Canada in 1967, the centennial of Confederation.",
        "answer": "The Order of Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ccd",
        "question": "What are the two official languages of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Chinese and English",
            "French and English",
            "English and Inuit",
            "English and British"
        ],
        "explanation": "English and French are the two official languages in Canada and are important symbols of identity.",
        "answer": "French and English"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cce",
        "question": "In Canada, how can a party in power be defeated?",
        "choices": [
            "If the Governor General resigns",
            "If a majority of the members of the House of Commons vote against a major government decision",
            "If the Queen votes against a major government decision",
            "If a majority of the members of the House of Commons vote in favor of a major government decision"
        ],
        "explanation": "If a majority of the members of the House of Commons vote against a major government decision, the party in power is defeated, which usually results in the Prime Minister asking the Governor General, on behalf of the Sovereign, to call an election.",
        "answer": "If a majority of the members of the House of Commons vote against a major government decision"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd5",
        "question": "What did Lower Canada mainly consist of?",
        "choices": [
            "Protestant and French-speaking people",
            "Loyalist, Catholic and English-speaking people",
            "Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking people",
            "Catholic and French-speaking people"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 divided the Province of Quebec into Upper Canada (later Ontario), which was mainly Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking, and Lower Canada (later Quebec), heavily Catholic and French-speaking.",
        "answer": "Catholic and French-speaking people"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd0",
        "question": "What is the origin of Habeas corpus?",
        "choices": [
            "Irish common law",
            "Magna Carta",
            "Civil code of France",
            "English common law"
        ],
        "explanation": "Habeas corpus, the right to challenge unlawful detention by the state, comes from English common law.",
        "answer": "English common law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd1",
        "question": "Which natives were farmers and hunters?",
        "choices": [
            "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest",
            "Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region and the Iroquois",
            "The Sioux",
            "The Inuit"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region, like the Iroquois, were farmers and hunters.",
        "answer": "Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region and the Iroquois"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd3",
        "question": "Who invented Basketball?",
        "choices": [
            "Wayne Gretzky",
            "Donovan Bailey",
            "James Naismith",
            "Terry Fox"
        ],
        "explanation": "Basketball was invented by Canadian James Naismith in 1891.",
        "answer": "James Naismith"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ccf",
        "question": "Which Act guarantees French and English services in the federal government across Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Bilingual Act",
            "The Official Languages Act",
            "The French Language Act",
            "The English Language Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1963 Parliament established the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism. This led to the Official Languages Act (1969), which guarantees French and English services in the federal government across Canada.",
        "answer": "The Official Languages Act"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd4",
        "question": "What are Municipal laws called?",
        "choices": [
            "City laws",
            "By-laws",
            "Local laws",
            "Municipal laws"
        ],
        "explanation": "Municipal governments usually have a council that passes laws called “by-laws” that affect only the local community.",
        "answer": "By-laws"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd2",
        "question": "Which province or territory holds the record for the coldest temperature ever recorded in Canada (-63 C)?",
        "choices": [
            "Nunavut",
            "Alberta",
            "Ontario",
            "Yukon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Yukon holds the record for the coldest temperature ever recorded in Canada (-63°C).",
        "answer": "Yukon"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd8",
        "question": "When was the Charter of Rights and Freedoms incorporated into the Canadian Constitution?",
        "choices": [
            "1982",
            "1859",
            "1902",
            "1949"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitution of Canada was amended in 1982 to entrench the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms.",
        "answer": "1982"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd7",
        "question": "What is the capital of New Brunswick?",
        "choices": [
            "Regina",
            "Fredericton",
            "Winnipeg",
            "Halifax"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saint John is the largest city, port and manufacturing centre; Moncton is the principal Francophone Acadian centre; and Fredericton, is the historic capital.",
        "answer": "Fredericton"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd6",
        "question": "Which of the following is not an objective of the laws in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Provide a peaceful way to settle disputes",
            "Express the values and beliefs of Canadians",
            "Put more people in jail",
            "Provide order in society"
        ],
        "explanation": "Our laws are intended to provide order in society and a peaceful way to settle disputes, and to express the values and beliefs of Canadians.",
        "answer": "Put more people in jail"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cd9",
        "question": "Who was the key architect of Confederation from Quebec?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier",
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir John Alexander Macdonald",
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir George-Étienne Cartier was the key architect of Confederation from Quebec. A railway lawyer, Montrealer, close ally of Macdonald and patriotic Canadien, Cartier led Quebec into Confederation and helped negotiate the entry of the Northwest Territories, Manitoba and British Columbia into Canada.",
        "answer": "Sir George-Etienne Cartier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cdb",
        "question": "What does \"Nunavut\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "Our village",
            "The land of the midnight sun",
            "\"Our land\"",
            "Our country"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nunavut, meaning “our land” in Inuktitut, was established in 1999 from the eastern part of the Northwest Territories, including all of the former District of Keewatin.",
        "answer": "\"Our land\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cda",
        "question": "Which province has 40% of the arable land in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Yukon",
            "Manitoba",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "New Brunswick"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatchewan, once known as the “breadbasket of the world” and the “wheat province,” has 40% of the arable land in Canada and is the country’s largest producer of grains and oilseeds.",
        "answer": "Saskatchewan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cdc",
        "question": "In a federal election, in each electoral district, what does the candidate who receives the most votes become?",
        "choices": [
            "The MP",
            "The Governor General",
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The House Leader"
        ],
        "explanation": "The people in each electoral district vote for the candidate and political party of their choice. The candidate who receives the most votes becomes the MP for that electoral district.",
        "answer": "The MP"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cde",
        "question": "When did Canada become a Constitutional Monarchy?",
        "choices": [
            "2001",
            "1867",
            "1988",
            "1980"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has been a constitutional monarchy in its own right since Confederation in 1867 during Queen Victoria’s reign.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cbc",
        "question": "What is a noble way to contribute to Canada and an excellent career choice?",
        "choices": [
            "Join a union",
            "Serve in the Canadian Forces",
            "Serve on a jury",
            "Learn English & French"
        ],
        "explanation": "There is no compulsory military service in Canada. However, serving in the regular Canadian Forces (navy, army and air force) is a noble way to contribute to Canada and an excellent career choice (www.forces.ca).",
        "answer": "Serve in the Canadian Forces"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce0",
        "question": "Why is the North sometimes called the \"Land of the Midnight Sun\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Daylight can last up to 24 hours in winter",
            "Daylight can last up to 24 hours in spring",
            "Daylight can last up to 24 hours in fall",
            "Daylight can last up to 24 hours in summer"
        ],
        "explanation": "The North is often referred to as the “Land of the Midnight Sun” because at the height of summer, daylight can last up to 24 hours.",
        "answer": "Daylight can last up to 24 hours in summer"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cdf",
        "question": "Which natives were hunter-gatherers?",
        "choices": [
            "Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region and the Iroquois",
            "The Inuit",
            "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest",
            "The Sioux"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest were hunter-gatherers. The Sioux were nomadic, following the bison (buffalo) herd.",
        "answer": "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce1",
        "question": "In the epic invasion of Normandy in northern France in 1944, known as D-Day, which beach did the Canadians capture?",
        "choices": [
            "Omaha",
            "Utah",
            "Juno",
            "Gold"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the epic invasion of Normandy in northern France on June 6, 1944, known as D-Day, 15,000 Canadian troops stormed and captured Juno Beach from the German Army.",
        "answer": "Juno"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce5",
        "question": "Which of the following provinces/territories borders the Arctic Ocean?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba",
            "Nunavut",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "Ontario"
        ],
        "explanation": "The territory of Nunavut borders the Arctic Ocean.",
        "answer": "Nunavut"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce3",
        "question": "What level of government did the Fathers of Confederation create?",
        "choices": [
            "Provincial and municipal",
            "Federal and provincial",
            "Provincial and territorial",
            "Federal and municipal"
        ],
        "explanation": "From 1864 to 1867, representatives of Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and the Province of Canada, with British support, worked together to establish a new country. These men are known as the Fathers of Confederation. They created two levels of government: federal and provincial.",
        "answer": "Federal and provincial"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce9",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border New Brunswick?",
        "choices": [
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Quebec",
            "Atlantic Ocean"
        ],
        "explanation": "Prince Edward Island does not border New Brunswick.",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce2",
        "question": "Who became the first French-Canadian prime minister since Confederation?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier",
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine",
            "Sir Wilfrid Laurier"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier became the first French-Canadian prime minister since Confederation and encouraged immigration to the West. His portrait is on the $5 bill.",
        "answer": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cea",
        "question": "What is Canada’s official summer sport?",
        "choices": [
            "Soccer",
            "Basketball",
            "Baseball",
            "Lacrosse"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lacrosse, an ancient sport first played by Aboriginals, is the official summer sport.",
        "answer": "Lacrosse"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce4",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Saskatchewan?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba",
            "Alberta",
            "British Columbia",
            "U.S.A."
        ],
        "explanation": "British Columbia does not border Saskatchewan.",
        "answer": "British Columbia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce8",
        "question": "Who invented the worldwide system of standard time zones?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John A. Hopps",
            "Sir Sandford Fleming",
            "Sir Sandford Greenwich",
            "Sir Henry Woodward"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Sanford Fleming, a Canadian engineer, was the first person to propose the use of worldwide time zones.",
        "answer": "Sir Sandford Fleming"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce7",
        "question": "To become a Canadian citizen",
        "choices": [
            "You must prove that you have a sufficient command of either English or French and pass a citizenship test",
            "You only need to show that you have a basic understanding of either French or English",
            "You are not required to demonstrate proficiency in either French or English",
            "All you need to do is pass a citizenship Test"
        ],
        "explanation": "You must have adequate knowledge of English or French to become a Canadian citizen.",
        "answer": "You must prove that you have a sufficient command of either English or French and pass a citizenship test"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ce6",
        "question": "What comprises a provincial legislature?",
        "choices": [
            "The elected Assembly",
            "The provincial MPs",
            "The provincial MPs and the elected Assembly",
            "The Lieutenant Governor and the elected Assembly"
        ],
        "explanation": "Parliament has three parts: the Sovereign (Queen or King), the Senate and the House of Commons. Provincial legislatures comprise the Lieutenant Governor and the elected Assembly.",
        "answer": "The Lieutenant Governor and the elected Assembly"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cec",
        "question": "Which of the following does not serve as a foundation for Canadian law?",
        "choices": [
            "Military code of France",
            "English common law",
            "Civil code of France",
            "Laws passed by Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian law has several sources, including laws passed by Parliament and the provincial legislatures, English common law, the civil code of France and the unwritten constitution that we have inherited from Great Britain.",
        "answer": "Military code of France"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cee",
        "question": "Which phrase embodied the vision for the Dominion of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The land of the free and strong",
            "Dominion from ocean to ocean",
            "\"Dominion from sea to sea and from the river to the ends of the earth\"",
            "Oh Canada, my home and native land"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Leonard Tilley, an elected official and Father of Confederation from New Brunswick, suggested the term Dominion of Canada in 1864. He was inspired by Psalm 72 in the Bible which refers to “dominion from sea to sea and from the river to the ends of the earth.” This phrase embodied the vision of building a powerful, united, wealthy and free country that spanned a continent.",
        "answer": "\"Dominion from sea to sea and from the river to the ends of the earth\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ceb",
        "question": "With which words does the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms begin?",
        "choices": [
            "Oh Canada! Our home and native land!",
            "Canadian citizens have rights and responsibilities",
            "\"Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law\"",
            "Canada is a free country and home of the braves"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitution of Canada was amended in 1982 to entrench the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms, which begins with the words, “Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law.”",
        "answer": "\"Whereas Canada is founded upon principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8ced",
        "question": "Which province has the second largest river system on North America’s Atlantic coastline?",
        "choices": [
            "New Brunswick",
            "Quebec",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador"
        ],
        "explanation": "Situated in the Appalachian Range, the province was founded by the United Empire Loyalists and has the second largest river system on North America’s Atlantic coastline, the St. John River system.",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cac",
        "question": "The federal government is required by law to provide services throughout Canada in",
        "choices": [
            "English, French and Chinese",
            "English and French",
            "English only",
            "Chinese and English"
        ],
        "explanation": "English and French define the reality of day-to-day life for most people and are the country’s official languages. The federal government is required by law to provide services throughout Canada in English and French.",
        "answer": "English and French"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf1",
        "question": "Who is the Sovereign represented by in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Nobody",
            "The Lieutenant Governor",
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The Governor General"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign is represented in Canada by the Governor General, who is appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister, usually for five years.",
        "answer": "The Governor General"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf0",
        "question": "Who were the Loyalists?",
        "choices": [
            "French settlers",
            "French and British settlers",
            "British settlers",
            "Settlers from the United States who were loyal to the Crown"
        ],
        "explanation": "More than 40,000 people loyal to the Crown, called “Loyalists,” fled the oppression of the American Revolution to settle in Nova Scotia and Quebec. Joseph Brant led thousands of Loyalist Mohawk Indians into Canada. The Loyalists came from Dutch, German, British, Scandinavian, Aboriginal and other origins and from Presbyterian, Anglican, Baptist, Methodist, Jewish, Quaker and Catholic religious backgrounds. About 3,000 black Loyalists, freedmen and slaves came north seeking a better life. In turn, in 1792, some black Nova Scotians, who were given poor land, moved on to establish Freetown, Sierra Leone (West Africa), a new British colony for freed slaves.",
        "answer": "Settlers from the United States who were loyal to the Crown"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf4",
        "question": "How does a bill become a law?",
        "choices": [
            "The bill must be approved by the Members of the Parliament",
            "The bill must be passed by the House of Commons and the Senate, and must receive royal assent",
            "The bill must be signed by the Queen or King of England",
            "The bill must be passed by the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "Both the House of Commons and the Senate consider and review bills (proposals for new laws). No bill can become law in Canada until it has been passed by both chambers and has received royal assent, granted by the Governor General on behalf of the Sovereign.",
        "answer": "The bill must be passed by the House of Commons and the Senate, and must receive royal assent"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf5",
        "question": "What should you do on election day?",
        "choices": [
            "Nothing",
            "Call Elections Canada",
            "Go to your polling station",
            "Go to the nearest Election Canada's office"
        ],
        "explanation": "Go to your polling station. The location is on your voter information card. Bring this card and proof of your identity and address to the polling station.",
        "answer": "Go to your polling station"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf3",
        "question": "Where do Inuit people live?",
        "choices": [
            "In reserve land across the Northwest Territories",
            "In scattered communities across the Arctic",
            "Across the Yukon",
            "In small towns across Manitoba"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Inuit, which means “the people” in the Inuktitut language, live in small, scattered communities across the Arctic.",
        "answer": "In scattered communities across the Arctic"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf2",
        "question": "What are the names of the three major political parties currently represented in the House of Commons?",
        "choices": [
            "Conservative Party, Liberal Party and New Democratic Party",
            "New Democratic Party, Royal Party, and French Coalition",
            "Conservative Party, Liberal Party and New Royal Party",
            "Quebec Coalition, Conservative Party and Liberal Party"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are three major political parties currently represented in the House of Commons: the Conservative Party, the New Democratic Party, and the Liberal Party.",
        "answer": "Conservative Party, Liberal Party and New Democratic Party"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf6",
        "question": "How is the Governor General chosen?",
        "choices": [
            "Appointed by the Prime Minister",
            "Elected by the House of Commons",
            "Elected by the people",
            "Appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign is represented in Canada by the Governor General, who is appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister, usually for five years.",
        "answer": "Appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cfb",
        "question": "How many Canadians have died in all wars up to the present day?",
        "choices": [
            "110000",
            "55000",
            "500000",
            "220000"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians wear the red poppy and observe a moment of silence at the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month to honour the sacrifices of over a million brave men and women who have served, and the 110,000 who have given their lives.",
        "answer": "110000"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf7",
        "question": "When did the Parliament establish the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism?",
        "choices": [
            "1969",
            "1945",
            "1963",
            "1970"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1963 Parliament established the Royal Commission on Bilingualism and Biculturalism. This led to the Official Languages Act (1969), which guarantees French and English services in the federal government across Canada.",
        "answer": "1963"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cfa",
        "question": "When did the British Parliament pass the British North America Act?",
        "choices": [
            "1982",
            "1867",
            "1759",
            "1840"
        ],
        "explanation": "The British Parliament passed the British North America Act in 1867. The Dominion of Canada was officially born on July 1, 1867.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cfe",
        "question": "Acadians are the descendants of what groups?",
        "choices": [
            "French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604",
            "Metis and Inuits",
            "British colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604",
            "First Nations who began settling in what are now the Prairie provinces in 1600s"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Acadians are the descendants of French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604.",
        "answer": "French colonists who began settling in what are now the Maritime provinces in 1604"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cff",
        "question": "Who was a celebrated sculptor of historical figures?",
        "choices": [
            "Norman Jewison",
            "Emily Carr",
            "Louis-Philippe Hebert",
            "Kenojuak Ashevak"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec’s Louis-Philippe Hébert was a celebrated sculptor of historical figures. Kenojuak Ashevak pioneered modern Inuit art with etchings, prints and soapstone sculptures.",
        "answer": "Louis-Philippe Hebert"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf8",
        "question": "Which part of Canada is sometimes called the \"Land of the Midnight Sun\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The North",
            "The South",
            "The East",
            "Central Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The North is often referred to as the “Land of the Midnight Sun” because at the height of summer, daylight can last up to 24 hours. In winter, the sun disappears and darkness sets in for three months. The Northern territories have long cold winters and short cool summers.",
        "answer": "The North"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cfc",
        "question": "When was the maple leaf first adopted as a symbol in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1800s",
            "In the 1900s",
            "In the 1600s",
            "In the 1700s"
        ],
        "explanation": "The maple leaf is Canada’s best-known symbol. Maple leaves were adopted as a symbol by French Canadians in the 1700s, have appeared on Canadian uniforms and insignia since the 1850s, and are carved into the headstones of our fallen soldiers buried overseas and in Canada.",
        "answer": "In the 1700s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cfd",
        "question": "When was the Yukon Gold Rush?",
        "choices": [
            "In the 1940s",
            "In the 1790s",
            "In the 1890s",
            "In the 1920s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Thousands of miners came to the Yukon during the Gold Rush of the 1890s, as celebrated in the poetry of Robert W. Service. Mining remains a significant part of the economy.",
        "answer": "In the 1890s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cf9",
        "question": "Where can you see the results of an election?",
        "choices": [
            "Only on television",
            "On television or on the Elections Canada website",
            "Only on the Elections Canada website",
            "You have to call Elections Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "You can see the results on television or on the Elections Canada website (www.elections.ca).",
        "answer": "On television or on the Elections Canada website"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d00",
        "question": "Where does the majority of the Métis live?",
        "choices": [
            "Prairie provinces",
            "Northern provinces",
            "Atlantic provinces",
            "Southern  provinces"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Métis are a distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry, the majority of whom live in the Prairie provinces. They come from both French and English-speaking backgrounds and speak their own dialect, Michif.",
        "answer": "Prairie provinces"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d03",
        "question": "How many Francophones are there in Canada today?",
        "choices": [
            "50 million",
            "7 million",
            "5 million",
            "10 million"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, there are 18 million Anglophones—people who speak English as a first language—and seven million Francophones—people who speak French as their first language.",
        "answer": "7 million"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d02",
        "question": "When was Canada’s original constitutional document created?",
        "choices": [
            "1980",
            "1720",
            "2000",
            "1867"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s original constitutional document was created in 1867, the British North America Act.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d04",
        "question": "What does the word \"Inuit\" mean?",
        "choices": [
            "The land",
            "The village",
            "\"The people\"",
            "The far North"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Inuit, which means “the people” in the Inuktitut language, live in small, scattered communities across the Arctic.",
        "answer": "\"The people\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d01",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Manitoba?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "U.S.A.",
            "Saskatchewan"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec does not border Manitoba.",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d09",
        "question": "Who proclaimed the amended Constitution of Canada in 1982?",
        "choices": [
            "The people of Canada",
            "The Senate",
            "Queen Elizabeth II",
            "The Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Canadian Constitution was amended in 1982 to include the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms.",
        "answer": "Queen Elizabeth II"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0a",
        "question": "Who was Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe?",
        "choices": [
            "The leader of the loyalists",
            "Lower Canada's first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of Toronto",
            "Lower Canada's first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of Ottawa",
            "Upper Canada's first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of Toronto"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lieutenant-Colonel John Graves Simcoe was Upper Canada’s first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of York (now Toronto). Simcoe also made Upper Canada the first province in the British Empire to abolish slavery.",
        "answer": "Upper Canada's first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of Toronto"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d06",
        "question": "Who is Canada’s head of government?",
        "choices": [
            "The people",
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The Queen or King",
            "The House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "There is a clear distinction in Canada between the head of state—the Sovereign—and the head of government—the Prime Minister, who actually directs the governing of the country.",
        "answer": "The Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d07",
        "question": "There can be many candidates in an electoral district",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "The people who run for office are called candidates. There can be many candidates in an electoral district.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d05",
        "question": "What percentage of Aboriginal people are First Nations?",
        "choices": [
            "60",
            "50",
            "80",
            "65"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 65% of the Aboriginal people are First Nations, while 30% are Métis and 4% Inuit.",
        "answer": "65"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d08",
        "question": "How is the Lieutenant Governor chosen?",
        "choices": [
            "Appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister",
            "Appointed by the Governor General",
            "Appointed by the Prime Minister",
            "Appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign is represented by the Lieutenant Governor, who is appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister, also normally for five years.",
        "answer": "Appointed by the Governor General on the advice of the Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0b",
        "question": "How many territories are there in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Three",
            "Two",
            "Four",
            "One"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has ten provinces and three territories. Each province and territory has its own capital city. You should know the capital of your province or territory as well as that of Canada.",
        "answer": "Three"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0c",
        "question": "How does Elections Canada give the election card to the electors whose names are in the National Register of Electors?",
        "choices": [
            "Door delivery",
            "By mail",
            "None of the above",
            "Electors have to pick it up their voter information card at an Elections Canada's office"
        ],
        "explanation": "Once an election has been called, Elections Canada mails a voter information card to each elector whose name is in the National Register of Electors.",
        "answer": "By mail"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0f",
        "question": "When was the Constitutional Act passed?",
        "choices": [
            "1758",
            "1791",
            "1889",
            "1609"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 divided the Province of Quebec into Upper Canada and Lower Canada.",
        "answer": "1791"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d13",
        "question": "What is Canada’s national capital?",
        "choices": [
            "Toronto",
            "Ottawa",
            "Montreal",
            "Vancouver"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ottawa, located on the Ottawa River, was chosen as the capital in 1857 by Queen Victoria, the great-great-grandmother of Queen Elizabeth II. Today it is Canada’s fourth largest metropolitan area.",
        "answer": "Ottawa"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d12",
        "question": "What form of government does Canada have?",
        "choices": [
            "Constitutional Monarchy",
            "Monarchy",
            "Autocracy",
            "Republic"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is a constitutional monarchy, a parliamentary democracy and a federal state. Canadians are bound together by a shared commitment to the rule of law and to the institutions of parliamentary government.",
        "answer": "Constitutional Monarchy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d14",
        "question": "What is the official Royal Flag of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Royal Standard Flag",
            "The Union Jack Flag",
            "Her Majesty personal Flag",
            "The Royal Arms Flag"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Union Jack is our official Royal Flag.",
        "answer": "The Union Jack Flag"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0e",
        "question": "The British territories in the Caribbean Sea are part of Canada.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the 1920s, some believed that the British West Indies (British territories in the Caribbean Sea) should become part of Canada. This did not occur, though Canada and Commonwealth Caribbean countries and territories enjoy close ties today.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d10",
        "question": "How many national parks does Alberta have?",
        "choices": [
            "Five",
            "One",
            "Ten",
            "Three"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alberta has five national parks, including Banff National Park, established in 1885.",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d0d",
        "question": "Why did the first European explorers call the native peoples \"Indians\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Because \"Indian\" means \"aboriginal\" in Irish",
            "They thought they had reached Indonesia",
            "Because they named their first town \"Indianapolis\"",
            "They thought they had reached the East Indies"
        ],
        "explanation": "When Europeans explored Canada they found all regions occupied by native peoples they called Indians, because the first explorers thought they had reached the East Indies.",
        "answer": "They thought they had reached the East Indies"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d11",
        "question": "Which province has the world’s richest deposits of uranium and potash?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba",
            "Ontario",
            "Alberta",
            "Saskatchewan"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatchewan boasts the world’s richest deposits of uranium and potash, used in fertilizer, and produces oil and natural gas.",
        "answer": "Saskatchewan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d15",
        "question": "What was the name of the free association of states that the British Empire had evolved into after the First World War?",
        "choices": [
            "The British Commonwealth of Nations",
            "The British Armed Nations",
            "The British Colonial Dominion",
            "The British Empire"
        ],
        "explanation": "After the First World War, the British Empire evolved into a free association of states known as the British Commonwealth of Nations. Canada remains a leading member of the Commonwealth to this day, together with other successor states of the Empire such as India, Australia, New Zealand, and several African and Caribbean countries.",
        "answer": "The British Commonwealth of Nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d16",
        "question": "What kind of commitment do Canadian institutions uphold?",
        "choices": [
            "Work, Order and Home Ownership",
            "Peace, Order, and Mobility Rights",
            "Peace, Order, and Good Government",
            "Work, Order, and Good Government"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s institutions uphold a commitment to Peace, Order and Good Government, a key phrase in Canada’s original constitutional document in 1867, the British North America Act.",
        "answer": "Peace, Order, and Good Government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d19",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of the provinces?",
        "choices": [
            "Interprovincial trade",
            "Highways",
            "Defence",
            "Foreign policy"
        ],
        "explanation": "The provinces are responsible for municipal government, education, health, natural resources, property and civil rights, and highways.",
        "answer": "Highways"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d18",
        "question": "Which of the following borders Nova Scotia?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Prince Edward Island"
        ],
        "explanation": "New Brunswick borders Nova Scotia.",
        "answer": "New Brunswick"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d17",
        "question": "Which city is the principal Francophone Acadian centre in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Charlottetown",
            "Quebec City",
            "Moncton",
            "Montreal"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saint John is the largest city, port and manufacturing centre; Moncton is the principal Francophone Acadian centre; and Fredericton, the historic capital.",
        "answer": "Moncton"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d25",
        "question": "When was the British North America Act. adopted in Canada",
        "choices": [
            "1999",
            "1765",
            "1700",
            "1867"
        ],
        "explanation": "The British North America Act, commonly referred to as the Constitution Act, was adopted by the British Parliament in 1867.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d26",
        "question": "Which of the following borders Newfoundland and Labrador?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "Ontario",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec borders Newfoundland and Labrador.",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d24",
        "question": "Where does the name \"Canada\" come from?",
        "choices": [
            "From the Inuit word \"kanata\", meaning \"village\"",
            "From the Iroquoian word \"kanata\", meaning \"village\"",
            "From the Iroquoian word \"kanata\", meaning \"home\"",
            "From the Iroquoian word \"kanata\", meaning \"land\""
        ],
        "explanation": "Cartier heard two captured guides speak the Iroquoian word kanata, meaning “village.” By the 1550s, the name of Canada began appearing on maps.",
        "answer": "From the Iroquoian word \"kanata\", meaning \"village\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d28",
        "question": "Quebecers are the descendants of what groups?",
        "choices": [
            "British colonists who began settling in the 1600s in what are now the Maritime provinces",
            "Metis and Inuit",
            "Acadians",
            "French settlers from the 1600s and 1700s"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebecers are the people of Quebec, the vast majority French-speaking. Most are descendants of 8,500 French settlers from the 1600s and 1700s and maintain a unique identity, culture and language.",
        "answer": "French settlers from the 1600s and 1700s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d27",
        "question": "What was known as \"British North America\" in 1791?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario and lower Canada",
            "The Atlantic colonies and the two Canadas (upper and lower)",
            "The two Canadas (upper and lower)",
            "Ontario and upper Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 granted to the Canadas, for the first time, legislative assemblies elected by the people. The name Canada also became official at this time and has been used ever since. The Atlantic colonies and the two Canadas were known collectively as British North America.",
        "answer": "The two Canadas (upper and lower)"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d29",
        "question": "What is the difference between the Head of State and the Head of Government?",
        "choices": [
            "The Head of State appoints the Head of Government",
            "The Head of Government doesn't actually direct the governing of the country",
            "The Head of State must approve all government decisions",
            "The Head of Government actually directs the governing of the country"
        ],
        "explanation": "There is a clear distinction in Canada between the head of state—the Sovereign—and the head of government—the Prime Minister, who actually directs the governing of the country.",
        "answer": "The Head of Government actually directs the governing of the country"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1b",
        "question": "Who does a member of Parliament represent?",
        "choices": [
            "The citizens in his/her electoral district, as well as all Canadians",
            "The Provincial Courts",
            "Only the citizens in his/her electoral district",
            "The Provincial and Territorial governments"
        ],
        "explanation": "An electoral district is a geographical area represented by a member of Parliament (MP). The citizens in each electoral district elect one MP who sits in the House of Commons to represent them, as well as all Canadians.",
        "answer": "The citizens in his/her electoral district, as well as all Canadians"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2d",
        "question": "Which province is the only officially bilingual province?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "New Brunswick is the only officially bilingual province.",
        "answer": "New Brunswick"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1e",
        "question": "When must federal elections be held?",
        "choices": [
            "By order of the Prime Minister",
            "Every four years following the most recent general election",
            "Every five years following the most recent general election",
            "By order of the Queen"
        ],
        "explanation": "Under legislation passed by Parliament, federal elections must be held on the third Monday in October every four years following the most recent general election.",
        "answer": "Every four years following the most recent general election"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1f",
        "question": "What was the \"Quiet Revolution\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The coming of the Old Age Security in Canada",
            "The development of Canada's autonomy in the world after the Second World War",
            "The Cold War between the East and the West",
            "An era of rapid change in the 1960s in Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "French-Canadian society and culture flourished in the postwar years. Quebec experienced an era of rapid change in the 1960s known as the Quiet Revolution. Many Quebecers sought to separate from Canada.",
        "answer": "An era of rapid change in the 1960s in Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2b",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of the members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures?",
        "choices": [
            "Agriculture and immigration",
            "Education and health",
            "Matters of international concern",
            "Keeping the government accountable"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada’s parliamentary democracy, the people elect members to the House of Commons in Ottawa and to the provincial and territorial legislatures. These representatives are responsible for passing laws, approving and monitoring expenditures, and keeping the government accountable.",
        "answer": "Keeping the government accountable"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d21",
        "question": "For which championship does the National Hockey League play?",
        "choices": [
            "The All Star Hockey Cup",
            "Stanley Cup",
            "NHL Cup",
            "Clarkson Cup"
        ],
        "explanation": "The National Hockey League plays for the championship Stanley Cup, donated by Lord Stanley, the Governor General, in 1892.",
        "answer": "Stanley Cup"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d23",
        "question": "In which Act are the responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments defined?",
        "choices": [
            "The Responsibilities Act",
            "The Constitution Act",
            "The Federal Act",
            "The Government Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "The responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments were defined in 1867 in the British North America Act, now known as the Constitution Act, 1867.",
        "answer": "The Constitution Act"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2e",
        "question": "What do the initials \"MP\" stand for in Canadian politics?",
        "choices": [
            "Member of Politics",
            "Ministers of Parliaments",
            "Member of Parliament",
            "Masters of Parliament"
        ],
        "explanation": "An electoral district is a geographical area represented by a member of Parliament (MP).",
        "answer": "Member of Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2a",
        "question": "What do you mark on a federal election ballot?",
        "choices": [
            "The candidate's name",
            "The candidate's number",
            "An \"X\"",
            "The party's name"
        ],
        "explanation": "Mark an “X” in the circle next to the name of the candidate of your choice.",
        "answer": "The candidate's name"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2c",
        "question": "What is the capital of Saskatchewan?",
        "choices": [
            "Regina",
            "Winnipeg",
            "Saskatoon",
            "Edmonton"
        ],
        "explanation": "Regina is the capital of Saskatchewan.",
        "answer": "Regina"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d20",
        "question": "How many First Nations people live on reserve land today?",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "About half",
            "About two thirds",
            "About one third"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, about half of First Nations people live on reserve land in about 600 communities while the other half live off-reserve, mainly in urban centres.",
        "answer": "About half"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1c",
        "question": "Who defeated Napoleon in 1815, and therefore played a direct role in founding the national capital?",
        "choices": [
            "The Duke of Wellington",
            "Bishop Laval",
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Sir Guy Carleton"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Duke of Wellington sent some of his best soldiers to defend Canada in 1814. He then chose Bytown (Ottawa) as the endpoint of the Rideau Canal, part of a network of forts to prevent the U.S.A. from invading Canada again. Wellington, who defeated Napoleon in 1815, therefore played a direct role in founding the national capital.",
        "answer": "The Duke of Wellington"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1d",
        "question": "What is the first sentence of the National Anthem?",
        "choices": [
            "O Canada! Our home and native land!",
            "From far and wide, O Canada",
            "O Canada, we stand on guard for thee",
            "The true North strong and free!"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first parts of O Canada are as follows;O Canada! Our home and native land!True patriot love in all thy sons commandWith glowing hearts we see thee riseThe true North strong and free!From far and wide, O CanadaWe stand on guard for theeGod keep our land glorious and free!O Canada, we stand on guard for theeO Canada, we stand on guard for thee",
        "answer": "O Canada! Our home and native land!"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d1a",
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Remembrance Day poppy?",
        "choices": [
            "To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day",
            "To honour prime ministers who have died",
            "To remember our Sovereign Queen Elizabeth II",
            "To celebrate Confederation"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians remember the sacrifices of our veterans and brave fallen in all wars up to the present day in which Canadians took part, each year on November 11: Remembrance Day.",
        "answer": "To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d22",
        "question": "In the territories, who represents the government?",
        "choices": [
            "The Commissioner",
            "The King or Queen",
            "The Lieutenant Governor",
            "The Premier"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the three territories, the Commissioner represents the federal government and plays a ceremonial role.",
        "answer": "The Commissioner"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cdd",
        "question": "In Canada, who is above the law?",
        "choices": [
            "The King or Queen",
            "The police",
            "The Prime Minister",
            "Nobody"
        ],
        "explanation": "One of Canada’s founding principles is the rule of law. Individuals and governments are regulated by laws and not by arbitrary actions. No person or group is above the law.",
        "answer": "Nobody"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d37",
        "question": "The rules for provincial, territorial and municipal elections are the same as for federal elections.",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Provincial, territorial and municipal elections are held by secret ballot, but the rules are not the same as those for federal elections. It is important to find out the rules for voting in provincial, territorial and local elections so that you can exercise your right to vote.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d38",
        "question": "What is Canada’s smallest province?",
        "choices": [
            "Nunavut",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Prince Edward Island"
        ],
        "explanation": "Prince Edward Island (P.E.I.) is the smallest province, known for its beaches, red soil and agriculture, especially potatoes. P.E.I. is the birthplace of Confederation, connected to mainland Canada by one of the longest continuous multispan bridges in the world, the Confederation Bridge.",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3e",
        "question": "Which of the following is a writer who has diversified Canada’s literary experience?",
        "choices": [
            "Healey Willan",
            "Michael Ondaatje",
            "Denys Arcand",
            "Louis-Philippe Hebert"
        ],
        "explanation": "Writers such as Joy Kogawa, Michael Ondaatje and Rohinton Mistry have diversified Canada’s literary experience.",
        "answer": "Michael Ondaatje"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d42",
        "question": "When did Canada draw closer to the United States and other trading partners?",
        "choices": [
            "Between 1925 and 1960",
            "Between 1945 and 1970",
            "Between 1980 and 1990",
            "Between 1970 and 1980"
        ],
        "explanation": "Between 1945 and 1970, Canada drew closer to the United States and other trading partners, the country enjoyed one of the strongest economies among industrialized nations. Today, Canadians enjoy one of the world’s highest standards of living—maintained by the hard work of Canadians and by trade with other nations, in particular the United States.",
        "answer": "Between 1945 and 1970"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d40",
        "question": "What did the Battle of Trafalgar (1805) represent?",
        "choices": [
            "The defeat of the British fleet",
            "The defeat of Napoleon Bonaparte's fleet",
            "The defeat of Major-General Sir Isaac Brock's fleet",
            "The defeat of the American fleet"
        ],
        "explanation": "After the defeat of Napoleon Bonaparte’s fleet in the Battle of Trafalgar (1805), the Royal Navy ruled the waves. The British Empire, which included Canada, fought to resist Bonaparte’s bid to dominate Europe.",
        "answer": "The defeat of Napoleon Bonaparte's fleet"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d34",
        "question": "During the Second World War, what was the ratio of Canadians in the Allied forces on D-Day?",
        "choices": [
            "1 in 10",
            "1 in 5",
            "1 in 3",
            "1 in 2"
        ],
        "explanation": "Approximately one in ten allied soldiers on D-Day was Canadian. The Canadian Army liberated the Netherlands in 1944–45 and helped force the German surrender of May 8, 1945, bringing to an end six years of war in Europe.",
        "answer": "1 in 10"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3a",
        "question": "When did the Fathers of Confederation form the Dominion of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "1600",
            "1999",
            "1790"
        ],
        "explanation": "From 1864 to 1867, representatives of Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and the Province of Canada, with British support, worked together to establish a new country. These men are known as the Fathers of Confederation.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d35",
        "question": "With whose expedition did European exploration begin in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Jacques Cartier",
            "John Cabot",
            "Pierre de Monts",
            "Samuel de Champlain"
        ],
        "explanation": "European exploration began in earnest in 1497 with the expedition of John Cabot, who was the first to draw a map of Canada’s East Coast.",
        "answer": "John Cabot"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d33",
        "question": "Which province was once known as the \"breadbasket of the world\" and, the \"wheat province\"?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Ontario"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatchewan, once known as the “breadbasket of the world” and the “wheat province,” has 40% of the arable land in Canada and is the country’s largest producer of grains and oilseeds.",
        "answer": "Saskatchewan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d30",
        "question": "Where is the highest mountain in Canada located?",
        "choices": [
            "Alberta",
            "Northwest Territories",
            "British Columbia",
            "Yukon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Mount Logan, located in the Yukon, is the highest mountain in Canada. It is named in honour of Sir William Logan, a world-famous geologist, born in Montreal in 1798 to Scottish immigrant parents.",
        "answer": "Yukon"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d31",
        "question": "What does the Canadian flag look like?",
        "choices": [
            "Red-white-red stripes with a red maple leaf in the center",
            "Red-white-red stripes with a red lily flower in the center",
            "Red maple leaf on a white background",
            "Red-white-red stripes with the Queen emblem in the center"
        ],
        "explanation": "A new Canadian flag was raised for the first time in 1965. The red-white-red pattern comes from the flag of the Royal Military College, Kingston, founded in 1876.",
        "answer": "Red-white-red stripes with a red maple leaf in the center"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d32",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what does MPP stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Members of the Politician Parliament",
            "Municipal and Provincial Parliament",
            "Members of the Provincial Parliament",
            "Major Politic Party"
        ],
        "explanation": "The members of the legislature are called members of the Legislative Assembly (MLAs), members of the National Assembly (MNAs), members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs) or members of the House of Assembly (MHAs), depending on the province or territory.",
        "answer": "Members of the Provincial Parliament"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d43",
        "question": "Which oceans line Canada’s frontiers?",
        "choices": [
            "Pacific Ocean and Arctic Ocean",
            "Atlantic Ocean and Pacific Ocean",
            "Pacific Ocean, Atlantic Ocean and Southern Ocean",
            "Pacific Ocean, Atlantic Ocean and Arctic Ocean"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is the second largest country on earth—10 million square kilometres. Three oceans line Canada’s frontiers: the Pacific Ocean in the west, the Atlantic Ocean in the east, and the Arctic Ocean to the north.",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean, Atlantic Ocean and Arctic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3d",
        "question": "In Canada, what does the Crown symbolize?",
        "choices": [
            "The Queen",
            "The government, including Parliament, the legislatures, the courts, police services and the Canadian Forces",
            "The RCMP",
            "The government"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Crown is a symbol of government, including Parliament, the legislatures, the courts, police services and the Canadian Forces.",
        "answer": "The government, including Parliament, the legislatures, the courts, police services and the Canadian Forces"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d41",
        "question": "What are Quebecers?",
        "choices": [
            "The French-speaking Aboriginals",
            "The people of Quebec",
            "The Acadians",
            "The francophones"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebecers are the people of Quebec, the vast majority French-speaking. Most are descendants of 8,500 French settlers from the 1600s and 1700s and maintain a unique identity, culture and language.",
        "answer": "The people of Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3c",
        "question": "When did the Montreal Stock Exchange open?",
        "choices": [
            "1887",
            "1832",
            "1932",
            "1905"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first financial institutions opened in the late 18th and early 19th centuries. The Montreal Stock Exchange opened in 1832.",
        "answer": "1832"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d39",
        "question": "Who invented the telephone?",
        "choices": [
            "Alexander Graham Shaw",
            "Alexander Graham Telus",
            "Alexander Graham Bell",
            "Alexander Graham Rogers"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alexander Graham Bell — hit on the idea of the telephone at his summer house in Canada.",
        "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3f",
        "question": "Who was John Buchan?",
        "choices": [
            "A victorious Canadian army General",
            "A famous Canadian general",
            "One of the Fathers of Confederation",
            "A popular Governor General of Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "John Buchan, the 1st Baron Tweedsmuir, was a popular Governor General of Canada (1935–40). Immigrant groups, he said, “should retain their individuality and each make its contribution to the national character.”.",
        "answer": "A popular Governor General of Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d36",
        "question": "Who were the Group of Seven?",
        "choices": [
            "Seven Canadian greatest war heroes",
            "Seven Canadian visual art artists who developed a certain style of painting",
            "The Father of the Confederation",
            "The Seven Canadian best hockey players"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the visual arts, Canada is historically perhaps best known for the Group of Seven, founded in 1920, who developed a style of painting to capture the rugged wilderness landscapes.",
        "answer": "Seven Canadian visual art artists who developed a certain style of painting"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d3b",
        "question": "Who composed the poem \"In Flanders Fields\" that is often recited on Remembrance Day?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Arthur Currie",
            "Sir Sam Steele",
            "Lt. Col. John McCrae",
            "The Duke of Wellington"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian medical officer Lieutenant Colonel John McCrae composed the poem “In Flanders Fields” in 1915; it is often recited on Remembrance Day.",
        "answer": "Lt. Col. John McCrae"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d44",
        "question": "Who battled with the French settlements for a century?",
        "choices": [
            "A confederation of three (later four) First Nations",
            "A confederation of five (later six) First Nations",
            "The English",
            "A confederation of four (later five) First Nations"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1604, the first European settlement north of Florida was established by French explorers Pierre de Monts and Samuel de Champlain, first on St. Croix Island (in present-day Maine), then at Port-Royal, in Acadia (present-day Nova Scotia). In 1608 Champlain built a fortress at what is now Québec City.The colonists struggled against a harsh climate. Champlain allied the colony with the Algonquin, Montagnais and Huron, historic enemies of the Iroquois, a confederation of five (later six) First Nations who battled with the French settlements for a century. The French and the Iroquois made peace in 1701.",
        "answer": "A confederation of five (later six) First Nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8cef",
        "question": "Which province has long been known for its fisheries, coastal fishing villages and distinct culture?",
        "choices": [
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "British Columbia",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Newfoundland and Labrador is the oldest colony of the British Empire and a strategic prize in Canada’s early history, the province has long been known for its fisheries, coastal fishing villages and distinct culture.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d46",
        "question": "What is the capital of the Yukon?",
        "choices": [
            "Whitehorse",
            "Iqaluit",
            "Yellowknife",
            "Edmonton"
        ],
        "explanation": "Whitehorse is the capital of the Yukon.",
        "answer": "Whitehorse"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d47",
        "question": "What are the main goods produced in British Columbia?",
        "choices": [
            "Auto industry products",
            "Farming products",
            "Forestry products",
            "Fishing products"
        ],
        "explanation": "About one-half of all the goods produced in B.C. are forestry products, including lumber, newsprint, and pulp and paper products—the most valuable forestry industry in Canada. B.C. is also known for mining, fishing, and the fruit orchards and wine industry of the Okanagan Valley.",
        "answer": "Forestry products"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d50",
        "question": "Who are the Métis?",
        "choices": [
            "First Nations",
            "Inuit",
            "Acadians",
            "A distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Métis are a distinct people of mixed  Aboriginal and European ancestry, the majority of whom live in the Prairie provinces. They come from both French and English-speaking backgrounds and speak their own dialect, Michif.",
        "answer": "A distinct people of mixed Aboriginal and European ancestry"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d58",
        "question": "What is the role of opposition parties?",
        "choices": [
            "To write bills",
            "To approve the leader party's bills",
            "To peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals",
            "To help the Prime Minister"
        ],
        "explanation": "The role of opposition parties is to peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals.",
        "answer": "To peacefully oppose or try to improve government proposals"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d54",
        "question": "At the end of the Second World War, Canada’s navy was:",
        "choices": [
            "Canada had no navy at that time",
            "The third largest in the world",
            "The largest in the world",
            "The second largest in the world"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Canadian Navy (RCN) saw its finest hour in the Battle of the Atlantic, protecting convoys of merchant ships against German submarines. At the end of the Second World War, Canada had the third-largest navy in the world.",
        "answer": "The third largest in the world"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4f",
        "question": "For a bill to become a law, how many readings must it go through?",
        "choices": [
            "None",
            "Two",
            "One",
            "Three"
        ],
        "explanation": "STEP 1 First Reading – The bill is considered read for the first time and is printed.STEP 2 Second Reading – Members debate the bill’s principle.STEP 3 Committee Stage – Committee members study the bill clause by clause.STEP 4 Report Stage – Members can make other amendments.STEP 5 Third Reading – Members debate and vote on the bill.STEP 6 Senate – The bill follows a similar process in the Senate.STEP 7 Royal Assent – The bill receives royal assent after being passed by both Houses.",
        "answer": "Three"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4b",
        "question": "Where was the new British colony for freed slaves?",
        "choices": [
            "Sierra Leone (West Africa)",
            "Nairobi (East Africa)",
            "Cape Town (South Africa)",
            "Abidjan (West Africa)"
        ],
        "explanation": "About 3,000 black Loyalists, freedmen and slaves came north seeking a better life. In turn, in 1792, some black Nova Scotians, who were given poor land, moved on to establish Freetown, Sierra Leone (West Africa), a new British colony for freed slaves.",
        "answer": "Sierra Leone (West Africa)"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4c",
        "question": "Since the 1800s, where were the majority of Canadians born?",
        "choices": [
            "England",
            "China",
            "Canada",
            "India"
        ],
        "explanation": "The majority of Canadians were born in this country and this has been true since the 1800s. However, Canada is often referred to as a land of immigrants because, over the past 200 years, millions of newcomers have helped to build and defend our way of life.",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d59",
        "question": "Which of the following is Canada’s main financial centre and largest city?",
        "choices": [
            "Montreal",
            "Vancouver",
            "Ottawa",
            "Toronto"
        ],
        "explanation": "Toronto is the largest city in Canada and the country’s main financial centre. Many people work in the service or manufacturing industries, which produce a large percentage of Canada’s exports.",
        "answer": "Toronto"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d49",
        "question": "In Parliament and throughout the administration, the standing of French and English is not equal.",
        "choices": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "explanation": "French and English have equal status in Parliament and throughout the government of Canada.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d48",
        "question": "What is a proposal for a new law called?",
        "choices": [
            "A new law",
            "A bill",
            "A law suggestion",
            "A law proposal"
        ],
        "explanation": "Both the House of Commons and the Senate consider and review bills (proposals for new laws).",
        "answer": "A bill"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d53",
        "question": "Which of the following provinces/territories borders the Pacific Ocean?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "British Columbia",
            "Alberta",
            "Northwest Territories"
        ],
        "explanation": "British Columbia borders the Pacific Ocean.",
        "answer": "British Columbia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d56",
        "question": "What is a \"responsible government\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The government is responsible for everything in the country",
            "The ministers of the Crown must have the support of a majority of the elected representatives in order to govern",
            "The government does not have to resign if it loses a confidence vote in the assembly",
            "The government is responsible for making laws"
        ],
        "explanation": "Responsible government refers to a government that is responsible to the people. It takes the form of a Cabinet that depends on the support of an elected assembly, rather than a monarch or their representatives.",
        "answer": "The government is responsible for everything in the country"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d52",
        "question": "When was Ottawa chosen as the capital of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1957",
            "1757",
            "1857",
            "1657"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ottawa, located on the Ottawa River, was chosen as the capital in 1857 by Queen Victoria, the great-great-grandmother of Queen Elizabeth II.",
        "answer": "1857"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4a",
        "question": "Why do Canadians enjoy one of the world’s highest standards of living?",
        "choices": [
            "By working hard and by trading with other nations",
            "Thanks to the Americans",
            "Thanks to the NAFTA agreement",
            "By working hard and by being a NATO member"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians enjoy one of the world’s highest standards of living—maintained by the hard work of Canadians and by trade with other nations, in particular the United States.",
        "answer": "By working hard and by trading with other nations"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4d",
        "question": "When were most Canadian female citizens, aged 21 and over, granted the right to vote in federal elections?",
        "choices": [
            "1889",
            "1945",
            "1918",
            "1921"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1918, most Canadian female citizens aged 21 and over were granted the right to vote in federal elections. In 1921 Agnes Macphail, a farmer and teacher, became the first woman MP.",
        "answer": "1918"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d55",
        "question": "Who granted the Hudson’s Bay Company exclusive trading rights?",
        "choices": [
            "King George II",
            "King Charles I of England",
            "King Charles II of England",
            "King James"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1670, King Charles II of England granted the Hudson’s Bay Company exclusive trading rights over the watershed draining into Hudson Bay.",
        "answer": "King Charles II of England"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d51",
        "question": "Who suggested the term, \"Dominion of Canada\" in 1864?",
        "choices": [
            "Joseph Howe",
            "Sir Leonard Tilley",
            "La Fontaine",
            "Robert Baldwin"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Leonard Tilley, an elected official and Father of Confederation from New Brunswick, suggested the term Dominion of Canada in 1864. He was inspired by Psalm 72 in the Bible which refers to “dominion from sea to sea and from the river to the ends of the earth.” This phrase embodied the vision of building a powerful, united, wealthy and free country that spanned a continent.",
        "answer": "Sir Leonard Tilley"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d57",
        "question": "Which province is Canada’s largest producer of grains and oilseeds?",
        "choices": [
            "Saskatchewan",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Ontario",
            "Manitoba"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatchewan, once known as the “breadbasket of the world” and the “wheat province,” has 40% of the arable land in Canada and is the country’s largest producer of grains and oilseeds.",
        "answer": "Saskatchewan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d4e",
        "question": "What are the Canadian Rangers?",
        "choices": [
            "The first pioneers of the North",
            "The part of the Canadian Forces Reserves overlooking Canada's vast North",
            "The Northern Divison of the RCMP",
            "The Canadian Northern mountain range"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada’s vast North brings security and sovereignty challenges. The Canadian Rangers, part of the Canadian Forces Reserves (militia), play a key role. Drawing on indigenous knowledge and experience, the Rangers travel by snowmobile in the winter and all-terrain vehicles in the summer from Resolute to the Magnetic North Pole, and keep the flag flying in Canada’s Arctic.",
        "answer": "The part of the Canadian Forces Reserves overlooking Canada's vast North"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5a",
        "question": "Who led thousands of Loyalist Mohawk Indians into Canada in 1776?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Robert Baldwin",
            "Joseph Brant",
            "Joseph Howe"
        ],
        "explanation": "Joseph Brant led thousands of Loyalist Mohawk Indians into Canada. The Loyalists came from Dutch, German, British, Scandinavian, Aboriginal and other origins and from Presbyterian, Anglican, Baptist, Methodist, Jewish, Quaker and Catholic religious backgrounds.",
        "answer": "Joseph Brant"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5b",
        "question": "In Canada, where do more than half of the people live?",
        "choices": [
            "Central Canada",
            "Prairie provinces",
            "Atlantic provinces",
            "West Coast"
        ],
        "explanation": "More than half the people in Canada live in cities and towns near the Great Lakes and the St. Lawrence River in southern Quebec and Ontario, known as Central Canada and the industrial and manufacturing heartland. Southern Ontario and Quebec have cold winters and warm humid summers. Together, Ontario and Quebec produce more than three-quarters of all Canadian manufactured goods.",
        "answer": "Central Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5c",
        "question": "Where is the world-famous Lake Louise?",
        "choices": [
            "Interior Mountains",
            "Rocky Mountains",
            "Appalachian Mountains",
            "Selkirk Mountains"
        ],
        "explanation": "Alberta is the most populous Prairie province. The province, and the world-famous Lake Louise in the Rocky Mountains, were both named after Princess Louise Caroline Alberta, fourth daughter of Queen Victoria.",
        "answer": "Rocky Mountains"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5d",
        "question": "Who chooses the ministers of the Crown?",
        "choices": [
            "The Queen",
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The Senators",
            "The Governor General"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Prime Minister chooses the ministers of the Crown, most of them from among members of the House of Commons.",
        "answer": "The Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5e",
        "question": "When was the R.C.M.P created?",
        "choices": [
            "1864",
            "1873",
            "1869",
            "1892"
        ],
        "explanation": "After the first Métis uprising, Prime Minister Macdonald established the North West Mounted Police (NWMP) in 1873 to pacify the West and assist in negotiations with the Indians.",
        "answer": "1873"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d65",
        "question": "What is the \"Dominion of Canada\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Alliance formed between the English and the French",
            "The English-speaking part of Canada",
            "The French-speaking part of Canada",
            "The name of the new country formed in 1867 known today as Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The old Province of Canada was split into two new provinces: Ontario and Quebec, which, together with New Brunswick and Nova Scotia, formed the new country called the Dominion of Canada.",
        "answer": "The name of the new country formed in 1867 known today as Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d66",
        "question": "Which of the following is Canada’s second largest city?",
        "choices": [
            "Ottawa",
            "Toronto",
            "Vancouver",
            "Montreal"
        ],
        "explanation": "Montreal, Canada’s second largest city and the second largest mainly French-speaking city in the world after Paris, is famous for its cultural diversity.",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d64",
        "question": "Who assigned Canada’s national colours (white and red) in 1921?",
        "choices": [
            "King George II",
            "King James",
            "Queen Victoria",
            "King George V"
        ],
        "explanation": "King George V assigned Canada’s national colours (white and red) in 1921, the colours of our national flag today.",
        "answer": "King George V"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6c",
        "question": "What is the opposition party with the most members of the House of Commons called?",
        "choices": [
            "The Loyal Great Opposition",
            "The Outside Opposition or Her Majesty's Loyal Opposition",
            "the Official Opposition or Her Majesty's Loyal Opposition",
            "The Side Opposition"
        ],
        "explanation": "The opposition party with the most members of the House of Commons is the Official Opposition or Her Majesty’s Loyal Opposition.",
        "answer": "the Official Opposition or Her Majesty's Loyal Opposition"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6b",
        "question": "When was the first European exploration in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1788",
            "1690",
            "1497",
            "1999"
        ],
        "explanation": "European exploration began in earnest in 1497 with the expedition of John Cabot, who was the first to draw a map of Canada’s East Coast.",
        "answer": "1497"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d63",
        "question": "For how many years is the Governor General usually appointed?",
        "choices": [
            "Five",
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Ten"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sovereign is represented in Canada by the Governor General, who is appointed by the Sovereign on the advice of the Prime Minister, usually for five years.",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d60",
        "question": "For what is the Prime Minister of Canada responsible?",
        "choices": [
            "The operations of the government",
            "Education, health, and natural resources",
            "Matters of national concern",
            "The operations and policy of the government"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the federal government, the Prime Minister selects the Cabinet ministers and is responsible for the operations and policy of the government.",
        "answer": "The operations and policy of the government"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d69",
        "question": "What was the name of the war that began when several liberated countries of Eastern Europe became part of a Communist bloc controlled by the Soviet Union?",
        "choices": [
            "The Union War",
            "The Soviet War",
            "The Cold War",
            "The Eastern War"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Cold War began when several liberated countries of eastern Europe became part of a Communist bloc controlled by the Soviet Union under the dictator Josef Stalin.",
        "answer": "The Cold War"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6a",
        "question": "Who was Canada’s greatest soldier during the First World War?",
        "choices": [
            "Colonel Sir Joseph Howe",
            "General Sir Arthur Currie",
            "Lt. Col. John McCrae",
            "General Sir Alexander Macdonald"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1918, under the command of General Sir Arthur Currie, Canada’s greatest soldier, the Canadian Corps advanced alongside the French and British Empire troops in the last hundred days.",
        "answer": "General Sir Arthur Currie"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6d",
        "question": "Which Act granted to the Canadas, for the first time, legislative assemblies elected by the people?",
        "choices": [
            "The Legislative Act",
            "The Constitutional Act",
            "The Confederation Act",
            "The Freedom Act"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 divided the Province of Quebec into Upper Canada (later Ontario), which was mainly Loyalist, Protestant and English-speaking, and Lower Canada (later Quebec), heavily Catholic and French-speaking. The Act also granted to the Canadas, for the first time, legislative assemblies elected by the people.",
        "answer": "The Constitutional Act"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d68",
        "question": "When was slavery abolished?",
        "choices": [
            "1912",
            "1800",
            "1899",
            "1833"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1807, the British Parliament prohibited the buying and selling of slaves, and in 1833 abolished slavery throughout the Empire.",
        "answer": "1833"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d67",
        "question": "What is the name of the parties that are not in power?",
        "choices": [
            "Outside parties",
            "Opposition parties",
            "Powerless parties",
            "Side parties"
        ],
        "explanation": "The other parties that are not in power are known as opposition parties. The opposition party with the most members of the House of Commons is the Official Opposition or Her/His Majesty’s Loyal Opposition.",
        "answer": "Opposition parties"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d62",
        "question": "What were the Atlantic colonies and the two Canadas known collectively as in 1791?",
        "choices": [
            "Upper Canada",
            "Lower Canada",
            "Ontario",
            "British North America"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Atlantic colonies and the two Canadas were known collectively as British North America.",
        "answer": "British North America"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d61",
        "question": "What was driving the vast fur trade economy?",
        "choices": [
            "The demand for beaver pelts in Asia",
            "The demand for beaver pelts in Europe",
            "The demand for beaver pelts in the Aboriginal communities",
            "The needs for beaver pelts in the settlers"
        ],
        "explanation": "The French and Aboriginal people collaborated in the vast fur-trade economy, driven by the demand for beaver pelts in Europe.",
        "answer": "The demand for beaver pelts in Europe"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d5f",
        "question": "Who recognized in 2006 that the Quebecois form a nation within a united Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The House of Commons",
            "The Senate",
            "The Cabinet Ministers"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons recognized in 2006 that the Quebecois form a nation within a united Canada.",
        "answer": "The House of Commons"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d70",
        "question": "Which province has its own time zone?",
        "choices": [
            "Yukon",
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "Nunavut"
        ],
        "explanation": "Newfoundland and Labrador is the most easterly point in North America and has its own time zone.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6f",
        "question": "What is the significance of \"l’Anse aux Meadows\"?",
        "choices": [
            "It is a World Heritage site where can be found the remains of the Battle of Trafalgar",
            "It is a World Heritage site where can be found the remains of Jacques Cartier",
            "It is a World Heritage site where can be found the remains of the first European town built by the early settlers",
            "It is a World Heritage site where can be found the remains of the Vikings from Iceland who reached Labrador and the island of Newfoundland 1,000 years ago"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Vikings from Iceland who colonized Greenland 1,000 years ago also reached Labrador and the island of Newfoundland. The remains of their settlement, l’Anse aux Meadows, are a World Heritage site.",
        "answer": "It is a World Heritage site where can be found the remains of the Vikings from Iceland who reached Labrador and the island of Newfoundland 1,000 years ago"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d6e",
        "question": "What is the most easterly point in North America?",
        "choices": [
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Newfoundland and Labrador is the most easterly point in North America and has its own time zone. In addition to its natural beauty, the province has a unique heritage linked to the sea.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d71",
        "question": "What is a voter information card?",
        "choices": [
            "A letter explaining how to vote",
            "A list with all the election candidates",
            "A card that confirms that your name is on the voters' list and states when and where you vote",
            "A card that you use to register for voting"
        ],
        "explanation": "Electors whose information is in the National Register of Electors will receive a voter information card. This confirms that your name is on the voters’ list and states when and where you vote.",
        "answer": "A card that confirms that your name is on the voters' list and states when and where you vote"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d72",
        "question": "In which province does the majority of Francophones live?",
        "choices": [
            "Alberta",
            "Manitoba",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "The majority of Francophones live in the province of Quebec. One million Francophones live in Ontario, New Brunswick and Manitoba, with a smaller presence in other provinces.",
        "answer": "Quebec"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d73",
        "question": "Which four provinces formed the new country called the Dominion of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick and British Columbia",
            "Manitoba, Quebec, New Brunswick and Nova Scotia",
            "Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick and Nova Scotia",
            "Ontario, Quebec, Manitoba and Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ontario and Quebec, which, together with New Brunswick and Nova Scotia, formed the new country called the Dominion of Canada.",
        "answer": "Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick and Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d74",
        "question": "What is the population of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "About 34 million people",
            "About 68 million people",
            "About 42 million people",
            "About 18 million people"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has a population of about 34 million people. While the majority live in cities, Canadians also live in small towns, rural areas and everywhere in between.",
        "answer": "About 34 million people"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d75",
        "question": "What are leaders like Jean Talon, Bishop Laval, and Count Frontenac famous for?",
        "choices": [
            "They built a British Empire in North America that reached from Hudson Bay to the Gulf of Mexico",
            "They defeated the French armies during the War between France and England",
            "They built a French Empire in North America that reached from Hudson Bay to the Gulf of Mexico",
            "They defeated the British armies during the War between France and England"
        ],
        "explanation": "Outstanding leaders like Jean Talon, Bishop Laval, and Count Frontenac built a French Empire in North America that reached from Hudson Bay to the Gulf of Mexico.",
        "answer": "They built a French Empire in North America that reached from Hudson Bay to the Gulf of Mexico"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d76",
        "question": "What is the responsibility of the Cabinet Ministers?",
        "choices": [
            "They are responsible for running each province of Canada",
            "They are responsible for running the federal government departments",
            "They are responsible for running the Senate",
            "They are responsible for running the House of Commons"
        ],
        "explanation": "Cabinet ministers are responsible for running the federal government departments. The Prime Minister and the Cabinet ministers are called the Cabinet and they make important decisions about how the country is governed.",
        "answer": "They are responsible for running the federal government departments"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d79",
        "question": "Which of the following provinces/territories borders with the Atlantic Ocean?",
        "choices": [
            "Alberta",
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "British Columbia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Newfoundland and Labrador borders with the Atlantic Ocean.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d77",
        "question": "When is the Royal Anthem of Canada sung?",
        "choices": [
            "On any occasions when Canadians wish to honour the Queen or King",
            "Only on Canada Day",
            "Never",
            "Only when the Queen visits Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Royal Anthem of Canada, “God Save the Queen (or King),” can be played or sung on any occasion when Canadians wish to honour the Sovereign.",
        "answer": "On any occasions when Canadians wish to honour the Queen or King"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7b",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Alberta?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba",
            "British Columbia",
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Northwest Territories"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manitoba does not border Alberta.",
        "answer": "Manitoba"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7a",
        "question": "In what area do Canadians mostly work nowadays?",
        "choices": [
            "Natural resources industries",
            "Service Industries",
            "Manufacturing industries",
            "Farming industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Service industries provide thousands of different jobs in areas like transportation, education, health care, construction, banking, communications, retail services, tourism and government.",
        "answer": "Service Industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7c",
        "question": "When were the responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments defined?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "1767",
            "1749",
            "1849"
        ],
        "explanation": "The responsibilities of the federal and provincial governments were defined in 1867 in the British North America Act, now known as the Constitution Act, 1867.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d78",
        "question": "Which province is the only official bilingual province?",
        "choices": [
            "New Brunswick",
            "Alberta",
            "Quebec",
            "Manitoba"
        ],
        "explanation": "While the majority of Francophones live in the province of Quebec, one million Francophones live in Ontario, New Brunswick and Manitoba, with a smaller presence in other provinces. New Brunswick is the only officially bilingual province.",
        "answer": "New Brunswick"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d81",
        "question": "Who invented the first cardiac pacemaker?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Sandford Fleming",
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Dr. Wilder Penfield",
            "Dr. John A. Hopps"
        ],
        "explanation": "Dr. John A. Hopps — invented the first cardiac pacemaker, used today to save the lives of people with heart disorders.",
        "answer": "Dr. John A. Hopps"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7e",
        "question": "When do Canadians celebrate Vimy Day?",
        "choices": [
            "February 9th",
            "April 9th",
            "March 9th",
            "April 10th"
        ],
        "explanation": "April 9th is celebrated as Vimy Day.",
        "answer": "April 9th"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d80",
        "question": "Where do one-third of Canadians live?",
        "choices": [
            "British Colombia",
            "Quebec",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Ontario"
        ],
        "explanation": "At more than 12 million, the people of Ontario make up more than one-third of Canadians. The large and culturally diverse population, natural resources and strategic location contribute to a vital economy.",
        "answer": "Ontario"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7f",
        "question": "In what year did Canada become a country?",
        "choices": [
            "1759",
            "1840",
            "1982",
            "1867"
        ],
        "explanation": "​​​​​​​​A federation of colonies in British North America - New Brunswick, Nova Scotia, Quebec, and Ontario - joined together to become the Dominion of Canada on July 1, 1867.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d7d",
        "question": "What is Canada’s national winter sport?",
        "choices": [
            "Ice fishing",
            "Skiing",
            "Ice skating",
            "Ice Hockey"
        ],
        "explanation": "Many major league sports boast Canadian talent and in the national sport of ice hockey, Canadian teams have dominated the world.",
        "answer": "Ice Hockey"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d82",
        "question": "Regarding the European - Aboriginal relationship, which of the following statements is false?",
        "choices": [
            "Large numbers of Aboriginals died of European diseases to which they lacked immunity",
            "European traders, missionaries, soldiers and colonists killed most of the native population in Canada",
            "Aboriginals and Europeans formed strong economic, religious and military bonds in the first 200 years of coexistence which laid the foundations of Canada",
            "The arrival of European traders, missionaries, soldiers and colonists changed the native way of life forever"
        ],
        "explanation": "The arrival of European traders, missionaries, soldiers and colonists changed the native way of life forever. Large numbers of Aboriginals died of European diseases to which they lacked immunity. However, Aboriginals and Europeans formed strong economic, religious and military bonds in the first 200 years of coexistence which laid the foundations of Canada.",
        "answer": "European traders, missionaries, soldiers and colonists killed most of the native population in Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8d",
        "question": "When was the current flag of Canada raised for the first time?",
        "choices": [
            "1982",
            "1892",
            "1949",
            "1965"
        ],
        "explanation": "A new Canadian flag was raised for the first time in 1965. The red-white-red pattern comes from the flag of the Royal Military College, Kingston, founded in 1876.",
        "answer": "1965"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d92",
        "question": "When was the province of Canada formed by combining upper and lower Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1840",
            "1500",
            "1800s",
            "1900"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1840, Upper and Lower Canada were united as the Province of Canada. Reformers such as Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine and Robert Baldwin, in parallel with Joseph Howe in Nova Scotia, worked with British governors toward responsible government.",
        "answer": "1840"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d96",
        "question": "In Canadian politics, what does MHA stand for?",
        "choices": [
            "Members of the High Assembly",
            "Municipal House Assembly",
            "Members of the House of Assembly",
            "Members of the Honourable Assembly"
        ],
        "explanation": "The members of the legislature are called members of the Legislative Assembly (MLAs), members of the National Assembly (MNAs), members of the Provincial Parliament (MPPs) or members of the House of Assembly (MHAs), depending on the province or territory.",
        "answer": "Members of the House of Assembly"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8e",
        "question": "Which provinces have some of the most fertile farmlands in the world?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba, Ontario and Quebec",
            "British Columbia, Alberta and the Yukon",
            "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta",
            "Ontario, Quebec and New Brunswick"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta are the Prairie Provinces, rich in energy resources and some of the most fertile farmland in the world. The region is mostly dry, with cold winters and hot summers.",
        "answer": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d97",
        "question": "Which of the following is the only part of the original Parliament building that still remains?",
        "choices": [
            "The Library",
            "The Centre Block",
            "The Peace Tower",
            "The Memorial Chamber"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Centre Block was destroyed by an accidental fire in 1916 and rebuilt in 1922. The Library is the only part of the original building remaining.",
        "answer": "The Library"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d95",
        "question": "How many provinces and territories are there in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Ten provinces and four territories",
            "Nine provinces and three territories",
            "Ten provinces and three territories",
            "Eight provinces and five territories"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has ten provinces and three territories. Each province and territory has its own capital city. You should know the capital of your province or territory as well as that of Canada.",
        "answer": "Ten provinces and three territories"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d99",
        "question": "Who selects the Cabinet Ministers?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The people of Canada",
            "The Senators",
            "The Queen"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the federal government, the Prime Minister selects the Cabinet ministers and is responsible for the operations and policy of the government.",
        "answer": "The Prime Minister"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d88",
        "question": "What is the oldest colony of the British Empire?",
        "choices": [
            "Newfoundland and Labrador",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Prince Edward Island"
        ],
        "explanation": "Newfoundland and Labrador is the oldest colony of the British Empire and a strategic prize in Canada’s early history, the province has long been known for its fisheries, coastal fishing villages and distinct culture.",
        "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d2f",
        "question": "When did the name Canada began appearing on maps?",
        "choices": [
            "1780",
            "1998",
            "1550",
            "2001"
        ],
        "explanation": "Cartier heard two captured guides speak the Iroquoian word kanata, meaning “village.” By the 1550s, the name of Canada began appearing on maps.",
        "answer": "1550"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d94",
        "question": "What is the head of a province called?",
        "choices": [
            "The Chief President ",
            "The Lieutenant Governor",
            "The Premier",
            "The King"
        ],
        "explanation": "In each province, the Premier has a role similar to that of the Prime Minister in the federal government, just as the Lieutenant Governor has a role similar to that of the Governor General.",
        "answer": "The Premier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d83",
        "question": "Since when has Canada been a constitutional monarchy?",
        "choices": [
            "1867",
            "1667",
            "1767",
            "1849"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has been a constitutional monarchy in its own right since Confederation in 1867 during Queen Victoria’s reign.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d85",
        "question": "What is the capital of British Columbia?",
        "choices": [
            "Calgary",
            "Vancouver",
            "Victoria",
            "Edmonton"
        ],
        "explanation": "Victoria is the capital of British Columbia.",
        "answer": "Victoria"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d84",
        "question": "What is the capital of Quebec?",
        "choices": [
            "Chicoutimi",
            "Quebec City",
            "Saint-Jean",
            "Montreal"
        ],
        "explanation": "Quebec City is the capital of Quebec.",
        "answer": "Quebec City"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d91",
        "question": "What is the capital of Newfoundland and Labrador?",
        "choices": [
            "Fredericton",
            "Charlottetown",
            "Halifax",
            "St. John's"
        ],
        "explanation": "St. John’s is the capital of Newfoundland and Labrador.",
        "answer": "St. John's"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8f",
        "question": "How are members of Parliament chosen?",
        "choices": [
            "They are elected by landowners and police chiefs",
            "They are chosen by the provincial Premiers",
            "They are elected by voters in their local constituency",
            "They are appointed by the United Nations"
        ],
        "explanation": "The citizens in each electoral district elect one MP who sits in the House of Commons to represent them, as well as all Canadians.",
        "answer": "They are elected by voters in their local constituency"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d90",
        "question": "Name 3 fathers of Confederation",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache, Sir George-Etienne Cartier, and Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Joseph Brant, Joseph Howe, and James Macdonald",
            "La Fontaine, Robert Baldwin, and Joseph Howe",
            "Jospeh Howe, Robert La Fontaine, and Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache"
        ],
        "explanation": "Some reformers, including Sir Étienne-Paschal Taché and Sir George-Étienne Cartier, later became Fathers of Confederation, as did a former member of the voluntary government militia in Upper Canada, Sir John A. Macdonald.",
        "answer": "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache, Sir George-Etienne Cartier, and Sir John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d89",
        "question": "Who were the first Europeans to reach Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "English",
            "Vikings",
            "Irish",
            "French"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Vikings from Iceland who colonized Greenland 1,000 years ago also reached Labrador and the island of Newfoundland. The remains of their settlement, l’Anse aux Meadows, are a World Heritage site.",
        "answer": "Vikings"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d98",
        "question": "Aboriginal and Treaty rights are not in the Constitution",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "Aboriginal and treaty rights are in the Canadian Constitution. Territorial rights were first guaranteed through the Royal Proclamation of 1763 by King George III, and established the basis for negotiating treaties with the newcomers— treaties that were not always fully respected.",
        "answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8a",
        "question": "What does \"equality of men and women\" mean in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Men and women can both perform household related tasks",
            "Women should earn more money",
            "Men and women must both drive a vehicle",
            "Both Men and women are equal under the law"
        ],
        "explanation": "In Canada, men and women are equal under the law. Canada’s openness and generosity do not extend to barbaric cultural practices that tolerate spousal abuse.",
        "answer": "Both Men and women are equal under the law"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d86",
        "question": "Who was the first European to explore the St. Lawrence River?",
        "choices": [
            "Pierre de Monts",
            "John Cabot",
            "Samuel de Champlain",
            "Jacques Cartier"
        ],
        "explanation": "Jacques Cartier was the first European to explore the St. Lawrence River and to set eyes on present-day Québec City and Montreal.",
        "answer": "Jacques Cartier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d93",
        "question": "What was the view on immigration of John Buchan, a popular Governor General of Canada in the 1930s?",
        "choices": [
            "No diversity",
            "Complete cultural assimilation",
            "Unity in diversity",
            "No unity"
        ],
        "explanation": "John Buchan, the 1st Baron Tweedsmuir, was a popular Governor General of Canada (1935–40). Immigrant groups, he said, “should retain their individuality and each make its contribution to the national character.”.",
        "answer": "Unity in diversity"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9a",
        "question": "Which following countries are part of the G8?",
        "choices": [
            "United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Canada, China and Russia",
            "United States, the United Kingdom, Japan, Canada, Australia, Russia, France and China",
            "United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Japan, Canada, Russia, France and China",
            "United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Japan, Canada and Russia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Today, Canada has one of the ten largest economies in the world and is part of the G8 group of leading industrialized countries with the United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Japan and Russia.",
        "answer": "United States, Germany, the United Kingdom, Italy, France, Japan, Canada and Russia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8b",
        "question": "Which of the following is Canada’s largest and busiest port?",
        "choices": [
            "Vancouver",
            "Halifax",
            "St. John's",
            "Toronto"
        ],
        "explanation": "British Columbia is known for its majestic mountains and as Canada’s Pacific gateway. The Port of Vancouver, Canada’s largest and busiest, handles billions of dollars in goods traded around the world.",
        "answer": "Vancouver"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d87",
        "question": "The Prime Minister and the party in power run the government:",
        "choices": [
            "As long as they have the support or confidence of the majority of the MPs",
            "As long as they are in good health",
            "As long as they have the approval of the Queen",
            "As long as they have the support of the senators"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Prime Minister and the party in power run the government as long as they have the support or confidence of the majority of the MPs.",
        "answer": "As long as they have the support or confidence of the majority of the MPs"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9d",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border British Columbia?",
        "choices": [
            "Saskatchewan",
            "Alberta",
            "Northwest Territories",
            "Yukon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Saskatchewan does not border British Columbia.",
        "answer": "Saskatchewan"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9e",
        "question": "Which of the following does not border Ontario?",
        "choices": [
            "Hudson Bay",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Manitoba",
            "Quebec"
        ],
        "explanation": "Nova Scotia does not border Ontario.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9b",
        "question": "Which industries make products to sell in Canada and around the world?",
        "choices": [
            "Manufacturing industries",
            "Natural resources industries",
            "Trading Industries",
            "Service industries"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manufacturing industries make products to sell in Canada and around the world. Manufactured products include paper, high technology equipment, aerospace technology, automobiles, machinery, food, clothing and many other goods.",
        "answer": "Manufacturing industries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9c",
        "question": "When was the Bank of Canada created?",
        "choices": [
            "1939",
            "1934",
            "1942",
            "1945"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Bank of Canada, a central bank to manage the money supply and bring stability to the financial system, was created in 1934.",
        "answer": "1934"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da3",
        "question": "Who chose Ottawa as the capital of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Queen Anne",
            "Queen Elizabeth II",
            "Queen Elizabeth I",
            "Queen Victoria"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ottawa, located on the Ottawa River, was chosen as the capital in 1857 by Queen Victoria, the great-great-grandmother of Queen Elizabeth II.",
        "answer": "Queen Victoria"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da5",
        "question": "Who was the first to map Canada’s Atlantic shore?",
        "choices": [
            "Samuel de Champlain",
            "Jacques Cartier",
            "John Cabot",
            "Pierre de Monts"
        ],
        "explanation": "John Cabot, an Italian immigrant to England, was the first to map Canada’s Atlantic shore, setting foot on Newfoundland or Cape Breton Island in 1497 and claiming the New Founde Land for England.",
        "answer": "John Cabot"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d9f",
        "question": "What did Great Britain rename the French colony of the 1700s?",
        "choices": [
            "The \"Province of Quebec\"",
            "Quebec City",
            "Ontario",
            "Acadia"
        ],
        "explanation": "Following the war, Great Britain renamed the colony the “Province of Quebec.” The French-speaking Catholic people, known as habitants or Canadiens, strove to preserve their way of life in the English-speaking, Protestant-ruled British Empire.",
        "answer": "The \"Province of Quebec\""
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da8",
        "question": "Why is the British North America Act important in Canadian history?",
        "choices": [
            "The Act granted to the Canadas, for the first time, legislative assemblies",
            "The Act officially made Canada a self-governing Dominion",
            "The Act restored British criminal laws",
            "The Act granted Canada complete independence from England"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Dominion of Canada was officially born on July 1, 1867. Until 1982, July 1 was celebrated as “Dominion Day” to commemorate the day that Canada became a self-governing Dominion. Today it is officially known as Canada Day.",
        "answer": "The Act officially made Canada a self-governing Dominion"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da4",
        "question": "How did the native people live when the first European arrive in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Off the land, by hunting and gathering",
            "Off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops",
            "By trading fur with other native in North America",
            "Off the land, by raising crops"
        ],
        "explanation": "The native people lived off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops. The Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region, like the Iroquois, were farmers and hunters. The Cree and Dene of the Northwest were hunter-gatherers. The Sioux were nomadic, following the bison (buffalo) herd. The Inuit lived off Arctic wildlife. West Coast natives preserved fish by drying and smoking.",
        "answer": "Off the land, some by hunting and gathering, others by raising crops"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da2",
        "question": "Who has the right to insist that you tell them how you voted?",
        "choices": [
            "Your union representatives",
            "Your employer",
            "Your family members",
            "Nobody"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadian law secures the right to a secret ballot. This means that no one can watch you vote and no one should look at how you voted.",
        "answer": "Nobody"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da0",
        "question": "Who had the reputation of being the \"shock troops of the British Empire\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Canadian troops",
            "The Caribbean troops",
            "The French troops",
            "The British troops"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Canadian Corps captured Vimy Ridge in April 1917, with 10,000 killed or wounded, securing the Canadians’ reputation for valour as the “shock troops of the British Empire.”",
        "answer": "The Canadian troops"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da6",
        "question": "Who became the first leader of a responsible government in the Canadas?",
        "choices": [
            "Joseph Howe",
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "La Fontaine",
            "Robert Baldwin"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine, a champion of French language rights, became the first head of a responsible government (similar to a prime minister) in Canada in 1849.",
        "answer": "La Fontaine"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da7",
        "question": "Which of the following symbolizes the close ties and common interests of Canada and the U.S.A.?",
        "choices": [
            "The Peace Arch",
            "The Peace Tower",
            "The Stanley Cup",
            "The Statue of Liberty"
        ],
        "explanation": "At Blaine in the State of Washington, the Peace Arch, inscribed with the words “children of a common mother” and “brethren dwelling together in unity,” symbolizes our close ties and common interests.",
        "answer": "The Peace Arch"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da1",
        "question": "Which of the following provinces/territories does not border Hudson Bay?",
        "choices": [
            "Northwest Territories",
            "Ontario",
            "Manitoba",
            "Nunavut"
        ],
        "explanation": "Northwest Territories does not border Hudson Bay.",
        "answer": "Northwest Territories"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8dab",
        "question": "What is the capital of Nunavut?",
        "choices": [
            "Iqaluit",
            "Yellowknife",
            "Edmonton",
            "Inuit"
        ],
        "explanation": "Iqaluit is the capital of Nunavut.",
        "answer": "Iqaluit"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8dac",
        "question": "Where was the first representative assembly elected?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "British Columbia",
            "Ontario",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first representative assembly was elected in Halifax, Nova Scotia, in 1758. Prince Edward Island followed in 1773, New Brunswick in 1785.",
        "answer": "Nova Scotia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8daf",
        "question": "What is the NAFTA agreement?",
        "choices": [
            "Free trade between Canada, the United States and Mexico",
            "Free trade between Canada, the United States and the United Kingdom",
            "Free trade between Canada, the Europe and Mexico",
            "Free trade between Canada, the United States and Europe"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1988, Canada enacted free trade with the United States. Mexico became a partner in 1994 in the broader North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), with over 444 million people and over $1 trillion in merchandise trade in 2008.",
        "answer": "Free trade between Canada, the United States and Mexico"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db0",
        "question": "Which of the following borders Prince Edward Island?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "New Brunswick",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Atlantic Ocean"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Atlantic Ocean borders Prince Edward Island.",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8daa",
        "question": "What was the name of the new country formed by the Fathers of Confederation?",
        "choices": [
            "Canada",
            "Dominion of Canada",
            "Confederation of Canada",
            "British Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "Ontario and Quebec, which, together with New Brunswick and Nova Scotia, formed the new country called the Dominion of Canada.",
        "answer": "Dominion of Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8da9",
        "question": "Which British Empire province was the first to abolish slavery?",
        "choices": [
            "Lower Canada",
            "Ontario",
            "Quebec",
            "Upper Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1793, Upper Canada, led by Lieutenant Governor John Graves Simcoe, a Loyalist military officer, became the first province in the Empire to move toward abolition.",
        "answer": "Upper Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8dad",
        "question": "What is the origin of the beaver as a symbol of Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a mascot by the first pioneers",
            "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a symbol of the fur trade in general",
            "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a mascot by the Natives",
            "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a symbol of the Hudson's Bay Company"
        ],
        "explanation": "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a symbol of the Hudson’s Bay Company. It became an emblem of the St. Jean Baptiste Society, a French-Canadian patriotic association, in 1834, and was also adopted by other groups.",
        "answer": "The beaver was adopted centuries ago as a symbol of the Hudson's Bay Company"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db1",
        "question": "What is known as the women’s suffrage movement?",
        "choices": [
            "The war liberation movement by women",
            "The effort by women to achieve the right to vote",
            "The feminist movement",
            "The effort by women to end suffering"
        ],
        "explanation": "The effort by women to achieve the right to vote is known as the women’s suffrage movement. Its founder in Canada was Dr. Emily Stowe, the first Canadian woman to practise medicine in Canada.",
        "answer": "The effort by women to achieve the right to vote"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8dae",
        "question": "Which province has the largest Aboriginal population in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "New Brunswick",
            "Manitoba",
            "Ontario",
            "Saskatchewan"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manitoba is also an important centre of Ukrainian culture, with 14% reporting Ukrainian origins, and the largest Aboriginal population of any province, at over 15%.",
        "answer": "Manitoba"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db2",
        "question": "Regarding diversity, as what is Canada often referred?",
        "choices": [
            "The Great Dominion",
            "The Great Outdoors",
            "The land of the strong and free",
            "A land of immigrants"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada is often referred to as a land of immigrants because, over the past 200 years, millions of newcomers have helped to build and defend our way of life.",
        "answer": "A land of immigrants"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d45",
        "question": "Who were known as \"habitants\" or \"Canadiens\"?",
        "choices": [
            "The Acadians",
            "The British settlers who spoke French",
            "The Metis",
            "The French-speaking Catholic people"
        ],
        "explanation": "Following the war, Great Britain renamed the colony the “Province of Quebec.” The French-speaking Catholic people, known as habitants or Canadiens, strove to preserve their way of life in the English-speaking, Protestant-ruled British Empire.",
        "answer": "The French-speaking Catholic people"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db4",
        "question": "When did the name \"Canada\" become official?",
        "choices": [
            "1758",
            "1791",
            "1889",
            "1609"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Constitutional Act of 1791 granted to the Canadas, for the first time, legislative assemblies elected by the people. The name Canada also became official at this time and has been used ever since.",
        "answer": "1791"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dbf",
        "question": "When did English colonies appear along the Atlantic seaboard?",
        "choices": [
            "The mid 1600s",
            "The early 1600s",
            "The early 1700s",
            "The late 1600s"
        ],
        "explanation": "English colonies along the Atlantic seaboard, dating from the early 1600s, eventually became richer and more populous than New France.",
        "answer": "The early 1600s"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8db9",
        "question": "Which of the following is Canada’s Asia-Pacific gateway?",
        "choices": [
            "Yukon",
            "Nova Scotia",
            "Alberta",
            "British Colombia"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Port of Vancouver is our gateway to the Asia-Pacific. About one-half of all the goods produced in B.C. are forestry products, including lumber, newsprint, and pulp and paper products—the most valuable forestry industry in Canada.",
        "answer": "British Colombia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dbb",
        "question": "For what is Lake Superior known?",
        "choices": [
            "Deepest lake in the world",
            "Largest fresh water lake in the world",
            "Largest fresh water fishing industry in the world",
            "Largest dam in the world"
        ],
        "explanation": "There are five Great Lakes located between Ontario and the United States: Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake Michigan (in the U.S.A.) and Lake Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world.",
        "answer": "Largest fresh water lake in the world"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dbe",
        "question": "In which year was Canada’s first Prime Minister elected?",
        "choices": [
            "1869",
            "1867",
            "1964",
            "1764"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1867, Sir John Alexander Macdonald, a Father of Confederation, became Canada’s first Prime Minister. Born in Scotland on January 11, 1815, he came to Upper Canada as a child. He was a lawyer in Kingston, Ontario, a gifted politician and a colourful personality.",
        "answer": "1867"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dbc",
        "question": "Which are the Prairie provinces?",
        "choices": [
            "Manitoba and Saskatchewan",
            "Saskatchewan, Ontario and Alberta",
            "Manitoba and Alberta",
            "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta"
        ],
        "explanation": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta are the Prairie Provinces, rich in energy resources and some of the most fertile farmland in the world.",
        "answer": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8db8",
        "question": "How often are members of Parliament elected?",
        "choices": [
            "Ten years",
            "Four years",
            "Five years",
            "Two years"
        ],
        "explanation": "The House of Commons is the representative chamber, made up of members of Parliament elected by the people, traditionally every four years.",
        "answer": "Four years"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db5",
        "question": "Who refused to surrender Quebec to the English in 1690?",
        "choices": [
            "Bishop Laval",
            "Pierre Le Moyne",
            "Count Frontenac",
            "Jean Talon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Count Frontenac refused to surrender Quebec to the English in 1690, saying: “My only reply will be from the mouths of my cannons!”.",
        "answer": "Count Frontenac"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dca",
        "question": "Where does the red-white-red pattern on the Canadian flag come from?",
        "choices": [
            "The British Flag",
            "The Royal Military College in Kingston",
            "The Royal Military College in Quebec",
            "The French flag"
        ],
        "explanation": "The red-white-red pattern comes from the flag of the Royal Military College, Kingston, founded in 1876.",
        "answer": "The Royal Military College in Kingston"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc5",
        "question": "Since the 1970s, from where do most immigrants come from?",
        "choices": [
            "South America",
            "Europe",
            "Asia",
            "Africa"
        ],
        "explanation": "The largest groups are the English, French, Scottish, Irish, German, Italian, Chinese, Aboriginal, Ukrainian, Dutch, South Asian and Scandinavian. Since the 1970s, most immigrants have come from Asian countries.",
        "answer": "Asia"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dcb",
        "question": "Who was Canada’s First Prime Minister?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir John Alexander Macdonald",
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier",
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1867, Sir John Alexander Macdonald, a Father of Confederation, became Canada’s first Prime Minister. Born in Scotland on January 11, 1815, he came to Upper Canada as a child.",
        "answer": "Sir John Alexander Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc2",
        "question": "When is Remembrance Day?",
        "choices": [
            "11th of November",
            "11th of September",
            "First of November",
            "21st of December"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians remember the sacrifices of our veterans and brave fallen in all wars up to the present day in which Canadians took part, each year on November 11.",
        "answer": "11th of November"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc3",
        "question": "Which of the following defines Northern Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "Nunavut, Northwest Territories and Yukon",
            "Nunavut and Northwest Territories",
            "Northwest Territories and Yukon",
            "Nunavut, Northwest Territories and Newfoundland"
        ],
        "explanation": "Northern Canada includes Nunavut, Northwest Territories and Yukon.",
        "answer": "Nunavut, Northwest Territories and Yukon"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc9",
        "question": "What was Pierre Le Moyne famous for?",
        "choices": [
            "He was a great hero of New France, winning many victories over the English in the late 17th and early 18th centuries",
            "He was a great hero of New England, winning many victories over the French in the late 17th and early 18th centuries",
            "He defeated the Americans in the Battle of Trafalgar",
            "He was Upper Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "Pierre Le Moyne was a great hero of New France, winning many victories over the English, from James Bay in the north to Nevis in the Caribbean, in the late 17th and early 18th centuries.",
        "answer": "He was a great hero of New France, winning many victories over the English in the late 17th and early 18th centuries"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc4",
        "question": "Which natives were nomadic, following the bison (buffalo) herds?",
        "choices": [
            "Huron-Wendat of the Great Lakes region and the Iroquois",
            "The Sioux",
            "The Cree and Dene of the Northwest",
            "The Inuit"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Sioux were nomadic, following the bison (buffalo) herd. The Inuit lived off Arctic wildlife. West Coast natives preserved fish by drying and smoking.",
        "answer": "The Sioux"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc8",
        "question": "On election day, what should you do once you mark your ballot?",
        "choices": [
            "Fold it and present it to the poll officials",
            "Present it to the poll officials",
            "Fold it and deposit it in the bin next to you",
            "Leave it on the table"
        ],
        "explanation": "Your vote is secret. You will be invited to go behind the screen to mark your ballot. Once marked, fold it and present it to the poll officials.",
        "answer": "Mobility rights, Aboriginal Peoples' rights, and official language rights"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dbd",
        "question": "When did English settlement begin in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1720",
            "1610",
            "1510",
            "1497"
        ],
        "explanation": "John Cabot, an Italian immigrant to England, was the first to map Canada’s Atlantic shore, setting foot on Newfoundland or Cape Breton Island in 1497 and claiming the New Founde Land for England. English settlement did not begin until 1610.",
        "answer": "1610"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db6",
        "question": "Who was a champion of French language rights?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier",
            "Count Frontenac",
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine, a champion of French language rights, became the first head of a responsible government (similar to a prime minister) in Canada in 1849.",
        "answer": "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dba",
        "question": "Whose portrait is on the $5 bill?",
        "choices": [
            "Sir Etienne-Paschal Tache",
            "Sir George-Etienne Cartier",
            "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine",
            "Sir Wilfrid Laurier"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier became the first French Canadian prime minister since Confederation and encouraged immigration to the West. His portrait is on the $5 bill.",
        "answer": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc0",
        "question": "In what year did Canada enact free trade with the United States?",
        "choices": [
            "1998",
            "1979",
            "1892",
            "1988"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1988, Canada enacted free trade with the United States. Mexico became a partner in 1994 in the broader North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), with over 444 million people and over $1 trillion in merchandise trade in 2008.",
        "answer": "1988"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8db7",
        "question": "Which of the following is a responsibility of a Member of Parliament?",
        "choices": [
            "Public transit",
            "Civil Rights",
            "Education",
            "National Defence"
        ],
        "explanation": "In our federal state, the federal government takes responsibility for matters of national and international concern. These include defence, foreign policy, interprovincial trade and communications, currency, navigation, criminal law and citizenship.",
        "answer": "National Defence"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc1",
        "question": "Where do the majority of Canadians live?",
        "choices": [
            "In rural areas",
            "In cities",
            "Along the East Coast",
            "In small towns"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada has a population of about 34 million people. While the majority live in cities, Canadians also live in small towns, rural areas and everywhere in between.",
        "answer": "In cities"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc6",
        "question": "Why was the war of 1812 important to Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "More than half of the Acadians were deported from their homeland",
            "Canada remained independent from the United States",
            "Quebec became part of Canada",
            "Canada became British"
        ],
        "explanation": "The present-day Canada-U.S.A. border is partly an outcome of the War of 1812, which ensured that Canada would remain independent of the United States.",
        "answer": "Canada remained independent from the United States"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dc7",
        "question": "What animal is a symbol of Canada’s North?",
        "choices": [
            "The beaver",
            "The moose",
            "The polar bear",
            "The caribou"
        ],
        "explanation": "The caribou (reindeer) is a popular game for hunters and a symbol of Canada’s North.",
        "answer": "The caribou"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8d8c",
        "question": "The arrival of Europeans in Canada changed the native way of life forever",
        "choices": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "explanation": "The arrival of European traders, missionaries, soldiers and colonists changed the native way of life forever. Large numbers of Aboriginals died of European diseases to which they lacked immunity.",
        "answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dcd",
        "question": "What is known as the birthplace of Confederation?",
        "choices": [
            "Quebec",
            "Ontario",
            "Prince Edward Island",
            "Nova Scotia"
        ],
        "explanation": "P.E.I. is the birthplace of Confederation, connected to mainland Canada by one of the longest continuous multispan bridges in the world, the Confederation Bridge.",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dce",
        "question": "What is the capital of Prince Edward Island?",
        "choices": [
            "St. John's",
            "Charlottetown",
            "Fredericton",
            "Halifax"
        ],
        "explanation": "Charlottetown is the capital of Prince Edward Island.",
        "answer": "Charlottetown"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd6",
        "question": "What do Canadians wear on Remembrance Day?",
        "choices": [
            "Red bracelet",
            "Red poppy",
            "Blue ribbon",
            "Red ribbon"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canadians wear the red poppy and observe a moment of silence at the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month to honour the sacrifices of over a million brave men and women who have served, and the 110,000 who have given their lives.",
        "answer": "Red poppy"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd2",
        "question": "What were the men who worked together to establish Canada called?",
        "choices": [
            "The Fathers of Canada",
            "The Fathers of Constitution",
            "The Fathers of Dominion of Canada",
            "The Fathers of Confederation"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Fathers of Confederation established the Dominion of Canada on July 1, 1867, the birth of the country that we know today.",
        "answer": "The Fathers of Confederation"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8ddb",
        "question": "Who contributed more to the Allied air effort than any other Commonwealth country during the Second World War?",
        "choices": [
            "India",
            "Canada",
            "Australia",
            "England"
        ],
        "explanation": "Canada contributed more to the Allied air effort than any other Commonwealth country, with over 130,000 Allied air crew trained in Canada under the British Commonwealth Air Training Plan.",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd8",
        "question": "When did the United States invade Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "2015",
            "2000",
            "1999",
            "1812"
        ],
        "explanation": "The British Empire, which included Canada, fought to resist Bonaparte’s bid to dominate Europe. This led to American resentment at British interference with their shipping. Believing it would be easy to conquer Canada, the United States launched an invasion in June 1812.",
        "answer": "1812"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd9",
        "question": "Who is Canada’s Head of State?",
        "choices": [
            "The Prime Minister",
            "The Senators",
            "The Governor General",
            "The King or Queen"
        ],
        "explanation": "As a constitutional monarchy, Canada’s Head of State is a hereditary Sovereign (Queen or King), who reigns in accordance with the Constitution: the rule of law.",
        "answer": "The King or Queen"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dda",
        "question": "What led to the Great Depression in the 1930s?",
        "choices": [
            "The stock market crash of 1929",
            "Low grain prices and a terrible drought in 1929",
            "The stock market crash of 1932",
            "Low grain prices and a terrible drought in 1932"
        ],
        "explanation": "The stock market crash of 1929, led to the Great Depression or the “Dirty Thirties.” Unemployment reached 27% in 1933 and many businesses were wiped out.",
        "answer": "The stock market crash of 1929"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dde",
        "question": "When did European exploration begin in Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1510",
            "1597",
            "1610",
            "1497"
        ],
        "explanation": "European exploration began in earnest in 1497 with the expedition of John Cabot, who was the first to draw a map of Canada’s East Coast.",
        "answer": "1497"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd7",
        "question": "Who made Upper Canada the first province in the British Empire to abolish slavery?",
        "choices": [
            "Joseph Howe",
            "Sir John A. Macdonald",
            "Joseph Brant",
            "Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe"
        ],
        "explanation": "Lieutenant-Colonel John Graves Simcoe was Upper Canada’s first Lieutenant Governor and founder of the City of York (now Toronto). Simcoe also made Upper Canada the first province in the British Empire to abolish slavery.",
        "answer": "Lieutenant Colonel John Graves Simcoe"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8ddd",
        "question": "For what is Laura Secord known?",
        "choices": [
            "She made a dangerous thirty km journey on foot to warn of a planned American attack during the war of 1812",
            "She was the founder of the Canadian feminist movement",
            "She was the founder of the women's suffrage movement",
            "She was an anti-slavery activist and the first woman publisher in Canada"
        ],
        "explanation": "In 1813, Laura Secord, pioneer wife and mother of five children, made a dangerous 19-mile(30-km) journey on foot to warn Lieutenant James FitzGibbon of a planned American attack. Her bravery contributed to victory at the Battle of Beaver Dams. She is recognized as a heroine to this day.",
        "answer": "She made a dangerous thirty km journey on foot to warn of a planned American attack during the war of 1812"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8ddc",
        "question": "When did the United States launch an invasion on Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "1840",
            "1849",
            "1812",
            "1867"
        ],
        "explanation": "The British Empire, which included Canada, fought to resist Bonaparte’s bid to dominate Europe. This led to American resentment at British interference with their shipping. Believing it would be easy to conquer Canada, the United States launched an invasion in June 1812.",
        "answer": "1812"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd4",
        "question": "Which region contains one-third of Canada’s land mass?",
        "choices": [
            "The Atlantic Provinces",
            "Central Canada",
            "The Prairie Provinces",
            "The Northern Territories"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Northwest Territories, Nunavut and Yukon contain one-third of Canada’s land mass but have a population of only 100,000.",
        "answer": "The Northern Territories"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd3",
        "question": "What is the capital of Manitoba?",
        "choices": [
            "Calgary",
            "Regina",
            "Winnipeg",
            "Edmonton"
        ],
        "explanation": "Winnipeg is the capital of Manitoba.",
        "answer": "Winnipeg"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd0",
        "question": "Who gained control over North America in the 1700s?",
        "choices": [
            "The Irish",
            "The French",
            "The Spanish",
            "The English"
        ],
        "explanation": "In the 1700s France and Great Britain battled for control of North America. In 1759, the British defeated the French in the Battle of the Plains of Abraham at Québec City — marking the end of France’s empire in America.",
        "answer": "The French"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd1",
        "question": "When were the first companies in Canada formed?",
        "choices": [
            "During the British regime",
            "After the Second World War",
            "During the French and British regimes",
            "During the French regime"
        ],
        "explanation": "The first companies in Canada were formed during the French and British regimes and competed for the fur trade.",
        "answer": "During the French and British regimes"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dcf",
        "question": "Where is the headquarters of the Canadian Navy’s Pacific fleet?",
        "choices": [
            "Vancouver",
            "Seattle",
            "Victoria",
            "Nanaimo"
        ],
        "explanation": "The capital, Victoria, is a tourist centre and headquarters of the navy’s Pacific fleet.",
        "answer": "Victoria"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dd5",
        "question": "Who was the first European to see present-day Quebec City and Montreal?",
        "choices": [
            "Jean Talon",
            "Jacques Cartier",
            "Pierre de Monts",
            "Samuel de Champlain"
        ],
        "explanation": "Jacques Cartier was the first European to explore the St. Lawrence River and to set eyes on present-day Québec City and Montreal.",
        "answer": "Jacques Cartier"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d152f53f234b9f8db3",
        "question": "When is Canada Day?",
        "choices": [
            "First of November",
            "11th of November",
            "11th of September",
            "First of July"
        ],
        "explanation": "The Dominion of Canada was officially born on July 1, 1867. Until 1982, July 1 was celebrated as “Dominion Day” to commemorate the day that Canada became a self-governing Dominion. Today it is officially known as Canada Day.",
        "answer": "First of July"
    },
    {
        "id": "65cce4d252f53f234b9f8dcc",
        "question": "What made it possible for immigrants to settle in Western Canada?",
        "choices": [
            "The completion of the Canadian National Railway",
            "The completion of the Canadian Pacific Railway",
            "The completion of the port of Vancouver",
            "The giving of free land to new settlers"
        ],
        "explanation": "Sir Wilfrid Laurier became the first French-Canadian prime minister since Confederation and encouraged immigration to the West. His portrait is on the $5 bill. The railway made it possible for immigrants, including 170,000 Ukrainians, 115,000 Poles and tens of thousands from Germany, France, Norway and Sweden to settle in the West before 1914 and develop a thriving agricultural sector.",
        "answer": "The completion of the Canadian Pacific Railway"
    }
]